In this lecture, I'm going to show you
how to handle exceptions in your programs.
So
continuing with the code from the last lecture,
to handle the Value
Error exception here,
we need to put this statement in
a try block.
So we add try colon,
we indented and
then after try we need to add an
except clause.
What is the type of the
exception that we get, if
the user enters a non numeric
value?
That's a ValueError exception. You
saw that in the last lecture. right?
So we add
the except clause and
then we'll print a
friendly error message like
you didn't enter a
valid age.
So this is how this works:
When
Python sees a try block
it will execute every
statement in this block.
If any of these statements throws
an exception, the code in the except clause
will be executed.
If we don't have any exceptions this
code will not be executed.
Let me show you.
So save
the changes.
back in the terminal.
Let's run
the program.
I'm going to enter a valid age.
So
our program completed successfully.
No error messages, beautiful.
I'm going to run the program one more time.
This time I'm going to enter a
for the age.
So we got a friendly error
message and our application didn't crash.
This
is the important thing about handling exceptions.
If you don't handle
exceptions properly, your program will crash.
So in
other words if you add another statement here,
let's print execution continues.
In
this example because we are handling this exception properly,
this
statement will be executed.
Let me show you.
So back
in the terminal.
let's run the program one more time.
Enter a.
We got our friendly our message and
also you can
see the execution of our program continue.
In contrast,
in the last lecture where
we didn't have the try block If
we put this print statement
after getting users age,
this line would not be executed.
Okay.
We
also have an optional else clause here.
So
else colon and
what we put inside this
block will be executed if
no exception is thrown in
the code that we add in the try block.
So let's print a
message like No exceptions were thrown.
Save the changes.
Back in the terminal.
Let's run this one
more time.
I enter a valid age.
You
can see this message:
No exceptions were thrown.
So
what we have in the else clause
will only be executed if
we don't have any exceptions.
This is very similar to
our for else loops.
Remember for else?
Earlier,
when I talked about for else loops,
I told you that the else clause
is executed if we don't
break out of the for loop.
In other words,
if the for loop completes,
then the
else clause is executed.
So here's the basic structure for
handling exceptions.
Now one more thing before we finish this lecture.
Here when handling the exception
we can optionally define
a variable that will include
the details about the exception, mostly
the error message and sometimes additional arguments.
So
here we add as
and then defining variable like
error or ex for exception.
So after
this error message, let's just print ex.
I'm
also going to print type of ex.
Now
let's run the program one more time.
Enter a.
So
here's our friendly our message.
Below that, we have the
actual error message that isincluded in the exception.
invalid
literal for int() with base 10.
Now this is
very technical to show it to an end user,
so we're not going to print it
on the terminal,
this is just for demonstration.
And below
that you can see the type of this exception,
it's an object of type ValueError.