In the last lecture, you learned that
we use the finally clause
to release external
resources.
Now we have a shorter and cleaner way to achieve
the same thing but
without the finally clause.
But it doesn't always
work.
It works with certain kinds of objects.
Let me
explain.
So online 2 I'm going
to make a couple of slight changes.
Instead of getting the
return value of the open function,
we prefix this
with the with statement.
And then we'll get access to
the return value of this function by
typing as file.
So this is the file object that
the open function returns.
After
that we add a colon, so obviously here
we're going to have a block.
In this block of code we can
work with this file object.
For example
we can read something from this file or
write to it and so on.
So
for now let's just print file opened.
Now,
Whenever we open a
file using the with statement, Python
will automatically call file dot close whether
we have a final clause or not.
In other words the
with statement is used to automatically release external
resources.
So now we can delete these
two lines from here.
that's better.
But let's
dive deeper and see how
this exactly works under the
hood?
So look at this file object file
dot.
These are the members of the file object.
We
have methods that start with two underlines and
we referred to them as magic methods.
In the next section, where
I talk about classes and objects,
you're going to learn about this in
detail.
But here we have two magic methods that
you should be
aware of.
We have __enter__ and __exit__.
when an object has these two methods,
we say that object supports
context management protocol.
Again in the next section I'm
going to talk about this in more detail.
So if an object supports
the context management protocol or
in other words if an
object has these two methods enter and exit,
we can use that object with the with statement.
Python
will automatically call the exit method
and there, it
will release external resources.
That is the reason we don't need
a finally clause here.
Now to take this to the next level there
are times that you might
be working with multiple external resources.
Let's say we want to read some data from one file and
write it to another
file.
So How do we do that?
Well here before
the colon we can add
a comma and open another
external resource like another file.
So open.
Let's
say another file dot txt
as we
give it a variable name like target.
with this
Python will automatically release both these external resources.
Now I'm going to delete the second one
here because we don't have a file called another
dot txt, so when we run this program
we'll get an exception and
our program will crash.
So delete.
So this is all about with statement.