So far you have learned how to handle exceptions.
but you can also raise
or throw exceptions in your own code.
Let me show you an example.
So
I'm going to define a function.
Let's call it calculate X
factor. This function takes age and
simply returns 10 divided by age. In
this example. age cannot
be zero or less. so
we can have an if statement here.
If age is
less than or equal to zero.
we can raise an exception. So
we use the race statement and
then specify the type of our
exception. So far. you have
seen a few types like value
error. zero division error and so on. In
Python we have various kinds
of built in exceptions. If
you go to Google and search
for python 3 built-in exceptions
on this page. we can see
all the built in exceptions in python and
what they're used for. Down
the bottom of this page you can see the
completely service exceptions.
So as you can see here,
we have a hierarchy like
a parent child kind of relationship.
At
the very top.
We have based exception below that
we have a few Children.
One of them is exception. Below
exception. we have arithmetic error.
and below that we have
zero division error.
So these are the built in exceptions in
python and
they're sufficient for most cases. But
you can also define your own exception types.
It's not something that
you do that often, but
it is something that you can do for sure.
In
order to do that you have to learn about classes
and that's the topic for the
next section.
back to our code.
In this
case we want to raise a
ValueError exception.
In
parenthesis we can specify an error message like
Age cannot be 0 or less.
So we have this function that
raises or throws an exception, if
we give it an invalid argument.
somewhere else in
our program,
we're going to use this function.
So recall
calculate_xfactor and pass, let's
say negative one.
Now let me run this program. You
can see our program crashed
with a value error exception. And
here's the message. Age cannot
be zero or less.
Obviously
this happened because
we didn't handle exceptions here properly, so
we didn't have a try block.
To fix this issue let's add a
try block and then. except clause of
type value error. Let's give this exception object
a name like error. and here
we can simply print Sarah. Now let's
run the program one more time.
So here's our
error message and our
program didn't crash beautiful. So
this is how you can raise exceptions in your cook.
But this is
not something that I advise you to do.
I only explained it here because
you will see this in other people's code.
as I will show
in the next lecture,
raising exceptions is costly.
So
in this example instead of
raising an exception here and
then handling it below this function,
you could take a different approach that
would result in better performance.
That's what I'm going to show you in the next lecture.