When writing programs, many things can go wrong.
Our programs may
encounter an error and terminate.
Usually these errors happen
because of programmers mistakes,
or bad data that
we get from the user,
or resources not being available.
For
example, you might need to open a file
but if that file doesn't exist
our program is going to crash.
It's your job as a programmer
to prevent your application from crashing in these
kind of situations.
Instead, we want to display a proper error
message to the user like:
Hey, this file doesn't exist.
So
let's take a look at a few examples.
I'm going to define a
list of numbers with two
items and then print the
third item.
When we run this program we
get this error "IndexError",
this happened in
this file app.py,
on line 2,
and
here is the statement that generated this error.
In
programming we referred to this kind of error as an exception.
An
exception is a kind of error that terminates the execution of
a program.
More specifically we say this line this
statement threw an exception.
And this is
an example of an exception that was thrown because of
the programmer's mistake.
Here's another example.
Earlier you learn about the input function to
get input from the user.
Let's say we ask for the
user's age.
You know that this function returns a string so
we need to convert it to an integer and
then store it
here.
Now instead of running this using the
code runner, let's go to the terminal and
run python or python3 app.py.
The
reason I didn't run this using
Code Runner is that by default Code
Runner runs our programs in the output window
which is read only
so we cannot enter data.
So here in the terminal. let's
run this program.
If we enter a non numeric value like
a, our program crashes.
In this example we
got an exception of type ValueError.
So
as I told you before,
it's your job as a programmer to
handle these exceptions and
prevent your application from crashing.
And let's I'm gonna show you next.