Alright.
I've simplified the code from the last lecture.
Now let's extend this
example. Let's make up a magic formula. Like
X factor equals 10. Divided
by H. Save the changes back in
the terminal. Let's run this program one more time.
I'm going to enter zero
as the h What happened. Our program crashed
again.
We got a different kind of exception that
is a ZeroDivisionError,
because in programming we
cannot divide a number by zero.
So the
statement online 3 threw an exception. but
we don't have a matching except clause for
that kind of exception.
In other words in this code
you're only handling ValueError exceptions and
that is why our program crashed. So to
solve this problem. we can
come back here and add
a second except Klaus. Accept and
specify a different kind of
exception in this case. zero
division error. Now below that.
we can print a
message like Age cannot be zero back
in the terminal. Let's run the
program one more time and enter zero
. Okay. beautiful.
Our program didn't crash. Now let's
take this to the next level.
Let's imagine if the
user enters zero for the age.
We want to print the
exact same error message.
So I want to copy this
and paste it here. Now our code looks
a little bit repetitive.
We have repeated this message. and
that means if in the future we
want to change this message. we have to
change it in two places.
There is a better way to handle this
situation.
In front of this except clause we
can specify multiple types of exceptions.
So
if the exception that is
thrown matches any of those exceptions
. then the code that we
have in the except block will
be executed. So here we need to
add parenthesis to specify multiple types of exceptions
separated by comma. So come on. zero
division error and close parenthesis. Save
the changes.
Now with this change, technically we don't
need these two lines.
We can delete them.
But
temporarily I'm going to keep them
to show you something interesting.
So
back in the terminal.
let's run this one more time.
And enter
zero.
Note that we get a single error on the
terminal.
In other words the code that
we have in this except block was
not executed, otherwise
we would see this message twice.
So
here's the lesson:
when Python executes the code that
we have in the try block,
if any of the statements throws an
exception that matches one
of the except clauses, that
except clauses executed and
the other except clauses are
ignored.
So to clean up this code
we can delete these two lines;
that is better.