There are times that we need to
work with external resources like files,
network connections,
databases and so on.
Whenever we
use these resources after we're done
we need to release them.
For example when you open a file
we should always close it
after we're done, otherwise
another process or another program
may not be able to open that file.
So let's take
this example to the next level.
Here in our try block, first
I'm going to open a file.
so we call the open function
and let's open up app.py.
Here this
returns a file object.
So let's get that here.
Now
When we're done we should close this file object.
So this
file object has a method called close.
Now the problem with this code
is that this statement will not be
executed in case of an exception.
In other words
if one of these two lines, line 3 or line
4, throws an exception the control will
be moved to our except clause, so
what we have on line 5
will not be executed.
One solution is to move this
down here. but again. the problem
is that this will only be
executed if we have an exception.
If we don't have an
exception. the control will be
moved here so our file will
not be closed. So another
solution is to duplicate this
year. And duplication is a
bad practice in programming. You
should not repeat yourself in your code.
So what is the solution. The
solution is to use the final clause.
Let me show you. So
I'm going to delete this line here and
at a final clause at the end.
This finally
clause is always executed whether
we have an exception or
not and we use it
to release external resources.
So
this is the perfect place
to close files, database connections,
network connections and so on.