As I explained in the last lecture,
when writing your own functions, prefer
not to raise exceptions because
these exceptions come with
a cost and
that's what I'm going to show you in this lecture.
So
from the timeit module,
I'm going to import a function called
timeit.
With this function, we can calculate the execution
time of some python code.
So this
is how it works.
Imagine we want to calculate the
execution time of this piece of code.
We define a
variable. Let's call it code1 and set it
to a string.
This string should include our python code.
So I'm going to use
triple codes because our python code is
spread across multiple lines and we terminated
here.
So this is one  piece of code now.
After
that, we call timeit as
the first argument we passed python code. That
is our code Juan Variable. Now. here we
have a keyword argument number.
We said this to the
number of times we want to
execute this piece of code. so
let's set it to 10,000 so
we can see the difference. Now
this function returns the execution time
of this piece of code after
10,000 repetitions. Now this function will execute
our prison code 10,000 times.
It will calculate the
execution time and return it
so we can simply print it
on a terminal.
I would like to add a
label as well. Let's say first code
. Now open up a terminal window.
You can't run this using code
runner. So type python uh. pie
. You can see our
program was executed 10,000 times and
we got 10,000 messages here.
And here's the execution time not
to clean this up.
Let's go back to our except clause
. I don't want to print
this error message. so let's use the
pass statement.
This pass statement is a statement that
doesn't do anything.
And we need to use that here because
we cannot have
an empty except block.
Okay. so save
the changes back in the terminal.
Let's run this one more
time. so here's a
total execution time. Now let's
try a different approach.
Back
in our calculate_xfactor function
instead of raising an exception, if
age is zero or less,
we can return a value like
None. So I'm going to select this
entire code. copied then pasted.
Let's change this variables name to coat
to in this implementation. Instead of
raising an exception.
we want to return none. So
None is an object that represents
the absence of a value.
In
this new implementation. We don't need a
try block so we can simplify our
code. Let's delete that as
well as the except clause
on the past statement.
We simply get the X factor
. You can store
it in a variable. so
instead of handling an exception.
we can compare this X factor
with none. So if X factor equals
nine. then let's just pass so
immediately you can see this code
is simpler than the previous implementation
. and as you will see in a second.
this will be executed almost four
times faster. Let me show you. So down
the bottom. I'm going to
duplicate this lying change the
label to second code and replace
Code Juan with CO two.
Save the changes back
in the terminal. Let's run the program. So
here's the execution time
of the first implementation. As
you can see.
our second implementation was almost four
times faster.
Now there is a caveat here.
We
see this difference when
we execute this piece of code 10,000 times.
So if you're on the code once
you're not going to see any differences.
In
other words, if you're building
a simple application for a
few users, raising exceptions in
your functions is not going
to have a bad impact on
the performance of your application.
But
if you're building an application where
performance and scalability is
important, then it's better
to raise exceptions when you
really have to.
As a general rule of thumb. when
you want to raise exceptions in your functions,
think twice.
See
if you can handle the situation with a simple if statement;
Whether
there is a performance difference or not,
your code will end up being a
little bit cleaner.
So raise exceptions if you really have to.