in this section. We're going to look
at some of the most popular
packages in the python community. So
you're going to learn how to
work with Excel spreadsheets. Pdf fires
. send text messages. automate browsers. scrape
websites and so on.
These have a lot of applications in
the real world before we get started.
I just want to let you know that
we're only going to look at the
basics of these packages because each of
these packages has so much detail
that goes beyond the scope of
this course. You need to look at
their documentation to learn these additional details
on your own. So in this section.
I just want to show you what is out
there for you and how you can use it.
Now. As you go through this
section. it is possible that some
of these packages may not work
on your machine. As you see in these videos.
there are basically two reasons
. If this happens. the first reason
is that you didn't follow the instructions exactly
as I showed you in the video.
Maybe you had a typo or you missed a
space or you didn't use
the lowercase or uppercase letters exactly
like how I type. So first.
make sure to follow each step exactly
as I show you. Now.
if you still encounter an error. then
chances are there is something wrong
on your machine. And unfortunately. I
won't be able to help you with that
because every machine is different. I don't know
what software you have installed or whether
you have changed any of the configuration settings
. So you need to resolve this
issue on your own.
How?
All you
have to do is simply copy
paste the error messages you get. And
Google. I can promise you
are not the only person on
this planet who encountered these problems.
I'm pretty sure
there are other people who have faced
the same situation. You're not the first one
or the only one in the
world with all that. Let's get
started. Yeah. yeah