In this lecture you're going to learn
how to work with Excel spreadsheets in Python.
Out
of all the lecturers in this course,
this is one of my absolute favorites
because it has a lot of applications in the real world.
So here
I have a brand new project called PyExcel.
In
this project, I have a spreadsheet
called Transactions. You
can download this as a zip
file attached to this lecture. When
you open this.
you're going to say something like
this. So we have three columns Transaction I
D. Product idea and Price
as well as three rows of
data. Pretty straightforward. So back
to the U. S. Code.
The package we're going to install is open
pie Excel. So let's run pip and install
open pie X l All
right. Beautiful. Now let's
select our virtual environment from
the status bar and set
it to pi Excel. Next
. we're going to install
pilot just like before. All
right now on the top.
we start by importing open
pie exile.
Now when working with spreadsheets,
we need to start with a workbook object.
We can either create an
empty workbook in memory or
load an existing workbook on disk.
So this module open Pie Excel
has this workbook class We can create a
new workbook object like this.
Now we have an empty workbook with
one sheet.
Later I will show you how to save this to disc.
We
also have this function open pie excel dot
load workbook for loading an existing workbook. So
in this demo. I'm going
to load transactions dot XLs
X and
this gives us a workbook object.
So
I'm going to comment out this line because
we're not going to use it.
So
we have a workbook.
Now this workbook has an attribute called
sheet names.
This is actually an attribute even though
VSCode is showing it as a function.
let's print this
on the terminal. So
in this workbook,
we have only a single sheet that is sheet1.
Let's go ahead and access that.
That is
pretty easy.
We use square brackets, just like how we work
with dictionaries.
So sheet1.
And
by the way, this is case sensitive,
so if you use a lower case
s, you're going to get an exception
telling you that this sheet doesn't exist.
So make sure to spell it properly.
Now
we have a sheet object.
We can also create a new sheet
or remove an existing one.
So our workbook object has
a couple of methods you should be aware of.
One is create_sheet
Here we pass the name of the new sheet
like Sheet2
and
optionally, we can pass an index,
for example we
can pass zero to put this
before sheet one.
We also have remove underlined
sheet that takes a sheet object like this
and it will remove it.
Now I'm not going to use these methods in this demo.
Just be aware of them in case
you need them in the future.
So we
have a sheet.
Next we need to access an individual cell
or a range of cells.
That is pretty easy.
So using
square brackets, we can
pass the coordinate of a
cell.
So we can pass a1 and
that refers to this cell here, a 1.
So first
row, first column.
So here we get a cell
object.
Now this cell object has a few attributes you
should know about.
One is value.
We can print
this on the terminal.
So the value of this cell is
transaction_id, you have seen that before.
We can also change the
value here.
Pretty straightforward, right?
We
also have row.
Let's print that
on the terminal.
We have column and
coordinate.
Let's have a look. So
the row of the cell is one.
The column is A and
the coordinate is A1.
Now
we also have another approach
to access an individual cell and
that is using the cell method
of the sheet object.
Let me show
you.
So instead of using square brackets
and passing the coordinate. we can call sheet
that cell and pass a role and a
column. So one and one
Now we can make this
code more readable by using
keyword arguments because it's not
quite clear what row or what
column we're working with here. So
we said. roll to one and column to
one.
and this gives us
the exact same cell.
Now
obviously this code is shorter and easier to use,
but the second
approach is useful when
we're iterating over all the
rows and all the columns.
and we want to dynamically access various
cells. Let me show you so this sheet
has a couple of attributes.
One is Max Row. Let's
print that on a terminal.
We also have Max column
Let's run the program. So in
this sheet we have four rows and
three columns. Now we
can easily iterate over all
these rows and columns so we
can write a for loop
like this four row in sheet
that max on the line row.
Now this returns a number. so
we need to pass that to the range function.
Now as
you know this function generates
numbers starting from zero. So
we need to set the start index to one
because we don't have
row zero in a spreadsheet.
The first row is one.
Also for this reason, we need
to increment this way one so we
can access the last row.
Now using the
same technique we can iterate
over all the columns.
So
for column in range of
one and sheet. But Max underlined
column plus one. Now
we can call sheet
dot cell and pass the
row and column here. And with this
. we can print the
value of each cell. save
the changes and run the program.
So these are all the
values we have in the spreadsheet. Now
using square brackets,
we can also access a range of
cells.
So let me delete this for loop.
Here are a few examples.
we can access sheet of
a and
this will return all the cells in the
a column.
So here's the A column, It will return all
these cells.
We can store the result
in column.
Let's print that and see what we get. So
we get to tuple because here
we have parenthesis.
In this tuple
We have four cell objects.
Sell a one a two
a3 and a4.
Pretty self explanatory.
We
can also work with a
range of columns. so sheet of
A to C This will return all
the cells in columns. A to see
Now let's do that
here so cells and then
print it on the terminal.
Let's see what we get. Note
that we get a tuple of tuples.
So each topple
in this topple will represent one column.
Let me show you
. So here's one of our inner
topples in this topple. We have cells
. A one a two. a three
and a four. So this inner topple
represents the A column that
is this column here. So a
one all the way to a four.
This is one of
the inner topples. Next to
that we have another topple and
then another topple. And these
three couples are packed inside
of another topple. Okay?
Now we can also use
coordinates here.
So sheet of, let's say a1 to
c3, and this will
return all the cells in
this area. So a
12 C three. OK?
Using
the same technique we can also
access the cells in a given row
or a range of rows.
So sheet
of one returns all the
cells in the first row
. Or. if you use
123 this will return all
the cells in row
one all the way to
go three. So this is
how we can access a
range of cells.
Now this sheet object has
a few methods you should be aware of.
One of them is a pan. and
we use that to add a row
at the end of the sheet. So
here we pass a list or a tuple of values.
Let's say 1 2 3.
We
also have insert rows,
and we use this to insert
a row at a given index.
We also have insert columns
. as well as delete
rows and delayed columns so
you can perform various kinds
of operations in a spreadsheet. You
can also add charts. sort and
filter data and so on. I
live it up to you to look
at the documentation of open pie. Excel and
learn about the features that you
need in your applications. Now. to
finish this lecture. let's save this workbook. So
workbook.save,
we're going to save it as
a new file,
so transactions2.xlsx.
Save the changes.
Run
the program. Now we have a
new spreadsheet here and in the spreadsheet.
We should have an
extra row of data.
And here's our updated spreadsheet,
we can see the row that we added using python.