In this lecture I'm going to talk about
a very important principle in computer programming
called Command Querey Separation. This principle states
that our methods or functions
should either be commands that
perform an action and change the
state of a system or queries
that return answer to the caller
without changing the state or
causing side effects.
So our methods should either be commands or
queries but not both.
Let's see this principle in action. So
in the last lecture you learned that
this workbook object has a method called
create sheet. This is an
example of a command method
because it's responsible for performing a task.
The task of
creating a sheet.
As a result of calling this method the
state of our system, in this case our workbook, changes.
So
every time we call it, we get
a new sheet in this workbook. Now
. let's take a look at an example
of a query method. So here we have this
sheet that represents the first
sheet in my workbook. In
the last lecture. you learned about
the cell method. We use this
to access a cell in this sheet.
This is an example of
a query method.
We use it to access a given cell.
However
this method violates the
command query separation principle. Let
me show you why.
I'm going to write a loop to print the value of
all the cells in
the first column. So for
role in range one. let's
say to 10. We want
to call sheet that cell
Castro here and one as the collar we
get the cell. Now we print sell that
value.
Let's run this program. So
here are the values we've got.
transaction id followed by
three rows of data and
a bunch of None objects.
Now
after this loop,
I'm going to call sheet dot
appened to add a new row
with these values and
finally saved the workbook
as transactions2.
Let's
see what happens when we run this program.
So run. Okay. Now
I'm going to open up this transactions2.
Here's the
result.
This new row that we added ended up here.
But
didn't we expect it to be right here after the last row?
This
is the result of violation of
Command Query Separation principle.
Here's
the reason: in this for loop.
we're iterating over the
1st 10 rolls to get
the cell in the first column
. Now. in our original spreadsheet.
we only had four rows
. These are the roads. so the
heading row followed by three data rose
. So when we use the for loop
to iterate over the 1st 10 rolls. the
cell method magically created these new
cells. In other words. when we call this
method to access a cell
at a given coordinate. if that
cell doesn't exist. this method
will create it for us. And
this is the violation of
command query separation principle. because
this is a query method.
so it should not change the state of
our system in this case.
the workbook. In other words. you should not
have a side effect.
So the developer who implemented this
method probably had no idea
of this very important principle in
programming. So. as you can see.
the violation of this principle can
create unexpected issues in your program.
It makes it hard to
reason about your code and figure
out what is happening. So it
would be better if this method
raised an exception if we try to
access a cell that didn't exist similar to
accessing the force item in
a list of three items. Let
me show you. So here we
have a list of numbers. 123
If we try to access
the fourth element. what happens. Our
list will raise an exception.
Or. if you have a dictionary and
try to access an item
with an invalid key again
. our dictionary raises an exception.
It doesn't magically create
a key value pair with this key.
because here requiring our
dictionary so earlier in the course.
you learn that when we
use square brackets to get an item.
but it's key. A
magic method called __getitem__ will
be alled. This is a quarry method.
It should not change the
state of the system or it
should not have side effects. In other
words. asking a question should
not change the answer. So
I thought this was a great
opportunity for me to talk about the
Command Corey separation principle.
It's very important. make sure
your methods are either
commands or queries. And when
using open pie Excel.
be aware of how this cell
method works.
So if you generate an Excel spreadsheet and
see some blank rows or columns,
go back, check your code and
make sure you didn't accidently refrence those cells.