In this lecture, we're going to look at
a very important package called Numpy, which
is heavily used in scientific computations.
So if
you wanna get into data science and machine learning,
this is one of the packages
you will be using quite often.
There also several other packages that
are built on top of this package.
So it's a very comprehensive topic,
and it really requires its own course.
But in this lecture, I'm going
to give you a very sweet introduction to numpy.
So you know what it
is and
what you can do with it.
So here on
the terminal, let's do
pipenv install numbpy.
So
numpy enriches python by bringing superfast, multidimensional
arrays that takes less memory
than the built in lists in
python. So any time you
want to work with large multidimensional
arrays, numpy is your best friend.
So let's important on
the top import numpy. we
can optionally give it an
alias using the ass keyword. So
call it np. and now
we can access this module with
np. This makes our code shorter
because in a real application. you're
going to use this package a lot
so we don't want to type numpy dot
numpy dot numpy dot, Okay?
Now here
we have this array function
for creating an array. We can
pass a normal list here.
and this will return a
numpy array.
Let's have a look.
So print
array.
So here's our array.
but this is actually a numpy array.
So if
you print the type of this array, you
can see it's an instance of n dimensional array
class in Numpy.
Now here we can create a
multidimensional array like this. So we
have one list in this list. Each item
is a list. Here is the first item.
It's a list of three
items. and here it
is the second list with
three more items.
So now we have a two dimensional array, which
is called a matrix in math.
Let's print this
on a terminal.
This is what we get. So
we have a matrix with
two rows and three columns.
Now
this array object has an attribute called shape. so
let's print array.shape and
run the program.
There you go.
So as you see this returns
a tuple that specifies the
number of items in each demention.
So here we have a matrix
with two rows and three columns and that's
why we get that tuple with two and three .
Now in
numpy we have a bunch of
helper methods for creating arrays and initializing
them with zeros, ones, specific numbers or
random values.
Let me show you.
So np
dot zeros. This will create an array and
initialize it with zeros. Now the
first argument of this method is
a tuple that represents the shape of this array.
So here we
pass a topple.
let's say three and four.
Now
we get an array and
printed on the terminal.
So
we get a matrix of
three rows and four columns, and
each element is initialized to zero.
Now by default all these
numbers are floating point numbers.
That's why we have this decimal point
here.
If you want to change the data type, you can pass a
second argument here that is dtype.
So dtype,
we set this to let's say integer.
Run the program again.
So now all our numbers are integers.
Now
We have another method called ones.
and we use that if
you want to initialize this array with ones.
Let's take a look.
Here
it is.
We can also fill this array with a specific number.
So we call the full method, and
as the second argument we'll pass the
number we want to fill this array with.
Let's say five and here's the result.
So pretty cool, right?
We also have a method for creating an
array with random values.
So we
go to the random module, in this module
we have this random function.
So we just passed the shape of this array and this will
create a three by four
array and every item
is a random number.
Now if you want to do this in pure python without
numpy, our code is definitely longer than
this.
It's going to be two or three lines of code.
So numpy
makes a lot of trivial things really really easy.
So
now we have a three by four array.
We can access individual elements
using an index.
So here we have our array.
Let's get
the element at the first row
and the first column.
So
print.
So here's our array and as you can see
the item at the first row in the first column
is this number which is printed
here.
Now in contrast, if this array was
a multidimensional list in Python,
our code would end up
looking like this:
array of zero and zero.
So
we would have extra square brackets
and this would make our code a
little bit noisy.
Now let me show you something really powerful.
I'm going to print an expression like this:
array greater
than 0.2.
Now let me comment
out what we have online 8, We don't need it anymore.
Let's run
the program.
See what we get here.
Here's our original array
and below that
we have an array of Boolean values.
Each
element determines if the corresponding element in
the original array was greater than 0.2.
Extremely
powerful.
If you want to do this in pure python would have to write a
lot more code than
this simple expression.
So Numpy
arrays support various kinds of mathematical operations.
We
also have boolean indexing.
Again extremely powerful.
So we print array of, now
instead of using a numerical index,
use a Boolean expression.
So
let's say array is greater than 0.2.
Let's
run the program and
see what happens.
So this will return a new
array with only
the values that are greater than
0.2.
We also have a bunch of functions
for performing computations on arrays.
Let me show you a
few examples.
So let's print numpy
dot sum and we pass our array.
This returns the
sum of all items in this array.
So
here's a result.
That's pretty cool.
We also
have floor and this returns a
new array with the exact same
dimension and computes the floor of
each item here.
Similar to floor We
have ceil to get the ceiling
of each number or round.
Let's
run this.
So when we round these
numbers, we get an array of zero's and one's.
Pretty cool.
And
one last thing before I finish this lecture.
we can also perform arithmetic
operations between arrays and numbers.
Let me show you.
So I'm going to delete all this code.
Let's
say we have one array
here and p dot array with
1 2 3. We have another array here. Now
we can print first plus second Let's
run it.
So here's the result.
All the
arithmetic operators that you're
familiar with like multiplication, division
subtraction, All these are
supported by numpy arrays.
We
can also add a number
to our first array.
Let's see what happens.
So this creates a new array and
adds 2 to each item in the original array.
Now
here's a real world example of
using this operation.
Let's say we have
an array of dimensions in inch
and you want to convert it to centimeters. So
dimensions underline. Inch was
set it to numpy dot
r a and pass 123 Here. Now
to convert these values to centimeter.
we can write code like this
so dimensions on the nine centimeter equals
dimensions. Underline inch multiplied by 2.54 Let's
print the result. So there
you go.
Again Pretty easy.
If you want to do this in pure python
without the use of numpy our code would be longer.
Let me show you.
So as comparison, we create dimensions inch
and set it to a regular list in Python.
Now
we need a list comprehension
to transform this array into
a different array.
So here is the syntax for list
comprehension.
Item for item in list.
In this
case. our list is dimensions inch. Let's
call each item X. Now we
need to get X and multiplied by
2.54 And with this we get dimensions
onderline Centimeter.
So this is the implementation
in pure python.
And here is the implementation in
Numpy.
So numpy provides multidimensional arrays
that are super fast and
take less memory Plus
they support
various kinds of mathematical operations
that regular python lists don't.
So it's the cool library for scientific computation.