These days a lot of websites make
their data available to others while
what we call application programming
interfaces or APIs.
In simple terms
these APIs are endpoints that
are publicly accessible on the Internet.
So they have URLs
just like the
Web sites themselves. Here is
an example,
on yelp we have this API for searching for
businesses.
And this API has an endpoint at
this address or u r
l that is api dot yelp
dot com slash version
three slash businesses slash search
so we can send an http
request to this end point to
get the list of businesses
that match some criteria. In
case you're not familiar with http.
it's basically the protocol that
powers our web. So as
we're browsing the web. our
browser sends http requests various websites and
get something back. Let me show you.
So here in chrome. on
the top from the view menu.
go to developer and
open up develop are tools. Now
open up the network tab.
In case you don't see anything here. press
command and are on mac
or control and are on windows
to refresh the page. There you go. So
these are all the http
requests that my browser sent to
yell. Look at the
first request business search. That's
a request to get a document. Let's inspect
this request here in the header step.
you can see various attributes of
an http request. So this is the request.
U r l or
address. And that is the end point where
we're sending this request to.
Every http request has
a method. and that method
determines what we're going to
use this request for We
have a few standard http
request methods get for getting data post
for creating data put for updating data and
delayed for deleting data
below the request method. We
have status code. and that
is the status code of the
response that we get from the Web.
Server 200 indicates
success. Now here. If you
look at the response tab. you
can see the response that
this Web server sent to our
browser. This is basically
an HTML document that represents
its web page. If you
open the previous tab. you can
see a preview of this Web page. So
over the next few lectures you're
going to learn how to communicate with
yelp. AP to search for businesses based on some criteria.