In this lecture we're going to have a
quick look at yelp a P I. So
if you search for Yelp API.
you can find this website yelp dot
com slash developers. Let's have a quick look
here. So we have this yelp fusion
. which is the
rest api for yelp. when
working with APIs quite
often you see this term rest. which
is basically a technical jargon
that stands for representational state
transfer. Basically. it's a
bunch of conventions and rules
that we have to follow to
build or consume APIs for
exchanging data. So let's take
a look at this yelp fusion
on this page. You should
see this documentation link. Here
we have various end points
for working with businesses. For example
. we have endpoints for
finding businesses by keyword location
category or using a phone number.
We also have
an endpoint forgetting details
about a particular business or
reviews. These are all business endpoints now on
the left side. If you look.
we also have 10
points for working with events
as well as categories. So
there are so many different things that we
can do with Yelp. a P I no
to get started. First.
we should create an app. So let's
give our application a name.
I'm gonna call this pie. Yup
. Now. if we do have a website.
we can put that here. But in this case
. we don't have a website.
We simply have a python program. Next
. We need to specify
the industry for this application. I'm
going to set that to business.
The next piece of
information admitted to supply is
the contact email and some description
. So I'm going to
type programming with Marsh at
gmail dot com and some description.
It doesn't really matter
. We can always come back and
change this in the future. So obviously
. we need to accept their terms and conditions.
And I don't want to
get any emails about their
product news and so on. So
let's go ahead with this and create
a new app. All right. Our applications created
Now we have a client ID that uniquely identifies our
application. This is like a
user name for an application. We
also have an API key.
which is kind of like a password for
an application. We'll need
this API key whenever we
want to talk to any of the
endpoints on Yell. This is for security. So
Yelp wants to know who's
calling their API endpoints. With
this basic information that we provided.
at least they have a contact information. They
know who is the creator of this application.
All right. we have created our
application.
Next I'm going to show you
How to send an http request to yelp API
to get the list of buisinesses.