All right. I'm starting with a brand
new project called Pie Young in
this project. Currently I only have
one file that is after pipe
. Now let's open up
the terminal window and using pip
and install the requests package. We
use this package to send http requests. Let's
go ahead. So this
is creating a virtual environment
. Our packag's installed. Beautiful. Now let's change
the virtual environment in VSCode
to the one that is created for
our PyYelp project. Now. this
college is telling us that
letter pilot is not installed. So
let's go ahead and
install this as well. All
right. now in after
pie on the top. Let's
import the requests module. This
object has a method called get,
for sending
an http get request to an end point.
As I
told you before, every http request has a method and
that method determines what we want
to use the request for. So
get is for getting data. So here
we need to pass the URL or the address of an endpoint.
Back
to yelp Documentation here under Yelp fusion
. Let's take a look
at business and points here
. We have this business search endpoint that
is right here.
So you can see we have to send
a get request to the send point.
I'm going to copy this
address and then paste it here. Now
this get method returns a response object. Now
let's save the changes. Yes.
God is telling us that for matter. Auto
. Pepe is not installed in
our virtual environment. So let's go
ahead and install this as well. All
right. Now let's print this response. Save
the changes and run the program.
We got a response with
the status 401 which is
one of the standard http
. Error codes. So here on Google.
if you search for http
401 you can see that for one
represents unauthorized in this case.
we got this error because
we didn't tell Yelp who we are.
So every time you
want to call one of the endpoints of yelp,
we should send our API key
to tell yelp who we are.
This is what we call authentication.
Now
back on yelp documentation,
here under
yelp fusion,
let's take a look at the introduction document
under authentication. We have a
link to the authentication Guide
So this page is telling us that
we should first create an app to
get an API key.
We've already done that. Beautiful.
So
next is telling us to authenticate API calls
We need to set the Authorization HTTP header to
Bearer API_KEY.
What is going on here?
Well
these http requests have
two sections or two components:
The
header section and
the payload section.
In the header section we
have a few headers that
specifies some meta data about this
request. These headers are key value pairs. One
of these headers is
an authorization header which is
defined in the http protocol.
We use this header
to tell the web server who we are.
Let me show you how to do that.
So to make this code a little bit cleaner,
I'm gonna grab this
URL and store it in a separate variable.
Let's call
that url and then pass that here.
Now
this get method optionally takes keyword arguments.
One
of them is headers.
You can read this in the documentation of
the requests package on pypi.
We can set
this to a dictionary of key value pairs.
So
for clarity I'm going to
create that dictionary separately. Let's
set headers here to a new dictionary. In
this dictionary. we're going to
have a key called Authorization. And
we should set this to bear followed by
a space and our API key. So
back on Yelp here.
let's go to manage AB
and grab our topic. So copy this. And
now let's store that in a separate variable.
So a p I underline key
. We set this
to this strength. Make sure
you don't accidentally put a space here.
Otherwise. Yelp is going to tell
us that it didn't receive
a valid API key. So no
space here and also no
space at the beginning. Right
. So here's my API key. Now we
need to append that here. Epic. Finally
. we set the headers here.
save the changes. Let's
run the program one more time.
Okay. This time
we got a response with a
different status code, that is 400.
Once again if you search for http 400, you
can see that 400 represents
a bad request. Which means
the server expected some data and
we didn't supply that.
How
do we know what the server expected?
Well this
response object has an attribute called text.
With
that we can see the details of
what the server sent us. So let's
run the program one more time.
This is a JSON object
with a property called error.
which is set to another JSON
object and
hear the error message says "Please specify
a location or a latitude and longitude. So
back to yelp.
Let's look at the documentation for this endpoint.
That
is under business endpoints. Let's
expand this one more time.
It's right here. Business search. So
these are the parameters that we
can send to the server. One of
them is turned. which is optional.
Another one is location
. which is required. And here
are some examples. We can set that
to something like New York
City or N Y. C or
an address. so we can
either send the location or a
latitude and longitude. So now
let me show you how
to pass parameters when sending http requests.
This
get method of the request object. Optionally takes
another keyword argument, params.
Just
like the headers. We set this
to a dictionary. so I'm going
to define a dictionary here. perhaps. and
set the location key to.
let's say. in New York City
. And then it passed
this keyword argument here. Save
the changes around the
program one more time.
Okay.
This time we didn't get an error.
Instead we got a JSON object
that includes the list of
businesses in New York City.
Now
let's filter this.
So in our params object I
also want to set the term to Barber. So
I only want to see the barbers in New York City.
Save the
changes and run this one more time.
If
you scroll to the top,
we can see that this JSON
object has a property called businesses. and this
is set to an array because here
we have square brackets.
In
this array we have a
bunch of JSON objects because we
have curly braces. so back to
our response object. Now.
instead of using the text attribute. I'm
going to call the Jason Method.
and this will convert the
result into a dictionary so we can
store that in a variable called result. Now
. as you saw. this dictionary
has a key called businesses that
is set to a list
so we can immediately access
this key businesses. And
let's rename this variable to businesses. Now
we have a list of dictionaries.
Now. in this print. the
business is variable. so
we get a list of dictionaries.
Each dictionary has
this key value pairs id, alias, name
and so on.
So this is the name of the business.
Now
let's say we only want to get
the name of this businesses.
So
we can simply iterate over this list,
get each dictionary
and extract the value of the name key.
So for
business and businesses. we
can print business of name.
Let's save the changes.
Run the program one more time.
That
is better.
Now let's take this to the next level.
We
can use a list comprehension to
get the name of businesses that
are rated 4.5 stars or higher.
So remember
list comprehension. The syntax is like this item
for item enlist in this case. our list
as businesses. Each item is a business which
is a dictionary object now to
get the name of the business here
with type business of name. So
this list comprehension will return
the list of these businesses. Now
we want to filter. So if business
of grating that's another property
that we have in the
result. So if the rating
is greater than 4.5. then
we want to add the name of
the business to the list. Finally. we'll start
to result in names. and then we can
simply print the names variable.
Let's
run the program one more time.
So these are the highest rated barbers in New York City.