So in our current implementation.
we have stored the api key in
our source code. There's a problem with this.
If you have this
code for version control system
like get and publish it
to get to this API key is visible to anyone who
has access to that Git hub repository.
And that means
they can create an application
and malicious application and use
our API key to pretend to be us.
That's not good. So
if they violate. any of the policies
of Yelp we';; be in trouble. So
How to prevent this?
Well. we need to extract this
API key. put it in a
separate file and exclude that file
from get Let me show you
how to do that. So that's
pretty easy. We add a
new file here. Let's call that
config. That pie in this
file will have all kinds
of configuration parameters or applications. So now
back to after pie.
I'm going to move line for into
conflict that pie so cut. then we'll
be here. Save the
changes now back to after
the pie on the top. we import this
conflict module in this module.
we have an attribute called
api key. right.
So we can access it using
the data operator. So this
is where we're referencing the API
key. We need to
prefix that with config dot
That was the first step.
Now. to exclude this file
from git,
we need to come to our project,
add
a new file and
call it dot gitignore.
Here we can specify what
files and directors should be excluded from
our git repository. So currently. that
is config that point save the changes. So
now when we push our code to git hub Repository,
our config file
will not be there.
So if you're working in a team, every developer
needs to create this conflict file on their own machine.
So it's
the responsibility of the team leader
who has access to the API key,
to give the API key to every developer in the team.