In this lecture I'm going to teach you
How to send text messages using TWILIO.
TWILIO is a very popular communication platform for
adding voice, video and messaging to our applications.
For
example, you can quickly
make and receive video calls,
send
text messages, and
this is particularly useful for confirming reservations,
sending appointment reminders or promotions.
The possibilities are
endless.
They provide an API that is perfectly documented
and it's super easy to use.
So we can directly communicate with
this API by sending http requests using the
request module.
But they also provide a library that
we can install using pip or penv.
This library
is essentially a wrapper around their API.
So
it gives us objects, and
these objects encapsulates all
that http communication, so
we no longer have to work at
a low level of sending
http requests to twilio API,
we work at a higher level,
in a more abstract and
simplified fashion.
Their objects,
these objects have methods,
recall them and they
internally will take care of
sending the right http requests to
twilio api.
All right.
so the first thing you need to do is
to create a twilio account.
Let's go to the sign up page.
Here
we have a simple form.
You need to provide your First Name, Last Name
Email and Password.
On the next page, It's going to ask you
to provide a phone number, and
this is used to verify your
account.
So pause the video and do these steps when you're done, come
back continue watching.
Okay
so here we are on twilio console.
On the left side,
let's go to phone numbers.
we need to provision a
phone number for
sending text messages or
making phone calls.
So let's click "Get Started" and
then click "Get your first Twilio phone number".
All
right.
This is the number we're going to use to send a text message in the
next step.
So let's go ahead and
choose this number.
Beautiful.
We have set up our account.
Now we are ready to write a program to send
a text message using Twili.
So let's start
by creating a brand new project.
We're going to call that PyText.
Now let's go to this folder and
open it in VSCode.
All
right.
Here first we need to install Twilio.
So pipenv
install twilio.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Now let's add a new file here, We
call it app dot py.
Next we
need to select our virtual environment.
So we can either click this
virtual environment on the status bar
or we can press
shift command and p on Mac or
shift control
p on windows.
Here we search for python
interpreter. There you go. So let's select that, and
we set this to PyText.
Okay.
Now from twilio dot rest
we need to import the client class. So
this class represents a client to twilio rest
API.
Now let's create a client object. Here
We need to pass an account_sid,
which is short for security identier
as well as an authentication token.
We can find both
these on twilio console.
So here on twilio
console, on the top,
you can see the PROJECT NAME, right
below that we've got ACCOUNT SID or security Identifier
Let's copy this.
Now back In VSCode. Here
I'm going to store this in a separate variable.
So later we can export
this and put it in a separate module.
So account
sid we set it to this string. Now
back to twilio consol, below
accounts it We've got authentication
token. So let's view that, copy and
then similarly
we're going to store it in a separate variable, so auth
underlying token, we set it to this string.
Now
we create a client object and
pass account_sid as
well as the authentication token.
And here's
our client object.
This client object has a few interesting
attributes.
The one that we're going to look at in this lecture is messages,
and we use that to send text messages.
We also have calls
for making voice calls.
We've got fax, video, chat
and so on.
So messages.
Now
this object has a method called create. Here
We need to pass three pieces of information.
to
which we set to a phone number,
from
underline which we set to our twilio number.
This
is the phone number that we generated earlier.
And
finally body, let's
say "This is our first message".
So with only
four lines of code we can
easily send a text message to
any numbers in the world.
This create method takes care of
sending the right http request to twilio api.
So
finally it will return a call object.
This call
object has attributes, like
date_created, date_sent, date_updated and so
on.
So this was the
basics of sending text messages using TWILIO.
Now earlier
when we consume the yelp api,
I told you that you should not store
this kind of information in your source code
and then check it into a version control
system like git.
So as a best practice, we should
take these two variables out,
put them in a separate file and then
exclude that file from our version control system.
But I'm
not going to do that, because
you already know how to do it and
I don't wanna waste your time repeating what you already know.