So you have learned how to consume APIs
using the request module.
However
not every website has an API for us to work with.
So
in situations like that, the only
way to get the data we want
is to parse the HTML behind a Web page,
get rid
of all the HTML tags, and
extract the actual data.
This
technique is called web scraping.
so we scrape all
the HTML tags and
get the actual data that we want and
that's what I'm going to show you in this tutorial.
So we're going to write a
program that will extract the
list of newest questions on
stack overflow dot com.
We refer to this kind of program as
a Web crawler or a Web spider.
So let me show you how
to build a Web crawler in Python. So
here in a new project,
first we need to install beautiful
soup version four.
This is a very popular
python package for extracting information from HTML and
XML files.
So let's go ahead. Beautiful.
We also need to install the requests module to download the Web
page that contains the newest
questions on Stack overflow. So
pipenv install requests.
All
right.
Now let's add a new file here, app dot py.
First let's change our virtual environment, so I'm
going to set that to PyCrawler virtual environment. Let's
install pylint. So
the first step is to download the
Web page that contains the newest questions.
Let's import the requests module and
then we call get and pass https stack
overflow dot com slash questions. Now
we get the response and store it here. This
response object as you have
seen before as an attribute called
text. and this returns the HTML content of this Web page.
So using this HTML content
we can create a beautiful soup.
Let me show you.
So from bs4 let's
import the BeautifulSoup class. Now
here we create a BeautifulSoup object and pass
our HTML content.
Now here we can get the HTML content from
the Web page on the Internet, but
we can also read the content of an
HTML file on disk.
BeautifulSoup doesn't care, as
long as we give it a string that
contains some HTML or XML content,
it's happy.
Now as the second argument we need to pass the
type of parser.
Because we're gonna parse on html file, We
should pass html dot parser. And
with this we get a soup object.
Now
this soup object
mirrors the structure of our HTML document so
we can easily navigate this document and
find various elements.
Now
back here.
Let's right click on the first question and
inspect it.
So here's the structure of
our document.
Here we have an anchor that contains the
title of Our question.
Now let me expand these
elements here.
So we have this div with the ID questions and
this is the container for all our questions.
let's look at one of
this questions.
That's a div with the class question dash
summary, inside of this div we have two
other divs,
one with the class statscontainer that
includes the number of votes and answers,
and another div
with the class summary that
contains the title and summary of
our question.
So using our super object, we need to find
all elements with the class
question dash summary. That's
pretty easy.
So soup has a method called
select that takes a CSS selector.
If you're
not familiar with CSS selectors,
you really need to learn that on your own because
that's beyond the scope of a python course.
But basically a CSS
selector is a string that
helps us find an element in
an HTML document.
So here we want to get all elements with
the class question dash summary.
We type dot to
specify a class and then
the name of the class, question
dash summary.
This will return a list.
Let's store
that here.
Each item in this list is an instance
of the tag class.
Let me show you.
So I'm going to print the
type of the first question, questions of
zero.
Let's save the changes.
Run the
program.
We get this error: No module named 'bs4',
because Code Runner is using
the wrong python interpreter. I
showed you how to fix this issue earlier.
so I'm not going to repeat that here.
nstead I'm going to run this program
using the terminal. So
python3 app dot py. So
each object in this list is
an instance of the tag class. In
this case, this tag object
represents this div here, the
first question.
Now as you see this element has a couple
of attributes, class and id.
These attributes
are stored in a dictionary in our tag object.
Let me
show you.
So I'm going to print questions
of zero dot attributes.
Save
the changes.
Let's run it one more time. So
here we have a dictionary with two key value pairs.
There's the
first one, class and
here's the second one. Now
we can easily read these
attributes using square brackets, so we
don't have to access the attributes dictionary,
we can simply use
square brackets here to get
the value of the id
attribute.
Now if this element doesn't have this attribute, we're
going to get an exception.
So a safer way is to call the
get method, get id.
And we
can optionally supply a default value. So
this is all about the attributes.
Now we need to get the
title for each question.
So back to our HTML document.
Here's our question summary
inside this day we have this
day with the class summary.
Let's expand that.
We have an h3
with an anchor that
contains the title of our
question.
Now look at the class attribute here. The
class of this element is question dash hyperlink. So
back to our code, this tag object also has this
select method, like the soup object,
and here we can pass another
CSS selector, in this case question dash hyperlink
Let's save the changes
Run the program again. This
returns a list of objects.
You can see the first object
here is our anchor.
Now in this particular case,
we know that each question has one title.
so we don't
need a list here.
We have another method called
select one that returns
one object instead of a
list.
And this is more efficient in situations where we know
we're dealing with a single element.
So we don't waste time searching
the entire document for more items.
So save
the changes.
Let's run this one more time. Now
we have one anchor.
So the next step is to get the
actual text here.
This is the title of a question.
This
tag object has a method called get text.
Let's try this so back
to the terminal. Let's run the
program and here's the title
of our first question. So
next we need to iterate over all
the questions and get the title of
each. So for question in
questions. let's print question
that select one and then get text.
save the changes. Run
the program one more time.
Here are all the questions Beautiful
. The last step is to
get the votes for each question. So
back to our HTML document.
As I told you before. each
question summary has a div
with the class status container
. Here we have another child
a div with a class stats
and we've got the votes right here. So
we have a span with
the class vote count Post. So
similarly. we print question dot select
one. The name of
the class is Vote count
post and once again we call get
text to get the text
inside of the span element
save the changes.
Run
the program one more time,
and we successfully got all the
newest questions and their vote on
the first page.
Now. to get the questions on
page two and onwards. we need
to follow the same approach. So
first we need to find
the pagination component on this
page. Here we can
find the last page. So
we extract that here and
then run this logic inside of
a loop.
In this loop, in each iteration,
we'll get the questions for specific page.