let's say you get hired as a test
engineering at a Web development company. Every
day you have to test various
functions of a website. Doing so requires
a lot of manual and repetitive work.
You have to launch your browser directed
to the address of your website.
click on a few lengths here and there. perhaps
fill out the form and repeat
all these with different values several
times a day. This is very time consuming.
and it doesn't scale. So
that's where selenium comes in the picture.
With selenium. we
can automate our browser so we
can write a bunch of scripts to
test various functions of our website.
Here's an example. Let's
say we want to test the
logging functionality of git hub dot com
so we'll have to launch our browser
head over to get a job dot
com. click on the sign in link. then
fill out this form and
finally click on this avatar and check to
see if our user name is displayed
here or not. If not. that means
there's something wrong with the
log in functionality. So this
is an example of automated testing.
Now let me show you how
to do this with Python and Selenia. So
here in the brand new
project called Pi Selenium under Terminal
. let's run Pip and install Cellini. Um
. next we need a driver.
A driver is a piece of software to
automate a specific browser
for all these popular browsers
like chrome firefox and so on.
We have a web driver that we need to
manually download. So head over two
pi pi dot org
and search for selenium Here
it is Now on this page.
if you scroll down under
drivers. you can see this table.
So here are the drivers
for chrome edge Firefox and Safari. In
this demo I'm going to automate chrome
So let me show you how to install
Chrome Driver Let's go here Now you can
see the latest release
is Chrome Driver version 2.44
Let's click this here In this director.
you can see
the chrome driver for
various operating systems. I use
a Mac so I'm going
to download this here we get
a zip file Let's extracted here So
we get an executable called chromedriver.
We need
to put this somewhere in the path.
If you're on windows, you
need to put this
in the Windows folder on C Drive.
If
you're on Mac or Linux, you need
to copy at your local BIN directory.
So
here on a terminal we can run.
Copy Chrome driver
two slash user slash local slash bin. That's
it. Now back to the school.
First. we need to
change our virtual environment to pi selenium. Beautiful
. Now on the top
from the selenium module. we
need to import the Web driver module in
this module. We have classes that
represent all the popular browsers like
Chrome, Firefox and so on.
So to automate chrome. we
need to create an instance
of the chrome class. So Web
driver dot chrome.
This is actually a class. but
we escaped. Intelligence shows it
as a module. so don't
worry about that. Let's create
an instance of chrome. and
this returns a browser object. Now
let's call browser that
get and head over to
https. get hub dot com. save
the changes and
run this program.
So this opened a new instance
of the chrome browser. and as you can see.
we're on git hub dot com. Beautiful
. Next minute to click on this
signing link So we need to tell
selenium to find this element
and click it. Now. when
it comes to finding elements.
we have a few different options. We can
find elements by their
i d class. name and
tag. So let's right click this element and
inspected. So here's our signing link
. We have an anchor with these classes.
None of these classes
uniquely identify this link because
we have header menu Dash
link which can be reused somewhere else.
We also have no underlying
as well as m R.
Three. So these are pretty generic classes
. so we cannot find
this element using its class. Also
. as you can see here.
we don't have the idea attribute. So
in this particular case. the only
way to find this element is
by its text. Let me show
you how to do that. So back
in the escort.
let's call browser that find element
by Lenk text. So
our link text is signing.
Make sure to spell this
exactly as you see on the Web page.
In this case. if we use a
lower case s. this method is
going to raise an exception. telling
us that there is no element
with this link text. So sign
in. Now this returns a web element. We
can get that and store it
in a variable like sign in link
. Now. to click this.
we can simply call the click Method. so
sinan dot click. save
the changes. Run the program again.
Okay,
we're heading over to get hub.
And now we are on the sign in
page. Beautiful.
The next step is to fill out this form. We're
going to follow the same approach.
so we inspect this
element. Right. Click and go to inspect. All
right. here's our input. Phil. As you
can see here. we have an i d
and this uniquely identify as this
element on our web page. So
this time we can find
this element by its ID. The
idea is. log in filled.
So I'm gonna copy this Now
. back in V s code.
let's call browser that find element
by i d. We passed the idea here
. This time we
get the user name box
. Okay. Now we want
to fill this out. So
here we have a method called
Sant Keys that simulates a user
typing in the text box.
So username box that
send keys. I'm going to type this
username ninja coder 22. Similarly
. we need to fill out
the password field. So here's our
password field. And as you can see.
the idea of
this field is passport.
So back in the U. S. Code
. I'm gonna duplicate there's two alliance and
change this to password box. Let's
change the idea to password and also
in line 12. Let's change
this to password box and
the password I'm going to pass
year is Today is Monday one
. Don't try this because I'm going
to change this after recording this lecture. What
. You can trade with your own
user and password. So we filled out the
farm. Now we need to submit it.
That is pretty easy. So
we call password box dot Submit. Save
the changes. Let's run the
program one more time. Okay
. We're going to get hub.
We logged in. and here
we are. So this
is my avatar. You saw
that happened pretty quickly. No human
can do it that fast. Finally
. to ensure that this
logging function works properly. You want
to make an assertion.
So when we click on this
avatar. we see our user
name displayed here. So here
we can make an assertion
that Ninja Coder 22 is rendered
in the html of this web page.
Here's one way. So
let me show you back
in the S code. So this
browser object has an attribute called Page Source
Again. we s code is making
a mistake here is displaying this
as a function. but it's
an attribute and this returns the
html content of this web page.
Now. in Python
. we have this
statement called Assert. and with
this. we can verify something.
For example. we want to verify that
Ninja Coder 22 is
in this string. So page source returns a
string that is the HTML content of this web page. Now
. if we do have ninja coder
20 to hear our program will continue
execution without any problems. Otherwise. if we
don't have this text in our HTML.
this is going to throw an
exception. So to simulate that. let me change
22 to 23.
Obviously. we don't have this. So
let's run the program
and see what happens. So
we're gonna log in
one more time. Beautiful. Now
back Invesco here on the terminal.
You can see. we have an
assertion error. So we asserted
that Ninja Code A 23 is
in the html of this Web page.
and that assertion failed
. However. if we change
that Tunisia Coder 22 and
run the program again this
time we don't have any exceptions on the terminal.
So this is the idea behind
assertions and automated testing. Now this assertion
is kind of general. Let me
show you a more specific assertion. Back
to git hub dot com.
When we click on this avatar, we see this drop
down box. Let's right
click and this element and
inspected. Okay. here's our label. It's inside
of a strong tag.
and the strong tag is part of
this anchor. which is part of
this list item. To do a more
specific assertion. we can find this anchor look
at its inner HTML and
ensure that here we have Ninja
Coder 22. This is more
specific than searching for ninja
Coder 22 in the entire HTML. right. So
look at our anchor.
Here we have this class user profile
link so we can find
this element using its class so
browser dot find element by class user
profile link. So
let's store that in profile link. Now
we need to get the inner HTML of this link. so we call
profile link that get attribute. The
attribute name is inner HTML. Now
we get the result and
store it and link labour
. Finally. we can
assert that Ninja Coder 22
is in link label. So
that was the basics of using
selenium to automate our browser. Now
there are more advanced topics
about automatic testing with selenium that
goes beyond the scope of this course.
So if you want to learn more. search
for python selenium on this page.
selenium-python.readthedocs.io ,
we
can read about these advance scenarios.
The two sections that
I highly encourage you to
read about are Waits and Page Objects.
This is a pattern that
helps you organize your code in a
reusable fashion. and it's
extremely important when testing a
real application with tens
or hundreds of functions. You
don't want to write all your test
code in a linear fashion like this
. you want to organize it into
classes with methods that you can reuse
in many different scenarios.
and one last thing before we finish
this lecture. Whenever you're done
with your browser object. you
need to call the quit method. Otherwise.
you will end up with so many open browser
windows. So down the bottom
recall browser dot quit