In this lecture you're going to learn
how to work with PdF files in Python. As
I showed you earlier in the course,
there are several packages to work with pdf
files and unfortunately
most of these are either unstable or
poorly documented.
The one that is more popular is pypdf2
and that's what we're going to use in this lecture.
So here in
a brand new project under Terminal, let's install
pypdf2. Okay.
Now here in the app.py on the top,
let's import
pypdf2.
In this module we have a
few classes to work with PDF files.
let's take a
look.
We've got PdfFileReader, PdfFileWriter and
PdfFileMerger.
I'm going to give you a quick overview of
each of these classes.
Let's start with PdfFileReader. So
here when creating a PdfFileReader,
we need to pass a
file stream.
This is the object that the built in
open function returns.
So using the
open function, let's open,
here I got a couple of pdf files
first and second.
You can download this as a
zip file attached to this lecture but
there is nothing particularly about this. You
can use any PdF files you want.
So let's
open first.pdf.
It's very important to
open this file in the binary mode.
So as the
second argument,
we need to pass rb which is
short for read in binary.
Now we get a file
stream object.
Let's use the with statement here. And
here's our file stream object.
So we pass this right
here and we get a file a
pdf file reader object.
Now this reader object has
a few interesting members.
One of them is num pages
which returns the number
of pages in your pdf. Let's
print that. Yeah. so
in this file we have only a single page.
We
also have this method getPage that
takes a
page number, but more accurately
this parameter should
have been called Page Index because
the index of the first page
is zero.
So here we passed zero to get the first page. This
returns a page object.
This page
object has a few interesting members.
like rotate clockwise
as well as rotate counterclockwise. We also have
a scale as well as
scaled by a given factor or
scaled to a given width and height.
You can read about this
in the documentation for this package.
In this demo. I'm
going to use the rotate method.
So let's rotate this
90 degrees clockwise.
Now what you need to
understand here is that this
does not modify the original pdf
. This is only rotating
the page object in memory. So
we need to write this
to a separate pdf file. For
that we need a PdfFileWriter.
So PyPDF2
.PdfFileWriter.
Now
here we don't pass any arguments.
It simply creates a writer object,
so we're dealing with a
writer object in memory, not a file on
disk.
So now we call
writer.addPage and
then we pass this page object here.
This method will
add this page object at the
end of this new pdf in
memory.
We also have another method insert
page that takes an index. So if you
want to reorder PDFs, you can
use this method to add pages at
specific indexes.
We also have insertBlankPage
that doesn't take any arguments.
So
let's regard this back to addPage and pass this
page object.
Now finally we need to write this
Pdf in memory to
a file on disk. For
that. we need another five stream
so we can use the with statement
here to open another file like
Rotated that PdF and as the second
argument. But it to pass w B.
which is short for write
binary. Very important to
pass this argument. Otherwise it's
not going to work.
Let's call this fine stream
output Now. Finally. we call writer that
. Write to this file strain. Let's
save the changes.
Run this program. So
here's my first pdf.
We have some basic text here. and
here's our rotated pdf.
So as you can see with
Python, you can easily write
a script to iterate over all
the PDFs in the directory
and process them by rotating
them, scaling them, or combining them.
So let me show
you how to combine multiple
PDFs into a single PdF so
back to VSCode.
As I showed you earlier. in this module we
have this class PdfFileMerger and
we use this to merge multiple pdf files.
So let's
create a merger object. Now
let's say we have an array of file names.
So file_names.
We set this to an array of two strings,
first.pdf and second.pdf.
In a
real world application instead of
this hard coded area, you can iterate
over all the PDFs in the directory.
So here
we have all the final names.
Let's iterate over this array. So
for file name in file names
we simply call merger.append and
pass this fine name as simple as that. So
up to this point we're merging
these PDFs in memory. Finally we
need to write the result to a file on disk.
And
that is pretty easy.
So merger.write. Now
here we can pass a file
object or a string that specifies
the name of the file.
So let's call that combined the
PdF and run this program. So
here's our combined PdF.
It has two pages. The first page
comes from our first PdF,
and here's the second page that
comes from the second pdf.