In Python Community,
We have a bunch of documents called python enhancement proposals
or peps here on Google.
If you search for python peps, you can see the list of all
this paps under python.org slash Dev slash peps.
Let's have a quick look here.
So here are the paps we can see each pep has a number and
a title.
The one that is very popular amongst python developers is
pep 8, which is a style guide for python code. a style guide
is basically a document that defines a bunch of rules for
formatting and styling our code.
If you follow these conventions the code that you write will
end up being consistent with other people's code.
If you have time you can go ahead and read this Pepe documentation.
But if not, don't worry because throughout this course I'm
gonna explain the key things in pep 8. In this lecture,
I'm gonna show you a tool that helps you automatically
format your code according to pep8.
So back in vs code.
Let's write some python code x equals 1. here
I'm declaring a variable and setting it to one.
If you're not familiar with variables,
Don't worry, in the next section
You're gonna learn about them.
So according to pep8 this code is considered ugly.
Because by convention we should add a space around this equal
sign or the assignment operator.
Now since you're starting out with python, you probably don't
know these rules.
So let me show you a tool that helps you automatically format
your code.
Let's revert this back to its original state.
Now.
We need to go back to the command palette remember so it's
right here under View and the shortcut is shift command and
pee. Here if you search for format, you can see this command:
Format Document. The first time you execute this command, you're
going to see this message here. formatter autopep8 is not
installed. So there are a bunch of tools for formatting python
code. The most popular one is auto pate and this is the tool
that this python extension
We installed uses to format our code.
So let's go ahead and install this. Good. now one more time
Let's open up the command palette and execute format document.
See, this tool automatically formats out code, beautiful.
Let's take a look at another example.
I'm going to declare another variable Y and set it to two
and if variable with the long name like unit underlined prize.
I'm set this to 3.
Now some developers have this habit of formatting there variable
declarations like this.
So they put all these equal signs and the same column. According
to pep8
this is considered ugly.
So once again, let's format our code. That is better, beautiful.
Now let me show you a trick. opening up this command palette and
searching for format document every time is a little bit
time consuming.
So I wanna show you how to have your file automatically
formatted as soon as you save the changes.
On the top.
Let's go to the code menu preferences and settings.
Here in the search box search for formatOnSave.
So we have this option editor format on Save take this. Now
back to app.py
I'm going to change the formatting of these lines make them
really ugly.
Now,
As soon as I save the changes you can see my code is reformatted.
beautiful.