mhm. Yeah. In
this section. we're going to look at
the built in data structures in python. which
are extremely important when building real applications. First
. we're going to look at lists.
and then we'll look at topples, sets and
dictionaries. So earlier. you have
seen that we can use square
brackets to define a list
or a sequence of objects
. In between these brackets.
we can have objects of any type so
we can have a list
of strings like this and
then assigned to a variable like letters. We
can also have a list
of numbers Boolean or even a
list of lists. Let me show you.
So here we have a
list. Each item in this
list will be a list
itself. So here's the first item. which is
a list of two items.
Now let's add another
item to our main
or parent list. This item
is also a list with two items. so
now we have a matrix.
which is a two dimensional
list. Now let me show
you some cool tricks. Let's
say you want to have
a list of 100 zeros. You
don't want to manually create that like this.
That's very ugly. Let me
show you a better way.
So we define a list of one item
on zero and then we
can multiply it by 100
and the result will be this.
Let me show you print
zeros. Here it is. There
you go. So. using a
star or an asterisk we
can repeat the items in
a list. Now Similarly we
can use a plus
to concatenate multiple lists. Let
me show you. So first.
I'm going to change this to five
. Now let's define a variable combined. which
is our zeros list. plus letters. Let's
see what happens. Print combined. You
know it. So we
have five zeros. followed by
ABC. As you can see in Python, every
object in the list can be of
a different type. so they don't have to
be exactly the same type.
We can combine a list of numbers with
strings and bullion or even lists. Now
let's say you want to have
a list of numbers like 0123 all
the way up to 20. You don't want
to type all of this by hand. There
is a better way.
So we had this list function as
you can see this function
takes an iterable so we
can pass any iterable here and
convert it to a list. Earlier
. you learn about the range function.
This function returns a
range object. which is iterable.
which means we can iterate or
loop over it. So here
we can call this function and
past 20 and with
this we can create a
list of numbers from 0 to 20.
Then I'll show you. So let's
story in numbers and then printed on
the terminal. There you go. So zero up
to 20. But note that
20 itself is not included as
another example. Let's call the list function and
pass a string.
Earlier. I told you that strings
are also vulnerable. We can loop
over them so we can pass them
to the list function and
see what we get. Let's
print chars on the terminal so
you can see each character
in our original string is
an item in this list.
So these are a few
different ways to create a
list in Python. Now that we
have a list. we can get the
number of items in that list using
the land function.
So here we can print the
len or length of chars. Let's take
a look. So we have
11 items in this list. Over
the next few lectures
we'll look at various operations around lists.