Here's another scenario for using a lambda function.
so we have our
list of items. Let's say we
want to filter this list and
only get the items
with price greater than or
equal to $10 again. One basic way is
to define an empty list like filtered. Then
we each right over our list
of items for each item we
get the price. If it
matches our criteria. will add it
to this list. But that's pretty basic.
A better approach is
to use the built in filter function. Look
at the parameters.
This function just like the map function takes
two parameters:
a function and an
iterable.
so it will apply this function on
each item of this iterable.
If the item matches some
criteria, it will return it. So, let's
see how we can use this function.
As the first argument we're
going to pass a lambda function.
This function takes
and I am and
returns a Boolean value that
determines if this item matches the criteria or
not. In this case.
we want to get the price of
each item and see if
it's greater than or equal to
$10. So the result of
this expression is a boolean
value. If it's true.
this item will be returned. Now
. as the second argument to
the filter function. we pass our items
list. Let's temporarily store the result in
a variable called X and then printed. So
we get a filter object.
A filter object, just
like a map object, is
iterable so we can loop over
it and we can also convert
it to a list right away
. So let's call list. Now
we get filtered list that we can print
on the terminal. So as you can see.
we only have product one
and three because their prices are greater than