So here's the usage of map and filter
functions that you just learn about. These
two functions are pretty useful in python.
and they are often used
by developers who come from
a functional programming background. So
the concept of mapping and
filtering lists is very natural
to them. But in Python
we have another feature for
achieving the same result. And as
far as I know. we don't have
this feature in other programming languages.
That is called comprehension
. So let me show you
how that works. Here is the
basic syntax:
We add our square brackets for
defining a list. And here
we'll write a comprehension expression
like this expression for items
in items. Well. this part
is very familiar to you.
right. It's like a for loop. So
we're iterating over and iterable and then applying
this expression on each item.
In this example. if
you want to get the price of each item.
we can write an expression like
this item of one. So this
is what we call a list comprehension.
and it produces the
exact same result as what we have on
line seven. So let's store the result in
prices as you can see
this coat is shorter and cleaner
. We don't have all
these parenthesis and colon. In
my opinion. what we have online
seven is a little bit ugly and
noisy now. Some developers might
disagree with me;
but generally
speaking in the Python community,
the preferred way to
map and filter lists is
to use a list comprehension.
But I wanted to include the
map and filter functions in this course because
. as you look at the
code written by others will probably come
across instances of using
the map and filter functions
. So I wanted to make sure
that you really understand how they work. But
as a best practice. my recommendation
to you is to use a list
. Comprehension is because they are
cleaner and also more performant. So
this is how we can use a
list comprehension to map a list into
a different kind of list.
Now. as part of this mapping. we
can also filter items.
So if I want to
rewrite what we have online 10.
Using a list comprehension
that would look like this filtered.
we set it
to square brackets. So we're
defining a new list. No
need to call the list
function in between. the brackets
will write an expression.
So here is the syntax expression for
item in items.
Now. what is the expression here
. Well. in this case. we don't want
to map the list of items to list of
prices. so our expression is simply the item
itself. So. basically. we'll iterate over the
list of items will get each
item and simply return it. However
. you want to filter them
so we'll add. And if statement
if item of one is greater than or
equal to 10 once again.
I personally find what
we have online. 11. More readable
and cleaner than what we have
online. 10. But if you want to
use the map or filter functions,
that's perfectly fine.