Here we have to list. Let's say we
want to combine these two lists into
a single list of topples like this. So
we have a list where
each item is a topple and
in the first couple. we're going
to have the first element of each
list. So one and 10 Similarly. in the
second Topple. we're going to have
the second element of each list. And
finally. the third Topple. How can we
combine these two lists into
a single list like this. Well
. in this case. we can use
the map function or a list comprehension
because both these work
with a single list. But
here we're combining multiple lists. To achieve this
. we use the
built in zip function. So
zip. Look. this function takes multiple deliverables
and it will combine them the
way I showed you. So we
pass list one and list too. Let's
print the result on the terminal. So
look, it returns a zip object
which is also iterable.
So we can iterate over
it or simply pass it to
the built in list function to convert it
to a list. Now. let me
show you something cool as you
saw this zip function
takes one or more honorables
so we don't have to pass a list here.
I can also pass a
string like ABC and look
at the result. So now our strength ABC
is spread across multiple topples in
this list. That's pretty powerful.
If you want to actually have the same thing
in other programming languages you have to write several lines of code,
but in Python we can do it in a single line.