In the last lecture. you learn about stacks.
you learn that stacks have
delightful behavior. Last in. First out
. we have another very
useful data structure called Q. which
has the Pfeifle behavior first in First Out
. and it resembles a Q.
In the real world. let's say
a queue of people to get
into a restaurant. The first person in
the queue is the first person
who would get in Now. Technically. you
can use a list to
implement a Queue in python. So
let's say we have a queue of three items.
If you want to remove
an item from this. Q.
We should remove the one at the
beginning as opposed to the
one at the end. So
we removed one and then
two and then three. However
if you're dealing with a large
list or a large Queue, you might see
some adverse effect on the performance because
let's say we have a large
number of items in this list. Every
time we remove an item from
the beginning of this list, all
the other items need to
be shifted to the left. So
if you have a list with 1000
and one items, when you remove one
item, 1000 items need to
be moved in memory. In
situations like that, it's more
efficient to use a DQueue
object. Let me show you
how to do that. So first
we need to import Dqueue
you from the collections module. I'm
going to talk about modules later in the course.
For now let's
imagine a module is a bucket
with a bunch of reusable code.
So from collections.
that's the name of our
module. We should import deque which is
a class.
Again I'm going to talk about classes later in the
course. so we import a deque class here.
Now,
instead of defining a variable and
sending it to an empty list, we
should wrap this list with a deque object.
So we
call deque and pass
our empty list as an argument.
This
deque object has similar methods that we have in
the list object.
So we can call queue dot append.
Let's
append a few items here. 1 2 3.
Now
to remove an item from the
beginning of the queue, We call queue
dot pop left.
We don't have this method in list
objects.
So after we remove one item, let's
look at our queue.
There
you go.
You can see one is removed and now we only have 2 and
3.
Also similar to lists, We can easily
check to see if a queue is empty using the not operator.
So
if not queue,
that means we have an empty
queue, then we can print something like empty.
So this is all about queues.