Now let me show you something really cool.
I'm going to define two
variables: x And y. A
basic exercise we give to
people who starting programming is
to write code to swap two variables. Do
you know how to do this?
If you don't pause the video and think
about it for a minute.
But here is the solution to
swap two variables.
we need a third variable. So
I'm going to define a third
variable like z and set it
to x. So basically
we're copying the value of x into
a separate variable as a backup.
Now we
can override x with y. So we
said x to y
we copy the value of
y two x.
Now we have the old value
of x stored in z.
So we
can use that to override y
we said y
to the With these three lines.
we can swap the
value of these two variables. So if
we print x as well as
y we will see that
x is changed to 11 and y is 10.
I've
got a good news for you;
In Python We can swap the
value of two variables using
only one line of code and
without a third variable.
let me show you. So instead
of writing these realigns.
we can simply right eggs
. comma y equals y.
Come on. X. Now. if
we run this code. we get
the exact same result. But let
me explain what exactly
happens under the hood.
Here
online four,
on the right side of the assignment operator,
we're
defining a tuple,
because in the last lecture I told you that
when defining a topple
you can use parenthesis or you
can exclude the parenthesis. So this code is
exactly equivalent to this: We have
a tuple,
What is y? it's 11,
What is x? It's
10.
Now, What do we have on line five? We
have a topple that we're unpacking.
So we're setting x
to 11 and
y to 10.
And that is
why with this line of code,
we can easily swap two variables.
For this very reason,
We can define multiple variables on
the same line.
so we can define a and b and set
them to 1 and 2.
Once again, we're
defining a tuple and
then unpacking it on the left side.
So a will be 1 and
b will be 2