So, you have learned a lot about
lists in Python. These lists are
very useful.
But if you're dealing with a large sequence of
numbers, we have a more
efficient data type in python called
array. These arrays take less memory and perform
a little bit faster.
But note that you will see the difference only
if you're dealing with a large
list of numbers, let's say 10,000 or
more. So for 90% of the cases. you
will use lists. But if you run
your program and you see some performance problems,
then you can see if you
can solve the problem by replacing a
list with an array.
If you don't have any performance problems
don't try to optimize.
In other words, don't solve a
problem that doesn't exist.
So let me show you how
to use arrays in python.
To use an
array we need to import it
from the array module. So on
the top from array import array.
So we have a module called array
and in this module we
have a class called array.
It has the same name as
the module itself.
Now we call array
Look at the first parameter.
This is called a typecode which is
a string that determines the
type of objects in your array.
So here in Google,
search for Python 3 type
code.
then click the first link.
In
this table, you can see all
the type code in Python. so
it's a string of one
character that determines the type
of objects in your list.
So if you're dealing with signed integers,
you should use a lower case i.
So here
let's add i.
And then as the second argument, we pass
a list of integers.
so we move this list here.
Now we get an array.
We can call it numbers.
In
this object, similar to lists,
We have methods for adding
new objects or removing existing ones.
so we can call numbers
dot append to append a number
to the end of the list. Or
we can use insert
to add a number at
a specific index. We also have pop and
remove exactly like lists.
and we can also access
items by their index.
So we can get the first item in
this array. However unlike lists, the
objects in this array are tight.
So here every
object should be an integer.
If we try to put a
floating point number here or any
other kind of objects will get
an error. let me show you.
So I'm going to change the first item
to 1.0. Now let's run the program. We
get this type error
in major argument expected. Got
float. So every object in this array should
be of the same type,
which is determined at the time of
creating the array using the typecode.
So to recap,
use arrays only if
you're dealing with a large sequence of
numbers and you encounter performance problems,
for other cases use lists and tuples by default.