In Python we have another very
useful data structure called a
set. which is basically a collection with no
duplicates. So let's say we
have a list of numbers
with a bunch of
duplicate items like this. If
you want to remove the duplicates.
you can convert this list to
a set. So I'm going
to define a variable, uniques. We
call the set function and pass the numbers
list. Now when we print this, take
a look, we only have unique items. so
one is not repeated.
Also note that we use
curly braces to define sets.
So here we can
define a second set using curly braces
with two items one and four.
Now similar to
list, we can add new items
to a set or remove an existing
one. So here we can
call second dot add; We
can append a new number here.
We can also
call remove and
we can use the len function
to get the number of items in
a set. So these
are the basics. but where
sets shine are in the powerful mathematical operations
that are supported by them.
Let me show you.
So I'm
going to delete these three lines,
These are pretty basic,
and
rename uniques to first.
So we
have two sets first and second.
Now we
can get a union of
two sets using the vertical bar.
So this expression will
return a new set that
includes all the items that
are either in the first or
in the second set.
Let me show you. So print. Actually
I'm going to change
this 4 to 5.
So now
when we run this code
you can see the union
of these two sets is another set that
includes all the items that are
either in the first set or the
second set.
We can also get the intersection
of two sets. So print first and
second. this will return
a new set that includes
all the items that are
in both first and second sets.
Take a look. So the only number
that exists in both
these sets is 1.
We
can also get the difference
between two sets.
So print
first minus second. When we
run this code. we get 2 3 4.
So
the first set has this additional
numbers that we don't have in
the second set.
And finally we have symmetric
difference. So print first carrot
second.
This will return
the items that are either in
the first or second set
but not both.
So
let's run this. We get 2 3 4 5.
Now
one thing you need to know
about sets is that unlike lists they're
unordered collection
which means the items that
we have in the set are not in sequence so
we cannot access
them using an index.
In other words if
we try to print first of zero. we
will get a runtime error set. Object does
not support indexing. So if
you need to access items
by index, you need to use a list.
With sets quite
often we use one of
these operations here or we can
check for the existence of an item in a set.
So we
can check to see if 1 is in the
first set. Then we can print Yes. there
you go.
So to recap, set is an
unordered collection of unique items.
We cannot have
duplicates and
these objects are unordered, They're not
in sequence, so we cannot access them using an index.