Here we are creating a list
using a list comprehension expression. Then
we iterate over all the
numbers in this list and print
them. When we run this program.
we get the even numbers from
0 to 18.
This is perfectly fine; but there
are situations that you might be
working with a really large dataset,
or perhaps an infinite stream of data.
In
those situations, you shouldn't store all
those values in the memory because
that's very memory inefficient. For example. What
if. instead of range of 10
here we had the range of. let's
say. a billion. We don't want
to store a billion objects in memory
that takes too much memory.
In situations like this, it's
more efficient to use a generator object.
generator
objects are iterable.
So just like lists, we can
iterate over them.
And in each iteration it generate or
spit out a new value.
So unlike lists, they
don't store all the values in memory,
they generate a
new value in each iteration.
Let me show you
how that works.
So here I'm going to replace these square
brackets with parenthesis.
save
the changes.
run the program.
we get the exact same result,
however values is no longer a list.
It's
a generator object.
Let me show you.
So print values.
run
the program.
We get a generator object.
So
as you can see, generator objects are iterable.
We can iterate over
them. In each iteration.
they spit out a new value. But
what is interesting,
is the size of generator objects.
Let
me show you how you can get
the size of an object. So on
the top from the sys module. we
should import a function called Get size off
. So here we have a generator object.
Let's change range to
1000. Now let's print the
size of this object. So
I'm going to delete everything here.
call. get size
of function. pass our generator object
and then print the result.
Let's also add a
label here. so generator run
the program so our generator object takes 100
and 20 bytes of memory.
What if we change the range to
100,000?
Let's run the program.
The
size of this generator object remains consistent. In
contrast,
if we used a list comprehension expression here,
we would end up with a list of 100,000 items.
Let
me show you. So I'm going to
copy this line and then duplicated and
change parenthesis to square brackets. So now
we have a list.
Let's copy this line as well. Change
the label and see the size
of this list. Run the program.
So our list is taking
over 800,000 bytes of memory compared to
our generator object that takes
only 100 and 20 bites. So
in situations where you're dealing
with a really large dataset
or potentially an infinite
stream of data, use a
generator expression to create a generator object. So
when we use parenthesis
around the comprehension expression, just
be aware that because generator
objects don't store all the
items in memory, you won't be able
to get the total number of items you're
working with.
For example:
Here let's
just keep the generator object and then
print the
len of values.
Let me run this code.
we'll get
an error.
Let's take a look.
Objects of type generator
has no land because we
can only access these items,
these values, when we
iterate over a generator object.
So
we won't know ahead of time,
how many objects or
how many items this generator is going to produce