There are times that you want to find
the index of a given object in
a list. So let's say we
want to find the index of
Letter a in our letters list.
We call letters
that index and pass a Let's
print the result. so this will return
. Zero. What if you
try to get the index of
an object that doesn't
exist here like d. we
get a value error.
D is not in the list. This
behavior is different from a
lot of programming languages out there.
C based languages return
negative one if you try to
get the index of an object
that doesn't exist in the list. But
in Python we get an error.
So to prevent this
from happening, first you should check to
see if the given object exists
in the list. And for that
we use the in operator. So
if d is in letters. then
we will print its index. So now
we run the program and we
don't get any errors. We also
have another method that you might
find useful in certain situations. and
that is count. So letters that count this
will return the number of
occurrences of the given item in
this list. So when
we print the result. we'll
get zero. Next. we're going
to look at sorting lists.