mhm. If you
have any experience with other programming languages.
you've probably heard
of the term Lambda
Expression or Lambda function. It's
basically a simple one line, anonymous function that
we can pass to other functions.
So here. online 12
. we're passing a reference
to our sort underlying item
function. We can improve this
code and make it cleaner
by using a lambda
expression or an anonymous function
. So we don't have to define
this function first and then pass it
here. So we remove this and
add Lambda. With this we're telling Python that
we're defining a lambda or anonymous function. The
syntax for writing a lambda function is like this:
We add parameters
colon expression. So using this syntax we
can rewrite this function.
How many parameters do we
have here? Only one.
So we add that here, item.
Then after the colon.
we should add an expression. What
are we returning in our sort
Underline item function? We
are returning item of one.
So we simply add that
here. item on one. Now we
can see with this syntax we
don't need to use def for defining
a function.
We don't need to give our function a name,
We
don't need these parenthesis here,
and we don't need the return statement. So
this is a shorter and
cleaner way to define a
function that we're going to use
only once as an argument to
another function. Now, Let's delete these
two lines.
Run our program again. We'll
get the exact same result.
Our items are sorted by the price.