Over the next two lecturers I'm going to
show you more examples of using lambdas
in your programs. So here we
have this list of items. Let's
imagine we want to transform
this list into a different shape.
So currently each item in
this list is a topple of
two items. Let's say
we're only interested in the
price of these items. so we
want to transform this list into
a list of numbers.
That is the list of prices. Here
is a basic way to do this.
We can define an
empty less. then iterate over our
list of items.
So for item in items we
call prices data hand item of
one which returns the
price of each item. Now
let's print the prices so we
get a list of numbers.
With this code we have transformed or
mapped our original list into a different list.
Okay. that there is a
better and more elegant way to achieve
the same result.
Instead of this loop, we can use the
map function. so we
call the built in map function.
As we can see. this
function takes two parameters:
a function and
one or more iterables.
So as the first argument we
can pass a lambda function.
And as the second argument we
can pass our list of items.
This map function
will apply our lambda
function on each item in
this list.
Let me show you what I mean. So it passed a
lambda. This lambda is
a function that will transform
each item in our original list. So
the parameter to dysfunction is item. And
here we simply want to return
the price of that item. So item
of one. Now. as the second argument to
the map function. we need
to pass our items list
. So this map
function will iterate over this
iterable and it will call this Lambda function
on each item of this vulnerable. Now
. let's see what this function
returns so temporarily I'm going to
assign this to a variable called eggs.
Let's print X
. And also we don't
need these three lines because
we can achieve the same result
using the map function so delayed
. Now. let's run this program.
So this map function returns
a map object which is another iterable. So
we can easily iterate over
it for item in X. we'll
print item. There
you go so we
get the prices. Alternatively we
can convert this map object
into a list object. So
we can use our list function. Earlier
you learn that you can
pass any iterables to this list function
to create a new list. So we
passed it here and now
we can rename X two
prices and simply print prices
. We don't need this loop here.
Let's run the program. So
we get a list of three numbers.
So this is
how the map function works.
It takes a lambda function and
applies it on every item of this iterable.