mhm. Yeah. Alright
. let's finish up this section by
looking at a few very useful shortcuts
for writing code fast. First.
I'm going to show you the shortcuts for
Windows users. and in the next lecture.
we'll look at the shortcuts format
. So if you're a Mac user.
feel free to skip this lecture. So
here we are on Line nine and
my cursor is right at the beginning of
the line. Let's say we want to move
the cursor to the end of the line
. Instead of pressing the right arrow
to go all the way to the end
. we can simply press the end key.
and here's the cursor. Or
if you want to move the cursor to
the beginning of the line. simply press the
home key. There you go. Similarly. if you
want to move the cursor to the
beginning of the file press control and
home here it is. or control an end
to go to the end of the file.
Now let's say we want to move this
line up instead of cutting
it from here and then
copying it somewhere else.
We can simply move it
up by pressing Ault and the up or
down arrows. Or. if you want
to move these two lines up
and down. simply select them.
then hold Ault and then up
or down. Very easy.
Now. If you want to duplicate a
line or multiple alliance. simply select them now
. Hold down.
shift hold and then press the
down key. We can duplicate it
as many times as you want. There
you go. Here's another useful shortcut. If
you want to convert this line.
or maybe these two lines into a comment. simply
hold down. Control and press Slash isn't
the same shortcut. You can remove
the comment so you can target
it very easy. And finally.
if you want to type the
name of a variable
or function like multiply. you
don't have to type all characters.
Here are a few ways to
type this quickly. You can
just type the first few characters
. and here in the intelligence you can see that.
So if you press enter. this
is what we call auto completion.
Here's another way. So
instead of writing the
first few letters. you can
just pick any letters
in sequence and type them
so I can type em t
y or I can just type M
p y or N Y.
There you go. Here it
is. So I hope you
enjoyed this shortcuts and thank