mhm. Yeah. Now
here's a question for you.
What is the difference between the great and
print functions. The difference is that
this print function takes an input. whereas our
great function doesn't take any input.
So let me show you
how to pass inputs like first
name and last name to dysfunction
when defining a function, in between parenthesis we'll
list are parameters.
So here we add two parameters,
like first under
line name and last underlie
name. Now when calling this function,
we need to
supply two values for those parameters. We
refer to them as arguments. So Marsh
Hamedani. these are the
arguments to the Greek function
. That's one of the terms that a
lot of developers out there don't know. They
don't know the difference
between parameters and arguments. A
parameter is the input that
you defined for your function. whereas
an argument is the actual
value for a given parameter.
Okay. now let's change
the line to and instead
of saying hi there. we can greet
a person by their full name so
we can convert this
to a formatted string and
past two fields here First name as well
as last name Save the changes run
the program. and this is
what we get in terminal. Now
. This function is more useful.
We can reuse it and call it
with different arguments. So that's great. John
Smith as well run the program so
we get high marks.
Hamedani and High John Smith. Now,
note that by default all the
parameters that you define for a
function are required. So here our greet function
takes two parameters. If I exclude one
of these arguments and save the changes. you
can see we have this red underline.
So Pilot is
complaining and saying there is
no value for argument last night
. Also. if we run the program.
we get this type error. Greet
missing one required positional argument. So
let's put this back now.
Later. I'll show you how