mhm. Yeah. Earlier
. I told you that all the
parameters that you define for a function are
required by default. In this lecture.
I'm going to show you how
to make the by parameter optional. So let's
say we don't want
to explicitly pass by equals
one. Every time we want
to call this increment function. we
want to use this function
to increment value by one. So
we removed the second argument.
Now we need to give this parameter
a default value. so we
set it to one. Now
. if we call this function
and don't supply the second argument
. this default value will be used.
Otherwise the value that
we specify here will be used.
Let me show you. So we
run this program. The result is three. But
if we pass. the second argument here will
increment to buy five.
so we will get seven so
you can see it's pretty easy
to make a parameter optional. Just
be aware that all
these optional parameters should come
after the required parameters. In other
words. I cannot add another required parameter
here. Let's call that another.
I cannot add that here. If
I save the changes. you can see.
we get a red underline
here. So all the optional parameters should
come after the required parameters. Now
. obviously. in this case.
we don't need the second parameter. so let's