mhm. Yeah. there
are times that you may want to
create a function that takes a variable
number of arguments.
Here is an example. Let's define
this function. Multiply. It takes two parameters X
and Y and simply returns X times
y. Now we can
call this function like this
. So far. so good.
But what if you want to pass one
or two more arguments here.
That doesn't work because our
multiply function takes only two parameters. To
solve this problem. we need
to replace these two parameters with
a single parameter. We use
a plural name here to
indicate that this is
a collection of arguments and
then we prefix it with an asterisk.
This is the magical part
. Let me show you what happens
when you use an asterisk here. So
temporarily. let's do it this
line and simply print numbers
. Let's see what we get here.
So run the program. You
can see all our
arguments and they're packed in
parenthesis. What is this. Well. earlier
you learned about lists. I briefly mentioned that
you can use square brackets to
create a list of objects like
2 3 4 5. Now. later in the
course we have a comprehensive section
about lists. so don't worry
about the details of lists and
how they work. But what I want you to note here is
that the only difference between
this list and what we
have here is in the notation.
So we use
square brackets to create lists and parenthesis to
create topples. Some people call
it two poles or two poles
. So a topple is similar to
a list and that it's a collection of
objects. The difference is
that we cannot modify this
collection. We cannot add a
new object to this topple once
again. Later in the course.
we're going to have a comprehensive section about
list topples and other data structures. What
matters now is that
these topples just like lists
are iterable so we can
iterate over them. which means
we can use them in loops.
Let me show you. So that's
right for number in numbers. Colon
. let's just print one
number at a time. Actually
. we don't need this
line so delayed and run
the program. So we
iterate over this top hole
. and in each iteration we get
one number and printed on the terminal
. So now. with a simple change.
We can calculate the product of
all these numbers.
All we have to do is
to define a variable like total.
Initially. we set it
to one and then in each iteration we
get total and multiplied by the
current number. Or we
can rewrite this statement using
an augmented assignment operator. So total times
equal number. line five and
four are exactly identical. So I'm going to
use line five because it's
shorter and cleaner delayed and
finally we'll return the total. Now
. one of the issues I see often in beginners code is
that they don't use
this indentation properly. So they
put the return statement here
and then they wonder why their
function doesn't work properly.
If you put the return statement here
. it will be part of
the for loop. So it will
be executed in each
iteration in this case after
the first iteration.
Because of this return. statement will
return from this multiply function.
so the total will
not be calculated properly.
We need to put this at
the same level of invitation as other statements
and dysfunction. So here we
have our four statement. We
loop over all the numbers
we calculate the total and
then finally return it. So with
this implementation we can get
the result and printed on
the terminal. Let's run the program and you