mhm. Yeah. So
in the last lecture.
you learned the syntax to pass a
variable number of arguments
to a function. We have
a variation of this
syntax with double asterisk. and
that's what I'm going to show you
in this lecture. So for this demo
. let's rename this function
to save underlying user and
renamed the Argument to User. So let's imagine
we're going to use this function
to save information about a user
now and this function. Let's just print this
user argument. We're done with our function. Let's
call it Save underline User. Now. instead of
passing arbitrary arguments here. we can pass arbitrary
keyword arguments. Remember keyword arguments. So we
have a name equals value. So here
we can add multiple
keyword arguments like ID equals
one name equals John. Age
equals 22 so on.
So we are passing three keyword
arguments to this function.
Now let's run this program. This
is what we get. Look at the syntax.
We have these curly braces
and in between them we have multiple key
value pairs. So key, colon, value, comma. Here's
another key value pair.
And here is the last one.
This object you see here
is called a dictionary. It's another
complex type or a data
structure in Python. and I'm
going to talk about that in
detail later in the course. For now,
all I want you to take
away is that when we use double asterisk
here, we can pass
multiple key value pairs or
multiple keyword arguments to a function
and python will
automatically package them into a dictionary. So
this user object here is
a dictionary, now using the
bracket notation We can get
the value of various keys
in this dictionary.
So we can print user square
brackets. You pass a string
and this is the name of
our key. Like I d
Let's run the program. We
get one or we
can access the value of
name key. Run the program. So name is