mhm. Yeah. So
far you have learned how to use
some of the built in functions in
python. such as print round and
so on. In this section,
you're going to learn how to write your
own functions. Now you might ask
But why do we even need
to write our own functions?
Well, when you build a
real program that program
is going to consist hundreds
or thousands of lines of code.
You shouldn't write all that
code in one file like we have
done so far. You should break that
code into smaller, more maintainable and potentially
more reusable chunks.
We refer to these chunks as
functions. so let me show
you how to create your own
custom functions. We start with the def keyword,
which is short for define.
Next, We need to give our function a
name. So let's call this greet. all the
best practices you learn about
naming your variables also apply to
naming your functions. so make
sure your function names are meaningful
. Descriptive. Use lower case
letters to name your functions and
an under square to separate multiple words. Now
. after the name we need to add parenthesis.
you will see why shortly
and then we'll add a corner. Now what
is going to happen. You know it.
We're going to get indentation. which
means the following statements will
belong to this function. So
here I'm going to add two statements. Hi
there. And welcome aboard
. Both designs belong to
this function because they're indented. Now
we're done with this function.
We need to call it so we
remove the indentation and we add two line
breaks after this function.
This is what Pep8 recommends
to keep our code clean and maintainable.
Now. if you forget
to add to line breaks. don't worry.
As soon as you save the changes. Auto
Pep eight will automatically add
these line breaks for you. Let
me show you. So I'm going
to remove these line breaks and
call this function great with parenthesis. just like
how we call the built in functions.
Now. save the
changes. There you go. So we get to
line breaks after our function. Now let's run
this program. So we get these