Mhm. Yeah. all
right. Now let's take a look
at the shortcuts for Mac keyboard. So
here we are. online nine.
and my cursor is right at the
beginning of the line. If you want
to move the cursor to the end of
the line instead of using the
right arrow to go all the
way. simply hold down
the function key and press
right here it is.
Or you can press function
and left to jump to
the beginning of the light. Similarly
. you can press function
and up to go to the
top of the file
or function and down to
jump to the end of the file.
Pretty useful. Now
let's say you want to move
this line up instead of cutting it
from here and then copying it somewhere else.
You can simply move
it up by holding
down alt or option and
then pressing the up arrow are down very
easy. or we can select
these two lines. Hold down the
altar option key. move it up or doubt
. Here's another useful shortcut.
We can convert these two lines into
a comment by pressing command and slash. and
then we can remove the
comment using the same shortcut so
we can target it. And finally.
if you want to type the
name of a variable or
function like multiply. you don't
have to type all the
letters like multiply. That is
very slow. You can type
the first few letters like malt
. and here in the intelligence.
you can see it's selected. so press enter. or
you can pick any
characters in sequence and type
them like M. T.
Y. Here it is. Or you
can type M p y or M T
p so you can abbreviate
it anyway you want. I