One of the questions that often
comes in programming interviews is
the fizz buzz algorithm.
You might be surprised that
there are a lot of developers out
there with even the years of experience. but
they don't know how to
solve this simple programming problem. That's
why I decided to include this
in my course. So let's see how
this algorithm works. And then
you can spend 10 to 15
minutes on this exercise on your own.
So here we have a function face
buzz that takes an input.
And depending on the
input we give it,
it returns different results. Here
are the rules:
If the input that we give it is divisible by
three, it will return the string Fizz. Let
me show you. So we run this program.
We get Fizz. If
the input is divisible by five,
it will return Buzz.
Take a look.
Here's Buzz. Now the third rule,
if the input is
divisible by both three and five,
it will return FizzBuzz. So let's
pass 15 here. we'll get FizzBuzz.
For any other numbers
it will return the
same input. So if I pass seven, it's not
divisible by three or five,
it will return seven
itself. So spend 10 to 15 minutes on this exercise.
You will see my solution next.