All right. let's see how we can
solve this problem. So we get the
input and check to see
if input is divisible by three
. Then we can set
a variable like result to
fears. Now let me temporarily simplify these
rules because I want to show
you a really cool technique. So
let's imagine if the input
is divisible by three will
return phase. otherwise will return bus. So
Els Colon. we set the result to
buzz and finally will return this result variable
. This is one way to implement these rules.
But it's not the best way
. There is a better and cleaner way.
Let me show you. So instead
of defining this result variable and then returning
it. we can simply return this string here
and also here.
And then we can get rid
of land sticks.
So be removed. One unnecessary line
of code. This was one technique.
The other technique
I want to show you is
when you have an if statement and
in your if block your
returning a value you don't really
need an else clause, Because
if this condition is evaluated to false,
the control moves
to the else clause and
all we're doing here is returning
a different value. So this
is the only possible outcome
. So here we can
remove this else clause and simply
return bus. So with this technique. I
removed an unnecessary indentation as well.
I've made our
code more linear. Okay. Now let's go back
to our original algorithm.
So if the input is divisible by
three will return phase. Now we
check to see if the input
is divisible by five will return bus
. So here we don't really
need an l f. Because if
this condition is false. will get here anyway
. So we can check
if input is divisible by
five. We will return buzz once
again. If this condition is false.
the control moves here
. Now we check to see
if the input is divisible by
three. And it is also divisible
by five. Then we will return fares
bus. Now this expression is
a little bit long. I
would prefer to make it
more readable by putting parenthesis around
the 1st and 2nd parts like
this. That is cleaner. Now. if
this condition is also false.
the control moves here. That
means our number is not
divisible by three or five so
we should simply return the same
input once again. We don't need an
else or another if we simply return the
input. Now let's run this
program and see if it's
working properly or not.
So we call our function with
three and we get face beautiful. Let's
call it with five. We get Buzz Perfect
. What if we call it with 15.
We should get face boss
. However we get fears.
What is going on here. There
isn't. This happen was because
when we passed 15 here. Line
two is executed. Obviously. 15 is divisible by
three or so. That is
why we immediately return phase
. To solve this problem.
we need to move this condition. which
is more specific to the top.
So I've selected these
two lines using all out and up. I
move these lines up.
Beautiful. All right. now let's
run the program one more time.
So we get fish
balls. Once again.
let's test it with three. Now
we get fares less tested with five.
When writing functions. don't
assume that your function is working.
Make sure to test it with all
different kinds of values.
Let's test it with five. We
get buzz. Beautiful.
What if you pass seven. which
is not divisible by three or five.
We get seven. Beautiful
So what you see here
is the simplest and most elegant implementation
of the FizzBuzz algorithm.
And that brings us to the end of
this section. In the next lecture
we're going to explore data structures
in Python. You're gonna
learn about lists, topples, sets
and dictionaries. I hope you enjoyed this section
and thank you for watching.