Yeah. yeah. So this is
the simplified version of this
great function we created earlier. Now,
in programming. we have
two types of functions: functions
that perform a task and functions that
calculate and return a value. Here
are some examples. Both
the print and greet functions
are examples of type one. They performing a
task which is printing
something on the terminal. In
contrast, the round function is
an example of a function
that calculates and returns a
value. So the functions that
you create fall into these
two categories. Now. let me
show you how to rewrite this
great function. But in the second form.
So instead of printing
this string on the terminal. we simply return
it. Let me show you. So I'm
going to delay it. All this code define
a new function.
But could it get underlying greeting
. We had the name
parameter and simply return this
formatted string high name. That's
all we have to do. So we
use the return statement to return a
value from this function.
Now we can call this function. get
underlined greeting. pass a name like
Marsh. Because it returns a
value we can store that
value in a separate variable like message. Now
you might be curious which
form of these grating functions is
better? Well, with this first implementation we
are locked to printing something
in the terminal. In the
future if you want to write
that message in a file or send
it in an email
you have to create another function so
we cannot reuse this greet
function in other scenarios. In
contrast this second form is not tied
to printing something under terminal.
It simply returns a
value. Now we get this value
and we can do whatever we
want with it. We can
print it on the terminal. or
we can use the
built in open function to
write this message to a file
so we can create a fire like
content dot txt. Open it
for writing. This returns
a file object. and then
we can call file that right message. Now,
don't worry about these two lines.
Later in the course I'm going to talk
about working with files. But what I want you to take away here
is that we have this message variable
and we can do whatever we want with
it. We can print it on the
terminal, write it to a file, send
it in an email and so on.
And one more thing before we
finish this lecture. So here's
our great function. and as
you can see.
we're simply printing a string. Now
. if we call great.
give it a name. run
the program. We get this
message by March. But what
if we put this
inside of a call to
the print function.
Let's see what we get. We
get high marsh followed by None.
What is this? None
is the return value
of the greet function. So
in Python all functions by default return the
None value. None is
an object that represents the
absence of a value. Later in the course
you're going to learn more about
None. What matters now
is that all functions return
None by default unless you specifically return
a value. So here if we return some
string. none will no longer
be returned. I just want
to clarify something. Earlier I
told you that we have two
types of functions in programming: functions
that carry out a task
or functions that calculate and
return a value. So back
to the code we previously had.
So even though this
function returns None by default, it
is still classified as a
function that carries out a task