mhm. Yeah. let's
create another function we call an increment. We
want to use this function
to increment a number by
a given value. So here was simply return
number. Plus. by now
we can call this
function like this increment two
and one. This returns a
value so we can store it
in a variable like
result and then printed on
the terminal. Let's run the program.
We get three
Beautiful. Now we can simplify this code. We
have used this result variable
only in a single place that
is line six. So we
don't really need it. So
online. Six we can replace result with
a call to increment function like this
. So when Python
interpreter execute this code first
it will call the increment function.
It will get the
result and temporary stored in
a variable for us. We
don't see that variable and then
it will pass that variable as
an argument to the print function. Now. if
we're on this program. we get
the exact same result. Beautiful. Now
we can make this code more readable.
If someone else looks at
line five they may
not know exactly what these
arguments are for. We can
use a keyword argument to
make this code more readable.
So this one here
is the value of this. By parameter. we
can prefix it with the
name of the parameter like
this. Now we can
read this code almost like
playing English increment to buy one. So
if you're calling a function
with multiple arguments and it's
not quite clear what the
arguments are for. you can make
your code more readable
by using keyword arguments.
So here by=1 is a keyword argument.