In programming We have a very
important concept called scope which
refers to the region of
the code where a variable is
defined. So in this example
we have this message variable. The
scope of this variable
is the greet function. It
only exists inside of dysfunction. So if
we go outside of this
function and try to print message
. see what happens as soon as I save the change as we get this
red underline undefined variable message and
if we run our program.
we get this name error. Name
message is not defined. The same rule applies
to the parameters of our functions.
So if you add a name parameter
here and then try
to print it outside of
the great function. we get
the same error. So the
scope of the name and message
variables are the greet function and
we refer to these
variables as local variables in
this function. Their local in this function
which means they don't
exist anywhere else. And that means
we can have another function.
Let's say. send email
with a parameter with the same name.
Here we can have a
message variable. But this
message variable is completely different
from the message variable we have
in the greet function. And of
course the same rule applies
to the name parameters in
these functions. they are completely separate. These local
variables have a short lifetime. So when we
call let's say the greet function and
pass the name.
Python interpreter will allocate some
memory and have the
name and message variables reference
those memory locations.
when we finish executing the
greet function because these
variables are not referenced or
used anywhere else
eventually they get garbage collected, which
means Python Interpreter will release the memory that
allocated for these variables.
So these are the local variables.
In contrast to local variables,
we have global variables. So
if we move this message variable outside of
the greet function, now
it's a global variable. which means it's
accessible anywhere in this file,
So the scope of
this variable is this file.
We can use it anywhere in this file
in any functions or outside
of a function. Now for
this reason, global variables
stay in memory for a
longer period of time until
they are garbage collected. And
you should not use them that often.
In fact global variables are
really evil.
so as a best practice create functions
with parameters and local variables. Now what
if here in the
greet function we set message
to; Let's say b.
Now let's delete this second function
we don't really need it for now.
so we call the greet function. In
this function we assign a new
value to the message Variable. Now
let's print this message and see what
we get. What do you think
we're going to get? Well, let's
take a look. We get a. But didn't
we change the value
of message variable to b? not
really, because by default Python interpreter treats
this message variable as a local
variable at the greet function, even
though it has the same
name as the global variable that
we have on line one.
So these two variables are separate. I
have seen some tutorials or
even books teaching you bad practices.
For example they show you
how to modify the value of
this global message variable inside of a function.
Let me show you how to do that.
But remember this is a bad practice
and you should avoid it at all times.
I will explain the reason
in a second.
so these tutorials or books teach
you to use the global keyword here and
reference the message variable. When Python interpreter sees
this line it will realize that
in this function we want to use
the global message variable so
it will not define a
local variable in this function. Now with this change
if we run our program
you can see we get
b on the terminal
because in this function we are modifying the
value of the global message variable. Why is
this bad? Because it is
possible that you might have multiple
functions that rely on the
value of this global variable.
If you accidentally or deliberately change the
value of this global variable
in one function this might
have a side effect in other functions. Those
functions may not behave properly.
and this way we can
create a bug in our program.
So global
variables have always been bad.
This is not a python thing. This
is a discussion that's been
going on for decades. Avoid them
as much as you can. or if
there are situations that you really need
to define a variable globally
in a file that's okay. but
do not modify it in a function
as you see here, this is a really bad
practice.
so that's all about local and global variables