In this lecture I'm going to show
you how to find and fix bugs in
your programs. So here's the
multiply function we wrote earlier
. Let's add a couple
of statements after this function
. So print start. and
then we'll call the multiply function. Give
it three arguments 12 and three. So the
result should be six.
And here we print the
result on the terminal. Now. to create a
bug in this program.
I'm going to deliberately. intended
this return statement.
So now when we run this
program instead of six, we get one. So
we're going to use a
technique called debugging to find and
fix this bug. All right.
First. we need to open the
debugging panel. The first time
you want to use debugging in
the Python project you need to
click this icon. This will generate a new
file called launch.json. In this file
we have a bunch of debugging configuration.
you never have to touch any
of this. so don't worry about it.
Close it. You
can see this file is
placed inside of this VSCode
folder. It's right here. launch.json. Now
when we have this file
we can go to the debugging panel and
from this list
we can select a debugging configuration.
Some of these configurations
are useful for more complex applications.
For example we use
Python: Django to debug a
Web application built with python. For this course
we're going to use
Python: current file with Integrated
Terminal. So select this. Now
to start debugging first we need
to add a break point on
one of these statements. So I'm
gonna put the cursor on line 8
and insert a breakpoint by pressing F9.
So this is a break point.
We can press f9 one more
time to remove it. If you're
on a Mac keyboard you should press
the function key which is on the
bottom left corner of your keyboard and
then press F9.
So here we have a break point.
Now we can press F5 to run the application
up to this point. so f5. so
this automatically opens the integrated terminal here. Don't
worry about this. I'm going
to close it. so you
can see our program is running
up to this point. This line is
highlighted. Now we can execute this program line
by line and see exactly
what happens at granting. So
to execute one statement at
the time Press F10
Okay. we're done.
Now we're on line 9. However on line
9 we're calling the multiply Function if
you press F10 again
the execution stops so
we couldn't figure out why we
got one as a result of
multiplying these numbers. So let's start debugging
one more time. We press F5 so
once again we are on line 8.
Let's step over this line
with F10.
At this time we want to
step into this multiply function
so we see exactly what
is going on here.
So instead of F10 press F
11 now we are on line 2.
So if you're calling a function
that you have defind you can
step into that function using F11. Now
here we are in the
multiply function. On the left side, inside
the variables panel, you can see
all the variables that are meaningful in
this function. So under locals.
we have numbers. So
this is our numbers argument.
You can see this is set to
topple with three numbers 1 2 3. Right now
our total variable is not in
this list because it's not defined yet.
The moment we step over
this line with F10 total
comes to existence and you can
see initially is set to one. Now
we are at the beginning of
our for loop. Let's press F
10 one more time. Here we are.
We're going to multiply
total by number. So let's step
over this line as well.
Now at this point we
have a new variable called number that
is our loop variable initially
is set to one. Now
here we are on line 5.
If you press F10 we
can see we jump out of this function.
So our loop did
not execute to completion.
And that is the reason
our program has a bug.
So to fix this I'm
going to stop the debgger
with shift and F5 now
back here. Let's remove the indentation. save
the changes. run the program
in debug mode one more time
. So we press F five. Here
we are. Let's step over
this with F 10 now. Step
into this with F11 and step over these
lines with F10 a
few more times. So
F10 one more time. Totally set.
Now we are in the second iteration.
Let's press F 10
1 more time. In this situation.
you can see number is
set to to our total
is still one. So let's
step over this line as well.
Now Total is
updated to two. Here we
are at the beginning of
the third iteration.
Let's step over this line in
this situation number is three. So after
we execute this line
because $12 currently to when
we multiplied by three
will get six So f
10 1 more time.
Now. we only have three
iterations in this loop. So if you
press f 10 1 more time. our
loop complete. Now we are
ready to return Total. which is
currently six. So f 10 were
online nine and we're done now
. One more tip in this demo.
I put the break point on
the first line of the program.
You don't always have to do this. For
example here we know that our
multiply function has a bug so
instead of putting the
breakpoint on line 8 so we
could put it on line 2. So when
we start the program in
debug mode with F5 We
immediately start in the multiply function. And
one more tip before we finish this lecture,
If you step into
a function and you know
that that function works properly you
can immediately step out of
that function with Shift and
F11. so you
don't have to execute the
entire function line by line.
You can press shift and F11 to step out of the function