In programming we have a common data structure called Stack
which resembles a
stack of items in the real world.
Imagine you have a stack
of books. The last book
that you put on top of
this tag is the first book
that you can remove. You refer
to this behavior as life Oh.
which is short for last in
first out. So this
is a stack data structure
. and it's very common
in real world applications. A good
example of that is your browser.
Whenever you navigate to a
new website. your browser keeps
your browsing session in a stack
. So when you click the back button.
it takes you to the previous website
. Let me show you how it works.
so we start with an empty stack. Now
let's say we navigate the website
number one now here for simplicity. I'm
using a number. If you're
building a browser instead of
a number. will use a string.
which is the address of the
current website. Now let's say we navigate to
a couple more websites and
then click the back button. At
this point. the browser removes
the item on top of
the stack. and then
it will redirect us to
the previous website. Now let's
say we press the back
button a couple more times.
so we'll end up with an
empty stack. At this point.
the browser will disable the
back button. This is how
a stack works, Last In
First Out.
Now let me show you how to use a
stack in python.
Basically we can use a list object as
a stack. So here I'm going
to define a variable like browsing
session and set it
to an empty list. Now
let's say the user navigates
the website number one. so we
call browsing session that a panned method and
add the address of the current website. Now
let's say the user navigates
to website number two and
then three. Let's have a look at what
we have in our stack.
So we printed. And
as you see. we have a
list of three items. Now when
the user presses the back button.
we should remove the last item
in this list. right.
How do we do it. We use
the pop method. so we call browsing session
dot pop. This will remove
the last item from the
stack and return it so
we can get it here. But
in this case. we're not going to
use this value. Let me just printed on
the terminal so you can see
that so three is removed from the stack.
Now. if we print our
stack one more time Prince browsing session. you
can see three is removed and
we have only two items in
our stack. So we need to take
the user to the previous website which
is the item on top of the stack.
And we can get that using
a negative one index. Very easy. So back
here. browsing session of negative one
. This returns the last item.
So we printed
. And I would like to
add just a label for clarity. Redirect
. Let's look at the result.
So when the user presses
the back button. we redirect
them to the previous website which
is website number two.
Now here. we need to check if
the stack is empty or not.
If it becomes empty. we
need to disable the back button.
So that is
very easy. Earlier in the course.
I told you about the false values
. So number zero and
empty string an empty list
. These are all false e values.
So if you apply. the
not operator to an
empty list will get the
bully and true. So to
see if our stack is
empty. we can simply
read code like this. if
not browsing session. then at this point
we will disable the back button. So
let me recap. We use the
append method to add an item on
top of the stack. We use Pop to
remove the item on top of the stack.
We use index negative
one to get the item on
top of the stack. And of
course. before doing that. we need to check
to see if our stack is empty or
not. Because if it's empty
when we run. this code
will get an error. So if not browsing
session. then we'll get the item on top