Throughout the course
I've mentioned tuples a few times.
In this lecture We're
going to take a closer look at them.
A topple is basically a
read only list.
We can use it to contain a sequence of
objects. but we cannot modify this sequence.
We cannot add
a new object to it.
We cannot remove an existing object and we
cannot modify an existing object.
So let's start by
defining a topple called point instead
of square brackets. We use
parenthesis to define a topple
. So here we add
a couple of numbers here. a
point with X and Y values. We can
also exclude parenthesis and python will
see this as a topple.
Let me show you. So let's print type
of point and run
this program so you can
see it's a class of topple.
Now, if
you have one item,
you should add a trailing comma, oherwise
python thinks you're defining an integer.
so if you
run this code. you can
see Point is an integer. But
if we add a training comma here. python
treats this as a top on.
Also. if you want to
define an empty topple. you should use empty
parenthesis. So let's find this one more time.
You can see Point
is still a topple
now similar to lists we
can concatenate two topples. So here
we have one topple.
We can concatenate it with another topple
. Let's print the result. So
now we have this topple
with numbers 1 to 4. We
can also use the multiplication operator to repeat
a tuple.
So now when we run this code, we have a
tuple with 1 2 1 2 and 1 2.
These
are different ways to create a tuple.
We can
also convert a list to tuple.
So let's say we have a
list of two numbers to
convert this list to topple. Recall
the Topple function.
As you can see, this function
takes an iterable so we can pass
any iterables
here and this function will
return a tuple. So here's
one example. let's print point. Now we have
a tuple of two numbers.
Or we can pass a string
like Hello World and
because strings are iterable now
we get tuple of 11 strings. Now
let me revert this back
to a simple topple similar
to lists. We can access
individual items using an index so
we can get the first item.
which is one. Or we
can get a range of items
like items from index zero to
index to. This returns another topple with
only those objects. We can also unpack
these tuples so we can
define three variables like x, y
and z and set
it to point.
Similar to
lists, We can use the in
operator to check for the existence of
an item. So if 10 is
in point. then we print exists. But
as I told you.
these topples are immutable. We
cannot mutate them. We cannot change them.
So if I try to
modify point of zero and
set it to a new
number look. we immediately get this
red underline and if we
run the code. we get
this type error topple
object does not support item
assignment for this very
reason on like lists. we
don't have methods to add
a new object or remove an
existing object. So you might
ask where in the real
world we use topples.
Here's a basic rule of thumb. Let's
say you're dealing with a sequence of
object and you want to make sure
that you don't accidentally modify this sequence. You
don't accidentally add a new object
to it or remove an existing object
so instead of a list you
can use a topple to prevent these accidental errors.