In Pytho we have a very
powerful data structure called Dictionary
that is basically a collection
of key value pairs. We
use it to map a key to a value.
A real world example
of this is a phone book.
In the phone book. we map a
person's name to their contact details. so we
use a person's name as the
key and their contact information as
the value. So a phone
book is a dictionary. It's a
collection of key value pairs.
Now let me show you
how to work with dictionaries in Pisa.
so I'm going to
define a variable point. We can
set it to an empty dictionary.
or we can add one or
more key value pairs Here.
Here is an example we said x
21 and why to
to So in this example.
I'm using a string for the key and
and in order for the value.
In python we can only
use immutable types for the keys.
So quite often we
use strings and numbers.
But the value can be
of any type. There are no limitations.
so here's one
way to define a dictionary.
We can also use the
Dict function just like
we have the list topple
and set functions. We also
have the dict functions that
we can use to
create a dictionary. So let
me redefine point by calling the
dicks function. So when
we call this function. we
pass one or more keyword arguments. Remember
keyword arguments. So X equals one
. This is a keyword argument.
We can also set why
to to now I personally prefer the second approach
because we don't have to deal with this quote.
I find this syntax a
little bit cleaner and shorter.
So now we have a
dictionary. We can get the
value associated with the key using
an index. So point of X
note that our index is
the name of a key. So
because dictionaries are collections of
key value pairs. we cannot
access an item using a
numeric index as we do
with lists. So here we
are getting the value associated
with the key eggs.
Let's print it on the terminal. so
we get one.
Similarly. we can change the value
of X to a new value. Now
let's print our dictionary. So X is
10. Why is too beautiful.
We can add a
new key. So let's
set Z to 20 and
then print the point.
So now we have three key
value pairs. Now. when reading a value. if
you use an invalid key
will get an error. So let's
look up the value of the
item with the key A and then
print this. Run the program. We
get this error. Kierra.
There are two workarounds here. One
solution is to check for
the existence of a key. So
if a in point. then we'll
get the value of the
item with Kia and printed. Now
we don't get the error anymore.
The other solution is to
use the get method.
So instead of using brackets and
the name of the key.
we call the get method. Here
we pass the name of the key.
Let's print it
So if the key
doesn't exist by default. it
returns None.
Or we can pass a default value
as the second argument.
So we say. Hey. if
you don't have an item with the key
a return zero by
default. let's take a look.
Now we get zero Beautiful
. To delete an item.
we use the del or delete statement. So
delayed point of X. Now
let's print point and look
at the results. So X is gone.
We only have Y and
Z. so these are
the basic operations around dictionaries
. We can easily add new items.
remove existing ones and look
up items by their key.
Finally. let me show you how
to loop over dictionaries.
So if we write a
simple for statement for X in
point. let's see what we get. We
get y and Z,
So in each iteration our
loop variable will hold the
key of an item. So
it's better to rename
this to key. Now we
can print the key as
well as the value associated with
the key. So we write point of key
. As you can see why
is to NZ is 20. There
is another way to
iterate over a dictionary. So
here we can call point that items. Now
let me rename key to
eggs and just print X
. Let's see what we get.
So in each
iteration we get a tuple.
In this tuple We
have the key and the
value so we can unpack it
right here We can extract key and
value and simply print them here like
this.
When we run the program,
we'll get the same result