So here we have a list of four items.
We can use square brackets
to access individual items
in this list. So let's
print letters of zero. This will return
the first item in this list.
So when we
run. this program will
get a. Now similar to
strings. If you pass
a negative index here like
negative one. this will return the first item
from the end of the list.
So when you run this
we'll get d using square brackets. We
can also modify items
in the list. So let's
change the first item to a capital A
and then print the entire list. There
you go. So this is
the basic of accessing individual
elements in the list. The earlier
in the course you learn that
we can use to indexes
to slice a string. We
have the exact same concept here.
so we add square
brackets. First index. colon second
index. and this will return a new list
with the first three items
in our original list. So
if we print our original list. you
can see that it's not changed now.
just like strength
. If you don't specify
the first argument. zero will
be assumed by default. So as
you can see. these two expressions
produce the exact same result. Similarly. if
you don't include the end index by
default. the length of the
list will be used here. So
this expression will return a
new list with all the items
in the original list. And similarly. we can
also exclude the START index here. And
with this syntax. we can get
a copy of our original list. There
you go. Now. when slicing a string.
we can also pass
a step. And this
is useful in situations where
you want to return every
second or every third element in
the original list. So now
when we run this code. we'll
get A and C So
be will be a skip. Let
me show you using
a better example. So I'm
going to delete everything here.
create a new list called
numbers. Here. We're going to
use the list function and
pass a range of 20. Let's
print our last. so we get numbers
0 to 19. Okay. Now. let's
see what happens when we
add square brackets here. We
to Collins and to this
will return every other element
in the original list. Take
a look. So we get
all the even numbers. 0
to 4 and so on.
It's pretty cool. isn't it. Here's
another cool thing you can do here.
Let's change the
step to negative one. As
you can see. this will return
all the items in the original list
but in reverse order.
So these are some useful
things you can do with lists.
Next we'll look at unpacking lists.