All right. Look at this piece of
code here on October. defining an
empty list. Then we're iterating over this
range object. In each iteration.
we get eggs multiplied
by two and added to our list.
As I told you
before, whenever you have this
pattern in your code you can
either use the map
function or preferably a list
comprehension. So let's review the syntax for
a list comprehension. We have
square brackets to define a
list. And here's our comprehension expression. We
have expression for item in items
. so we iterate over an iterable. In
each iteration. we get
this item and then do
something with it. So what
is our iterable in this
example is this range
object that is returned from
the range function So range of five here
. What is our loop.
Variable. That is X and
what is our expression.
They're multiplying eggs by two
so we can start
a result in values. This
line of code is
exactly identical to these three
lines. So let's still at this now. These
comprehension are not limited to list.
We can also use
them with sets and dictionaries. So now if
we replace these square
brackets with curly braces. We
get a set. let's print values. So
we get a set of even numbers. right?
Now
What is the syntactical difference between a set and a
dictionary?
Well, for both these data structures
we use curly braces.
In sets We just have values;
but in dictionaries we
have key value pairs that are
separated using a colon.
So here we can map one
to a character to another
character and so on. So
we can easily use
comprehension expressions to create dictionary
objects. So here. in this expression. all
we need to do is to
change this expression such that we have
a key value. Parents. So here we
can use X as the key and
X Times two as the value.
Now let's dilate these two
alliance. save the changes
and run the code. We
have this dictionary with these key value pairs
. Okay. So instead of defining an
empty dictionary. then looping over an
iterable and then in each iteration adding
something to this dictionary like
values of X equals X
times two. Whenever you have this pattern in
your code. you can
use a dictionary comprehension. So
to recap. we can
use comprehension with lists, sets
and dictionaries. But what about tuples?
Let's take a
look. So let's remove this key value pair
and only use X Times two and
also change the curly braces to parenthesis. Let's
also delay these few lines. Run the
program.
We don't get a tuple; What's going
on here? We get
a generator object. and that's