So in this section you have learned a
lot about data structures in Python. One
operator that comes handy when
working with these data structures is
the unpacking operator. Let me
show you how that works. So
let's say we have a
list of numbers. 123 If
it print this list. we'll
get a list on the terminal. But
what if you want to
print the individual numbers. In
other words. what if we
want to get an outward like
this. Let's run this program. So here
we don't have square brackets and
we don't have comma. We're printing out
individual numbers. individual items in our list. To
achieve this. we can use
the unpacking operator. So all we
have to do is
prefix this variable with the
unpacking operator. In JavaScript. we have an
operator called Spread Operator. which is three
dots. This is exactly the same.
So here we unpack a
container. take out its individual elements and pass
them as arbitrary arguments
to the print function. Now
. if we run this program.
we get the exact same outfit. Another
useful application of this
is when creating lists. So
let's say we want to have
the list of numbers from 0 to
5. You know that
this range function returns a
range object. so we need
to convert it to a
list and then stored a result in It's
variable. Now let's print this. We
get 0 to 4 beautiful.
In this case instead of calling
the list function, we can
use the unpacking operator. So
we call range of five. This returns an iterable.
right?
The good thing about this unpacking operator is
that we can unpack any iterable.
It doesn't have to be a
list. So we unpack this iterable.
which basically means
we take individual values.
Then we put them in
a list and finally
start a result here. By
the same token. we can
unpack a string. so unpack
a string like Hello. Now let's take
a look at the result.
So we have the numbers 0
to 4 now because
we're unpacking this Hello string.
We're getting individual characters
and put them in our list
So these are some cool tricks that
we can do in Python that as far
as I know,
we don't have in other popular languages.
let's look at another example.
Using this operator, we
can combine multiple lists.
So here we can have my
list and another list.
Now,
to combine these lists,
we can unpack the
first one and then the
second one.
We can
also put something in the middle or unpack
a string at the end. Hello.
So it's very powerful.
Now,
we can also unpack dictionaries,
but we need to use two
asterics.
Let me show you.
So I'm going to define one
dictionary. Let's add a
key value pair here. so
X. Now let's define the second dictionary. I'm
going to repeat X here.
but with a different value. and also
add why. Now. To
combine these dictionaries. we can use the
unpacking operator so we
create an empty dictionary. We
unpacked the first dictionary. This will take out
all the key value pairs in our first dictionary.
And
then we'll unpack the second dictionary.
We
can additionally add another key value pair.
Now
let's print the result.
Note
that the value of X is 10.
So if you have multiple items with
the same key, the last
value will be used.
So
to recap:
we can use the unpacking operator to
take out individual values in
any iterable.