All right.
Time for an exercise.
This exercise I'm going to give you
is one of my favorite, because
it's a common interview question
that big companies like Microsoft, Amazon and Google
used a lot.
So let's say we have some text.
I
want you to write a program
to find the most repeated character in
this text.
So pause the video,
work on this exercise for
5 to 10 minutes,
when you're done,
come back continue watching.
All
right.
How do we solve this problem?
Well, first we need to know how
many times each character is repeated?
Once we have that information
then we can find the most repeated character.
What kind
of data structure is useful for storing this information?
A
dictionary;
because a dictionary is a collection of key
value pairs, so here we
can use the characters as
the keys and the repetition as the value.
So I'm going to start by defining an empty dictionary.
Let's
call it char or character frequency.
We
set it to an empty dictionary.
Now we need to iterate over
this string,
get each character and
update its frequency in
this dictionary,
so we need a for loop for char
in sentence.
Now, first we need to
see if you have this character in our dictionary?
If we don't
have it we need to set its frequency to one,
otherwise we
need to increment the frequency.
So if
char in char_frequency.
If
we do have it then we simply get
the value and increment it by
one.
otherwise, we need to add it
to our dictionary.
So char_frequency of
char set it to one.
So let's print this
dictionary and see what we get?
char_frequency.
There
you go.
run the program.
So capital T
is repeated once,
h is repeated Once,
i is
repeated five times and so on.
Now this output is
a little bit unreadable,
so I'm going to show you a trick to make
it more readable.
We have a module called Pretty
Printing.
So on the top from
pprint module,
we need to import
pprint function.
With this function, we have more control
over printing stuff on the terminal.
So here instead
of the regular print function,
we use pprint,
And
as the second argument
we pass a keyword argument
called width,
that determines the number of characters on
each line.
If this output doesn't fit,
this function will
add a line break.
Let's set this to 1 and see what happens.
We
run the program.
So this is a better way of
printing a dictionary.
So now we have all the information to
solve this problem.
The next step is to sort this dictionary by
the frequency of characters.
However, as
I told you before,
dictionaries like sets are
unordered collections, We cannot sort them.
We can only sort
lists.
So we need to pull out the items in this dictionary and
put them in a list for sorting.
So basically we need to take
out each key value pair,
convert it to a tuple and
then put it in a list.
we'll  end up with a list of tuples that
we can easily sort.
So how do we do this?
Pay
close attention to what I'm going to do.
I'm going to call the
sorted function.
Earlier You learn that this function takes
an iterable and sorts it.
As the iterable, I'm going
to pass char_frequency dot
items.
Earlier you learn
that this method returns all
the key value pairs as tuples.
So at
this point if we print this result, let's
see what we get?
We get a list of tuples,
in each tuple we have two items:
the first is the character and the
second is the repetition or frequency.
But as you
can see, this list is not sorted because
by default this
sorted function doesn't know how to sort these tuples.
So
earlier I told you that we
can pass a second argument here
key,
we set this to a lambda, which
is an anonymous function,
this function takes the key value
pair and
returns the value, so that
is key value of one, that is the frequency of
each character.
We're going to use that for sorting.
So
let's run the program one more time.
Now,
as you can see, this list is sorted.
So T is
the least repeated character and space and
i are the most repeated characters.
Now
we need to reverse the sorting, so back
to our sorted function,
as the third argument We're
going to pass the keyword argument: reverse equals
True.
Save the changes Run the program one
more time.
Now, all these items are sorted in
descending order. Beautiful.
So instead
of printing the result, let's store it in
a list like char_frequency underlie sorted.
Finally
the first item in this list, is the solution to our problem.
So
we simply print char_frequency_sorted
of zero.
Save the changes.
Run
the program one more time.
So i is the most repeated character
with five repetitions.
Now, one final improvement.
You can see the code on line 12,
it's kind of outside the screen,
partly this is because
I've zoomed in so you can see properly.
But
pepe8 recommends a
maximum of 80 characters on
one line,
so if you have a line that is too long,
it's better to
break it down into multiple lines,
this makes your code more readable.
So here I'm going to list each
argument on a new line. Like this.
That
is better.
And that brings us
to the end of this section.
In
the next section, you're going to
learn about errors and exceptions.
I hope
you enjoyed the section and
thank you for watching.