mhm. Yeah. There
are times that you may want to
get individual items in a list and
assign them to different variables.
Here is an example. We
can define a variable like
first and set it to numbers
of zero. Similarly. we can define second. set
it to numbers of one and
third set it to numbers of
two. Perhaps you're going
to use these variables in
a few complex expressions
in your code. Now there
is a cleaner and more
elegant way to achieve the
same result. And that is
what we call list unpacking
so we can unpack
this list into multiple variables
. Let me show you how that works.
So we define our variables
like 1st. 2nd and 3rd and then
set them to our list.
What we have on
line two is exactly identical to what
we have on lines 4 to 6.
This is what we call lest
unpacking. Now. What is important here is
that the number of variables that we
have on the left side of the
assignment operator should be equal
to the number of items we
have in the list.
So if we exclude third
year and run this program. we will get
an error value error. Too many values to
unpack. So there are too
many items in this list and
we cannot unpack it into enough variables
. Now what if in this list
we have so many items. but we
only care about the first two.
We don't want to define so
many variables on the left
side of the assignment operator. Well
. we can get the 1st
and 2nd and then pack the
rest inside of a separate list called Other
. With This syntax will
get the 1st and 2nd
items and everything else will
be stored in a separate list
called other Let me show You.
So let's print first and
let's also print other. No. we
don't need these few lines here.
Let's run this code. So
first is one and other is a
list of all the items after the second
item. That is the
list I'm talking about. So
in this example
we have both unpacking and packing.
First we try to
unpack this numbers list into
the variables on the left
side of the assignment operator. and
then because we have used
an asterisk air. we're basically packing
all the other items into a separate list
now to refresh your memory.
Earlier. we used this same tax
when defining a function with
a variable number of arguments. Remember
. we had a
function like this multiply with
a parameter called asterisk numbers. and
then we could call this multiply with
arbitrary number of arguments.
So when we prefix a
parameter with an asterisk, Python would get all
these arbitrary argument and
packed them into a list.
This is exactly what
is happening on line two. Now
let me delay it this other stuff. Now
let's change this example a little bit.
What if we care only about
the first and the last item? Well. we
can put other in between.
so we get the
first other and then the last item
. So let's change the
last item to nine and
then print first. last and
other. This is what we get.
So first there's one. Last
is nine and the rest is here.
So this is all about list unpacking.