mhm in
this lecture. I'm going to show you
how to loop over lists. So here
we have a list of three
items we can use our for loops
to loops over this list.
So for letter
in letters colon and then we print each
letter.
save the changes
and run the code.
We
get a b c.
Now what if you want to get the index
of each item as well?
Well we have a built in function
called enumerate. We call
it here. and this will
return an enumerate object which
is iterable. In each iteration this enumerate
object will give us a topple.
Let me show you. So
now when we run this code.
Look.
In each
iteration we're getting a topple.
So to topple. As
I told you before,
it's like a list but
it's read only.
we
cannot add new items to it.
So in each iteration
we're getting a topple of two items.
The first item
in this topple is the index and
the second item
is the item at that index.
So now. to get the index
we can use square brackets
to access the first item in
this topple. So if it print letter of
zero. We will get the indexes and
right next to that we
can add letter of one. So
we will see the item
at a given index. But
this syntax is a little bit ugly.
In the last lecture you've
learned about list unpacking.
So if we
have a list with two items zero
and a we can unpack it into
two variables like this: index comma letter
equals items. So here we are unpacking the
items list.
Now what if we change square brackets
to parenthesis?
Now we have a topple and we
can still unpack this topple. So you
saw that this enumerate function returns an enumerate
object which is iterable. In each iteration this
enumerate object will return a topple that
looks like this.
So we can unpack it right here
. So we add another variable index. Now
. with this. we no longer
have to use square brackets and
we can simply print index and letter. Let's
run this code.
There you go. So now we
don't need this anymore. So
to recap. you can use
four loops to iterate over
lists. If you also need the index.
you should call the
enumerate function this will return and enumerate object
which is iterable in each iteration.
It will return to
topple and you can unpack that topple right