In this lecture. I'm going to show you how
to add new items to a list or
remove existing items. So for adding items. you
have two options depending on
where you want to add this
new item. If you want to add
an item at the end of the list,
you should use
the append method. so earlier
You learn that everything in
python is an object. so you
can use the dot notation
to access individual functions or
more accurately
methods in that object. So when
a function is part of an object
we refer to that function as a
method. So here are
all the methods available on
list objects. We use the
append method to add something
at the end of this list.
Let's print our
letters and we will
get a B C D.
Beautiful. Now, if you want
to add an item at a
specific position, you should
use the insert method. So
letters dot insert we can add something at
the beginning of the list.
So Index zero. Let's
add hyphen and then print the
results. So this is what we get. Now,
for removing objects again.
You have a few different options. If
you want to remove item at the
end of the list, you should use
the pop method.
So here we call letters dot
pop. This will remove the
letter d at the end
of our list. So now let's print our
letters. As you can see d is gone.
You can also pass an index
here to remove the item at the
given index. So if you pass zero, instead
of d, this hyphen will be removed.
Let's take a look. We
run this so the hyphen
is gone and we get a
VCD. Beautiful. Now there are
times that you want to remove
an object but you don't
know it's index. If that's the
case you can use the remove method.
so letters that
remove here we can remove B. and
this will remove the first
occurrence of the letter b.
So if you have multiple bs
only the first one will be removed. If
you want to remove all bs in this list
you will have to loop over this
list and remove each b individually. Now let's
run this code one more time so
you can see b is gone. We
have another way to remove an
item from a list and that
is using the del or delete statement.
So here we
can delete an item by its index. We
can also delete a range of items.
So this is
the difference between the delete statement and the
pop method. The pop method
will remove only one item by
index. whereas with the delete
statement we can remove a
range of items.
And finally,
if you want to remove all
the objects in the list,
you should use the clear method.
Next we look at finding objects in the list.