Here we have this list with a bunch
of numbers that are not in any particular
order to sort this list.
We call numbers that
sort. Now let's print it and
you can see our numbers
are sorted in ascending order. What
if you want to sort these
items in descending order. Well. this
sort method takes two parameters:
key, which will look at
later
and reverse which we can use to change the sort order.
So here we can use a
keyword argument to set a value for
the reverse parameter.
We said this to true. and
with this you can see our
numbers are sorted in descending order. So
this is the basic
of sorting lists. However. in
addition to the sort method.
we have a built in function called
Sorted. As you can see.
this function takes an
iterable so we can pass
any iterables here and it
will sort it for
us. So we can pass
our numbers list. And this will return a
new list that is sorted.
So unlike the sort method,
this will not modify
the original list, it will
return a new sorted list.
So let me comment on this line
and print the result
of calling this function. Now
let's run this program. You can
see here is our new list
that is sorted. and below
that we have our original list
that is not sorted.
Also similar to the sort method
. If you want to change
the sort order. you can simply set
the reverse argument to true. Let's
run it one more time.
And here's the result. Beautiful. so
sorting numbers and strings is pretty easy.
But what if
you're dealing with a list
of complex objects?
For example:
what if we have a list of topples?
Let me show you. So
I'm going to deal with everything here.
Let's imagine we're building an application for
processing orders and we have
this list of order items
. Every item in this list
is a topple with two items. the
product name followed by the
price. So here's the first item. Now let's
add another item with
a different price. And finally
. the third item.
What happens if we try to
sort this list. Let's take a
look so items not sword and
then we print the items So
nothing is changed here
because Python doesn't know how
to sort this list. In
situations like this we need
to define a function that
Python will use for sorting lists.
Let me show you. So here
I'm going to define a function. Let's
call it sort underline item. This function should
take an item like this topple. There
you go. And it should
return a value that will be
used for sorting. In this example Let's imagine
we want to sort these
items based on their price. So
if each item is a topple.
we can get the price using
square brackets of one. So we'll return Item
of one. So all this function does
is that it takes an item and
it returns its price.
Now, Python is dealing with
a list of numbers and it
can easily sort that list. Now,
finally we need to
pass this function when sorting
our list of items. So once again,
look at the sort method, The
first parameter is key
and this is where we
need to pass our sorting function. So we
pass sort underlying item, but note
that I'm not calling this function,
I'm simply passing a
reference to this function.
When Python attempts to
sort this list, the list of items.
it gets each item
and it will pass each
item to our sort function. Okay.
so let's run this
program and see what happens. We
get a TypeError
sort takes no positional arguments
which basically means here
we can only use keyword arguments.
So we need to specify our argument.
That is key. We
set it to sort_item.
Now, let's
run this program one more time.
Okay. Look. Our
list of items is sorted by
the price of each item. However
the way we have implemented this sort function is a little bit ugly.
There is a better way and let's gonna show you next.