So here we have this course
variable set to "Python programming".
As I told you before, whenever you
work with texts you should surround
your text with quotes.
You can either use double quotes or
single quotes. That's more of
a personal preference,
but quite often we use double quotes.
We also have triple quotes and
we use them to format a long string.
For example if you have, let's say a
variable message. That is the message we want
to include in the body of an email.
You can use triple quotes to
format it like this.
Hi John,
This is Mosh from codewithmosh.com
Blah blah blah
So that's when we use triple quotes. Now we
don't need this in this lecture
So delete. Let
me show you a few useful
things you can do with strings. First
of all we have this
built in function in python for getting
the length of strings.
What is the function? A
function is basically a
reusable piece of code that
carries out a task. as a metaphor
think of the
remote control of your TV. on this remote control. You
have buttons for different functions
like turn on, turn off,
change the channel and so on.
These are the built in functions in
your TV. in Python
and many other programming languages
We have the exact same concept.
So we have functions that
are built into the language
and the platform. You can reuse
these functions to perform various tasks. So
here we can use the
built in Len function to get
the length of a string.
which means the number of characters in
that string.
Now, whenever you wanna use a function, you
should use parenthesis.
Now we say we're
calling this function, which basically means
we're using this function.
Now some functions take additional data,
which we refer to as arguments.
These arguments are
input to these functions. so this
len function takes an
input or an argument. Here
we pass our course variable.
and this will return the
number of characters in this string.
So let's print
that and see what we get. Run the
program. We get 18 because we
have 18 characters here. Let's look
at another example. If you
want to get access to a
specific character in the string,
you use the square bracket
notation. So here we add course square
brackets to get the first character,
you use the
index zero. So in python, like
many other languages, strings are zero index;
which means the index of
the first character or the first element
is zero. So now
when we print this we'll
get P. Okay. Now
you can also use
a negative index. Like minus
one. What does that mean? Well if
zero represents the first character here
what do you think negative one represents? that
takes us back to the end
of the string. So that returns the
first character from the end
of the string. Let's run
this program. You will see
you'll get g. There
you go. Using a similar syntax, you
can slice strings. let me show you. So
I'm going to duplicate this
line and remove negative one.
Now let's say we wanna
extract the first three characters in
this string. So here
we need two indexes: the
start Index colon(:) the end index. So
this would returns a
new string that contains the
first three characters in this course variable. That
will be P y and t.
So the index of
these characters are 0 1 and 2. So that
means the character at the
end index is not included.
Okay. let's run the
program and make sure we
get the right result.
There you go. Pyt. Now
what if we don't include the end index?
What do you think we're gonna get?
It's common sense. We
start from Index zero and
go all the way to
the end of the string.
So this will return a new string. That
is exactly the same
as the original string. Let's
take a look. So we get python programming.
now. What if we don't include
the start index
but include the end index?
What do you think we're gonna get?
once again it's common sense.
So by default
python will put zero here. so it
will start from the beginning of the string.
So when I run this
program we should get Pyt one more time. There
you go. And finally, as the last
example, If we don't include the start and
the end index this will
return a copy of the original
string. Let's look at this. So we
get Python Programming. Now
you don't have to memorize
any of these. Just remember we
use the len function to get
the length of a string. We use
bracket notation to get access
to a specific element or
a specific character.
and we use this notation to slice a string