In this lecture we're going to look at
a few useful functions to work with
numbers. So we have
this built in function round
for rounding a number.
So if you pass 2.9 here
and print the result. we'll get three
. We have another useful
built in function called A
B s. which returns the
absolute value of a number. So
if you past negative 2.9 here.
we'll get positive
2.9. Technically. we have only a handful of
built in functions to
work with numbers. If you
want to write a program that
involves complex mathematical
calculations you need to
use the math module. A
module is like a separate
file with some python code. So,
in python we have this
math module which includes lots
of mathematical functions for working with numbers. But
we need to import this module
so we can use it. on
the top, We type import math. Now
math in this
program is an object so
we can use the dot notation to see
all the functions or
more accurately all the methods
available in this object. As an example we
have math dot ceil for getting the
ceiling of a number.
So if you pass 2.2 here
and run this program. we get
three. Now in this math module we
have lots of functions. Let me show
you how to find the complete list.
Here on Google
search for python 3. Make
sure to add the version number. math module.
On this page
you can see all the
functions in the math module.
So in this lecture we looked
at math.ceil. We also have
math.copysign, fabs
and so on. As an
exercise I encourage you to play
with a couple of functions in this module.