In the last section we explored Python Standard Library.
Now even
though this library is very comprehensive,
it doesn't have everything that
we potentially need when building a real application.
There
are times that we need
features not implemented in Python Standard
Library.
That's where pypi or PYthon Package Index
comes into the picture.
pypi is like NPM or Node
Package Manager for JavaScript developers.
It's basically a
repository of python packages built by people like
you and I.
So if you head over to pypi dot org, on
this page you can see that
currently we have almost 160,000 projects
registered in this repository.
For pretty much anything you
imagine, there is a python package here.
Let's say
you want to work with PDF files in your application.
Simply search
for pdf here.
As you can see currently
we have over 2000 projects for working
with PDF files.
Here are a few examples.
This first package
is a two dimensional barcode generator.
We also have
this package for managing and processing pdf files.
The
next one is for converting a PDF file to text.
We
can also convert a pdf to image and so on.
So
we have tons and tons of packages for working with PdF files.
Of course not all of these are useful.
Some of them are buggy or
incomplete.
But if you do a little bit of research, you can find a
good and stable package for your projects.
Alternatively you
can also google the best python packages for working with
pdf files and see what other people in the community say.
So
in this section you're going to learn about
all the tooling you need to install
these packages and publish
your own packages to this
repository.
Are you excited?
All right, now let's get started.