In Python. We have a utility called
Pi Doc that comes with python
installation. With this utility.
We can easily see the
documentation for a module. That module
can be one of the modules in
Python Standard Library or one
of our own modules. Let
me show you. So here on the terminal.
if you're on Windows type
I. doc. if you're on Mac
or Lenox type. I dock three
. Next. we add mass. So we're
going to look at the documentation for
the mass module in Python Standard Library. There
you go. So the name
of this module is math. Here's
the reference documentation. So you
can copy paste this into your
browser. and on this page.
you can see all the
details of the math module.
You can see all the functions and
their description. Alternatively. you can
see all the documentation here
in the terminal window. So look
at this cool in here. That
means this is a multiple of documentation
and you can go to the next
page by pressing space. So
here is the description for this module and
below that you can see all the functions
and the short description now to exit this
multiple documentation. We press Q. Now
let's take a look at the documentation
of our pdf to text module soap
. I ducked three March pdf dot pdf
to text. There you
go. So here's the
name of our module. Next
to that. you can see our
one line description. This module provides
functions to convert to pdf
to text below that. you can
see classes. so any classes
that we have documented will
end up here. As you can see.
we have this converted class that
derives from the object class
in Python Standard Library. So
here we can see the hierarchy of our class.
Below that. we have the
documentation for the converted class.
Here you can see our
short summary for the converted class.
After that. we have
methods defined here.
So here's our convert method. followed
by its short description.
Let's go to the next page. You
can see its parameters.
the return value and so on. Now
this pie dog has a
few interesting switch. Is one of
them is W. For writing
this documentation to an HTML file
so pie 0.3 dash W. Marsh
pdf the pdf to text Now
this generated this HTML file
that contains the documentation for
this module. Now let's
open this HTML file. There
you go. So here's our module.
It's short description the
classes hears are converted class
that derives from the object class
and you can see the convert method.
its parameters and so on. We
also have another interesting switch
for loading the documentation for
this application as well
as Python standard library in
a Web server. So we
run pie Dock three dash
p that is short for port
and then add a port number
like 1234 So you started a
web server at this address.
Local host port 1234
If you open this in a browser.
we see something like
this. So on the top.
we have a few built in modules. After
that. you can see the modules in our application.
So we have this APP
module you have to set up
module as well as March PdF. which
is a package. Let's go here.
In this package. we
have two modules.
pdf to image and pdf to
text. And this is
the documentation for pdf to
text module. Now let's go back below
this you can see the
documentation or Python Standard library. for
example. We have the past
lip module here. Let's take a
look. So in this module.
we have the past class
that you have worked with.
As you can see. this class derives from
another class called Pure Path.
which derives from the object
class. Also. PATH has to derivatives politics. path
and windows path.
Again here we can see the complete documentation
all the objects in this module.
So this is all about pydoc.