To install a package from Pypi,
we use a tool called Pip.
Now If you're on Mac similar to Python,
you should use Pip3.
Now With this tool we can do various things
such as installing packages,
uninstalling them, upgrading them,
or listing the currently installed
packages.
Let's take a look at a few examples.
So
here to install a package,
as the first argument we pass install
and as the second argument we specify
the name of the target package.
So
here I'm going to install this requests package which
we're going to use to send http requests.
So let's
go ahead.
All right.
This is successfully installed,
but here down the bottom we have a
warning in yellow that is saying
you're using pip version 10
However version 18 is available.
So this version
10 is the version that came
with my python installation.
But because
pip is developed independently,
we need to upgrade it from
time to time.
So right below that you can see the command that
you need to run to upgrade Pip that
is PIB Install Dash dash upgrade
Pip.
All
right. Now I have the latest version of Pip.
Let's look at
the packages that are currently installed on my machine.
So pip
list.
Here in
this list you can see we
have installed the version 2.20 point
one of the requests package.
This version you see
here is what we call semantic versioning.
The first number
represents the major version.
The second number represents the
minor version.
and the third number represents the patches or
bug fixes.
Now back on pypi dot org.
let's
search for the request package.
So here we
have a few packages with a similar name.
We've got requests, requests3
and requests2
and they're not always in the same order,
so
make sure to pick the requests package without
2 or 3.
Now on this page on
the left side you can see
the release history of this package.
So
the latest version that I have installed is 2.20 point one
at the time of recording this video.
There are times that you want to install an
earlier version.
Perhaps the latest version has a bug or
is incompatible with the
other packages you're referencing.
So
let me show you how to install an earlier version.
back on the terminal.
Let's say we want to install version 2.9 point
zero.
That is very easy.
Just like before Pip install
requests. Now we add to equal sign
followed by the version 2.9 point zero.
So
as you can see
this successfully uninstalled the latest version
that was version 2.20 point one and
then installed version
2.9 point zero.
Now here we can also use wild
cards.
For example pip install requests
equal 2.9 point asterisk.
That
means installed the latest compatible version with
version 2.9.
So if there are any patches or bug fixes
include those as well.
Now
here on pypi dot org
you can see we have three 2.9 versions
This is the base version,
and then we got a couple more versions before
version 2.10.
So when I run this command pip will
install the latest compatible version with 2.9 point
zero which is 2.9 point two.
Let's
take a look.
Now we've got this message "Requirement
already satisfied" because we already have version 2.9
point zero installed.
So first we need to uninstall it before we
install the latest compatible version with this.
So
that is very easy.
pip, this
time we're going to use uninstall and then requests.
We
don't care about the version.
This is asking
for confirmation.
so let's go ahead.
Now Requests Version
2.9 point zero is uninstalled.
So now let's
install requests Version
2.9 point asterisk.
This will install
the latest compatible version with 2.9.
We
also have another syntax for installing the latest compatible version.
So instead of two equal sign, we use a
tilde equal sign.
And then here we specify a
specific version.
Let's say 2.9 point zero.
Once
again this will install the latest compatible version with
2.9 point zero, which
is 2.9 point two.
Now we can use this
asterisk with the minor version as well.
For example
let me uninstall this first.
so pip uninstall
requests.
Okay.
let's go ahead.
Good.
Now pip install
requests two point asterisk.
This
will install the latest compatible version with version two.
So back to the release history.
If your scroll to the very top,
you can see the latest compatible version with version two is 2.20
point one.
Let's go ahead and run this.
There you go.
So we successfully installed requests
to 0.20 point one.
Now we can use
this package just like the modules and python standard library.
So we import requests.
Now
we have a module object with these
members.
You can read about this on the documentation for
this package.
So back on pypi dot org.
Here
on the page for the request package,
If you scroll down, you
can see a link to the documentation.
Now
back to our code.
I'm going to call the get method.
Let's
send an http request to google dot
com.
This returns a response object.
For
now let's simply print the response on the terminal.
Let's
run the program.
So we got a response with the status two hundred
which indicates success.