In the last lecture you learned
how to install a package using pip.
Now
let's run pip list. You
can see currently we have installed requests version 2.20.1
There is a problem here.
Let's say we have another
project and in that project we
want to use an earlier version of
this package.
With the current structure we cannot have two versions
of any of these packages side by side.
We can have only
a single version.
To solve this problem, we need to create an
isolated virtual environment for each application and
install these dependencies into that virtual isolated environment.
Let me show you how to do that.
So here in
the project folder,
we run Python Dash m venv
and then specify the name of a directory for containing
this virtual environment.
By convention we call that env.
Now don't worry about memorizing any of these
because later I'm going to show you a
better and simpler way.
So technically you're never going to execute this
command after I show you the latest tools.
I'm just going to
take you on a step by step journey.
So you understand exactly how
these various tools come together.
So let's
go ahead and run this command.
Good. Now
here on the file Explorer panel,
you can see we have a new directory and
in this directory we have this conflict file with these
parameters:
home is referencing the directory where my
python interpreter is installed,
and here's
the version of that interpreter.
So I'm using C Python version 3.7.
We also have this bin or binary directory where
we have a bunch of tools like pip, pip3, python,
python3 and so on.
Next to that we have includ which is
currently empty.
You have lib, inside of
this directory we have python3.7 and inside
of that we have site-packages.
Now this directory
structure is slightly different on Windows.
So if you're a Windows user,
don't get hung up on these subtle differences.
Focus on the big
picture.
What matters here is that this site-packages
directory is where, we'll install the packages for
this application.
So a virtual directory is an
isolated environment where we have a specific Python interpreter,
in this case C Python version 3.7, as well
as a bunch of packages that this application needs.
Okay
now that we have a virtual environment,
we need to activate it.
Here
in the bin folder we have the script called activate.
We
need to run this from the terminal.
So back
in the terminal.
if you're on windows,
you execute this script directly
So you reference it like this env backslash bin
back slash activate that bat.
If
you're on Mac or Linux,
you will have to type source env
slash bin slash activate.
There
you go.
Now we can see the name of the currently active virtual
environment, in this case that is env.
We could
call this anything but by convention we use env.
So
now that we are in the virtual environment for this application,
let's go
ahead and install an earlier version of requests package.
So
pip install requests 2.9
point asterisk.
So
as you can see,
we have installed requests version 2.9
point two which is different
from the request package that we
installed globally on this machine.
This is specific to
this application.
Now back to our directory
structure.
Now under the site-packages directory, we
have this new directory requests.
This is where we
have installed the request package for this application.
Finally
whenever we're done,
we need to deactivate this virtual environment
So we run deactivate.
Done.