So you have learned about pip and creating virtual environments.
As
you have noticed, using these tools
requires memorizing various commands and
arguments.
There is a lot to remember.
That's where pipenv
comes into the picture.
pipenv is a tool that combines pip
and virtual environments into a single toolchain.
So
we don't have to use pip or virtual environments separately.
If
you're familiar with NPM or Node Package Manager, pipenv
is the equivalent tool in the python work.
So it's a
dependency manager for Python project.
Now you
might be curious
why I didn't start this section with pipenv?
Because
as I told you pipenv internally uses pip and virtual environments.
So you need to understand how exactly it works under the hood.
Also
as you look at various websites,
you will come across pip or
virtual environments, so I wanted to
make sure that these tools are not
foreign to you.
Now let me show you how to use pipenv.
Here on the terminal first we need to install it.
So pipenv install
pipenv.
All
right.
Now back to VSCode.
I'm gonna
delete this env directory because we don't need it anymore.
We're
going to use pipenv to automatically create a virtual directory.
So
delete.
Good.
Now back
to the terminal.
Instead of using pip to install a package, we
use pipenv.
So pipenv install requests.
Now a few things happen here.
This tool created a couple of
files:
Pipfile and Pipfile.lock.
We look
at this later.
It also created a virtual environment for us and
installed this request package
inside of that virtual environment.
But that virtual environment is not here.
Where is it?
Let
me show you.
So here on the terminal, let's run pipenv
dash Dash venv.
This
is the path to our virtual environment directory.
As
you can tell, this directory is not part of our project,
and this is
a deliberate decision because
as we install various packages we'll
end up with hundreds or even thousands of files in this virtual
environment,
and this will increase the size of our project.
So
we want to exclude this virtual environment from our project directory.
Now
I'm going to uninstall the request package that we
installed globally using pip.
So pip
uninstall requests.
Let's
proceed.
Good.
So installed independently
using pipenv.
Now let's run our application.
But for this demo,
I'm not going to use code Runner.
You will see why in a second.
So
let's run pythonapp.py.
We've
got a ModuleNotFoundError: No module named 'requests' ,
because we removed the requests package from the list of global packages,
and here python doesn't know where to locate this package.
It
has no knowledge of this new virtual environment.
So we
need to activate it.
So once again, we use the same tool that
is pipenv and
as the first argument we
pass shell.
So as
you can see this activated the virtual environment
for this project.
Now let's run our program one more time.
We
got a response.
Beautiful.
So python could successfully locate the
requests package.
So here we are currently in the virtual environment
for this project.
If you want to deactivate it,
simply type exit