So in the last lecture,
I didn't run this program using the code runner. I
used the terminal.
Now let's see what happens when we were
on this program using the code runner extension.
So there
you go.
We get the same error,
No module named
requests, because Code Runner is running this program using
the python interpreter that is installed globally,
and
that python interpreter cannot
find the requests module.
To
fix this problem, We need to tell code Runner to
use the python interpreter
in our virtual environment.
So back in
the terminal.
let's find the virtual environment directory for this project,
pipenv Dash Dash venv.
There
you go.
Now let's open this.
So
this is our directory structure that you have seen before.
Here in
this virtual environment inside of the bin folder, we've
got python3.
If you're on Windows, you have python.
So
we need to get the past so
this python interpreter and give it to the
code runner extension.
Back in VSCode, on the
top, let's go to the code menu.
then preferences and
settings. Here. click this dot. dot. dot
An open settings that Jason if
you scroll down somewhere here. you should see
Code Runner that execute her map. We said
this earlier in the course in
case you missed that step. Simply add
a new key value pair.
Here. The key is code that
runner that execute er map. When
you press enter. it automatically
generates all these settings. Now
. here we have the
path to Python. As you
can see. I've changed this
to Python three. Now we need
to replace this with the
past to the Python interpreter in
a virtual environment.
So this is the path our
virtual environment.
Let's copy this.
then back
to user settings and
replace this with this past slash Bin
slash. So we're referencing the python interpreter in
our virtual environment that save the changes back
to abduct pie. Let's run
this program using the code runner
extension. There you go. So
we fixed the issue with code Runner.
but we have a read on the line
here unable to import requests.
So
VSCode cannot find our requests module.
To
fix this problem, we need to tell VSCode which
python interpreter to
use.
Now if you look at the status part here, you can see Python
3.7.
Click this.
In this list you
should see various Python interpreters.
Now look at the last one here.
This
is the path to the python interpreter in a virtual environment.
If
you don't see this on your machine,
you need to go back to the user settings
page and add
a new setting that is python dot
python pass. We said this to the
past to the Python interpreter
in a virtual environment. So
let's pace the path to
the virtual environment. then slash
bin slash python three.
Now
after we add this,
we need to restart VSCode.
Then
when we go back to app.py,
here in the list of virtual environments,
you should see this new python interpreter.
So let's
select this.
You can see the compilation error is gone.
but
we got this other error
Linter pylint is not installed,
because
earlier we install this globally,
and now it's not available in this isolated
virtual environment.
So we need to go ahead and install
it here.
All right.
The error is gone.