When we install a package using pipenv,
two files get automatically created
Pipfile and Pipfile.lock.
These two files are
used to keep track of
the dependencies of our project and
their version.
Let's
take a look.
So first I'm going to open up the file.
Here
we have four sections.
The first one is source that
specifies address
of the repository where
these packages are downloaded from.
Below that we have Dev or
development packages,
These
are the packages that we used
as part of our development,
such as
packages that we used for automatic testing.
They're only used during
development so they don't have to
exist for our application to run.
Below that we've got the
packages that our application is
dependent on.
In this case, we are dependent on the request package,
and this asters you see here because
we didn't specify a version
when installing this package.
This asterisk means the latest
version.
If you specify the version that would end up here.
And
finally below that we've got
requires that specifies the
version of python we need to run this application.
So
this is our Pipfile.
Now let's look at the file
dot lock.
This is a JSON file that lists the
dependencies of our application and their exact version.
Let me show you.
So here on the top, we've got this section called Meta,
Don't
worry about that.
Below that we have default, and
inside of the default,
we've got all the dependencies of our application and
their exact version.
Here's the first one, certifi.
Now
we didnt explicitly install this package.
This is one of
the dependencies of the requests package.
So all
the packages that we installed and
their dependencies and their dependencies are
listed in this file.
So the version that is installed on my machine
is this version.
Now if you scroll down, you
can find the requests package and here's
the version that is installed on my machine.
Now with all the
information stored in this file,
we can take our source code,
put
it on another machine like a production environment and
reproduce
this exact execution environment.
And this minimizes or
eliminates the situation where your
application runs on your machine
but doesn't run on another machine
because there is a different version of
one of these dependencies on that machine.
Now let
me show you this workflow in action.
So here on
the terminal,
let's find the virtual environment for this project,
pipenv
dash dash venv.
Okay
here's the directory.
I'm going to delete this directory to
simulate the scenario where we
copy our project onto another
machine.
On that machine this spiritual environment does
not exist.
All we have is the source code of our application.
Right?
So on Mac or Linux we can delete that directory by
running rm -rf and
then the path of the directory delete.
So now if you run
pipenv Dash dash venv one
more time.
It tells us that no virtual environment has been
created for this project yet.
All we have is
this source code and our
Pipfiles that specify the
dependencies of our application.
Right?
So now
we need to install all these dependencies and
that is very easy.
We run
pipenv install without any additional arguments.
When we run this command pipenv
will look at our Pipfile and install
all the dependencies of our application.
All
right.
Now let's run pipenv dash dash
venv.
You can see we have this virtual environment.
And
in this virtual environment, we've got
all the dependencies of this project.
Now these dependencies are
installed based on the version specified
here.
So for the request package, we're asking for
the very latest version.
However on my machine at the
time of development,
I've been using version 2.20 point
one.
So chances are in the future when
we put this project
on a different machine and install the dependences,
we might have
a newer version of the request package.
In that case
those dependencies installed on that machine
will be different from the
dependencies on my development machine.
If you want to
install the exact same versions listed here,
you should tell
pipenv to ignore the pipfile and
use pipfile.lock.
So back on the terminal,
we run pip
env install and then supply an
additional parameter,
dash dash ignore dash
pipfile.
As
you can see,
this time pipenv have installed
the dependencies from Pipfile.lock.