So you have learned the basics of pipenv.
Now let's take a look at a
few useful commands for managing
the dependencies of our application.
We
can run pipenv graph
to see the list
of all the installed dependencies.
So currently we have installed requests
version 2.20 point one and
below that
you can see
the dependencies of the requests package itself.
In
front of each dependency,
you can see the version that was required by
the requests package, as well as
the version that is installed on
our machine.
Now let's uninstall the requests package.
So pepenv uninstall requests.
So
the request package is gone.
If you look at the Pipfile, it's
not here anymore.
Also if we run pipenv graph
it's gone.
However the dependencies of
the request package are still
here because pipenv doesn't know
if these dependencies are used
somewhere in our application or not.
However,
if we take this project,
put it on a different machine, and
install all
these dependencies from scratch,
these packages will not end up there because
currently we have not referenced them in our Pipfile.
Now
let's install an earlier version of the requests package.
So
pipenv install requests version
2.9 point asterisk.
All
right.
Now in our Pipfile, you can see we
have the request package with the version that we have requested,
and
if you look at Pipfile dot lock,
you can see the actual
version that is installed;
that is 2.9 point two.
Now to find the outdated packages,
we can run pipenv
update dash dash outdated.
We
get this yellow warning "Skip Update of Package requests".
So
this is the version that we have installed.
As you can see, there
is a newer version available,
but pipenv won't be able to install
that,
because in our Pipfile we asked for the most recent version
compatible with 2.9
So 2.20 may
not be compatible with 2.9
So let's
go to our Pipfile.
Let's change this to two
point asterisk.
So we are asking for the latest compatible
version with version two.
Now let's
run this command one more time.
This
time we don't see the yellow warning anymore.
Package 'requests' is
out-of-date,
this is the version that is installed and
this
is the version that is available.
Now we have two choices:
We
can update this package or
all packages in our project.
To
update all packages we run pipenv update,
And
to update a specific package,
we add its name here, so requests.
Okay
Now all our dependencies are up to date.
So
if you look at Pipfile dot lock, you
can see that we have requests version 2.20 point
one.
And similarly if we run pipenv graph,
you can see that
we have installed
the latest version of the requests package.