In this lecture, I'm going to show you
how to publish your own packages to
pypi dot org.
The first step is to create a new
account.
So pause the video,
create a new account,
Make
sure to activate it by clicking on the link that they send you, and
then come back continue watching.
Next
here on the terminal,
We need to install three tools globally.
So
pip or pip3 install set
up tools wheel and twine.
You will see these in action momentarily.
So let's go ahead.
Alright.
Now I'm going to start with a brand new project.
Let's say
we're going to create a package to work with PDF files.
So
I'm going to create a new directory,
call it marshpdf.
Now let's go to this directory and open VSCode
Now as a best practice, we
should create a high level directory with
the same name as our package.
So
I'm going to call that mashpdf.
Here
potentially we could have another directory for unit
tests.
We're going to look at unit tests in the future.
Perhaps
we could have another top
level directory for some sample
data and so on.
All our source code will end up here.
Now in this directory, we should add an
__init__ file,
so python will see this as a package
Now let's add a couple of modules.
So I'm going to add a
new file call that pdf2text
dot py.
Here I'm going to write a basic function like
convert, so convert that simply
prints pdf2text.
Okay,
I got this error message:
Formatter autopep8 is not
installed.
And I realized that VSCode is still referencing the
virtual environment for our previous project.
So make sure
to change that to
the main python interpreter installed
on your machine because now we are
in the context of a completely different
project.
So let's ignore that.
So
here's our pdf2text module.
We can add another module.
Let's say pdf2image dot py.
Again
here we could have some code.
Let's not worry about that.
So this
is a basic structure for a package.
Now in
order to publish this to pypi,
we need to add three files
here.
The most important one is setup dot
py.
So at the root of this project, add
a new file setup.py.
Here
on the top, we should import setup tools that we installed earlier.
This
module has a method called setup.
We
call this method and pass
a few keyword arguments.
Here
are the essential ones:
The first one is name.
We
should set this to
a unique name for our package,
So it doesn't conflict with
another package in pypi repository.
In
this demo I'm going to say this to mashpdf.
Next
one is version.
I'm going to set this to version one point oh.
we need a long description.
For now I'm going to set this
to an empty string.
We're going to come back to this in a second.
And
finally, we need to tell what packages are
going to be distributed, because
in this project currently we have one
package that is mashpdf, and
in this package we
have these two modules,
so we need to
tell setup tools about
the modules and packages
that we're going to publish.
So here we add packages and we
set it to setuptools dot find underlyine
packages.
This method
will look at our project and
automatically discover the packages that we
have defined.
However we need to tell it to exclude two
directories:
tests and data,
because they don't include
source code.
So we pass an array here with
a couple of strings tests and data.
So this is our setup file.
Now we should create a read me
file.
What we put in the read me file,
will be displayed in the homepage of
our package on pypi.
So here
in the root of the project,
let's add README,
And
by convention,
we use all capital to read me and then
lower case md,
which is short for markdown.
So here
we can use the markdown syntax.
For now I'm just going to go with a
simple example.
This is the homepage of
our project.
Save the changes.
We
also need a license file.
So once again in the root of
the project, let's add LICENSE.
Now
if you head over to choose a license dot com,
you can
find a basic template for this license file.
So let's
say you care about sharing improvements.
Click that.
Here we can see a basic license agreement template on
the top.
I'm going to click this button to copy this to Clipboard and
then paste it into this file.
That's
where license.
Now back to setup dot py.
We
should set this long description to
the content of our README
file.
So on the top, from path lib
we should import the Path class and then
create a path Object,
set it to README dot
md and then call read_text.
There you go.
So here's the final result.
Actually
I realized I forgot the keyword argument here.
So
exclude equals.
So we call find_packages
and tell it to exclude these two directories.
Now
let's quickly recap.
We added three files to our project:
A README file,
a LICENSE file, and
a setup py.
Now
we need to generate a distribution package, and
that's pretty easy.
You open up the terminal and
run python setup
dot py and pass two arguments sdist,
which is short for source distribution and
bdist underline wheel,
which is short for built distribution.
So with this command, we're going to generate
two distribution packages:
a source distribution and
a built distribution.
Let's
go ahead.
All right.
Now here we have two
new directories:
build and dist.
In the dist directory,
we have a wheel file,
which is a built distribution and a
source distribution.
Both these are zip files.
You
can unzip them and see what is inside, If you're adventurous.
Now
that we have these two distribution packages,
the final step is
to upload them to pypi dot org.
Back in
the terminal, we use twine to do that.
So twine upload
dist slash asterisk.
So
we're telling twine to upload all
the files in the dist directory.
Let's go ahead.
It's asking for my username, so mash.
And
then the password.
Alright.
My
packages uploaded to pypi dot org.
So
back here, if we search for moshpdf, we can
find that here, the current version is version one.
Here
on the homepage, we have the
content of our README file.
So
we can easily install this package
just like the other packages on
pypi.
For example, here in
our HelloWorld project,
I'm going to use pepenv to install
moshpdf.
Okay.
It's installed here.
So on the top, we can import mosh
pdf.
you can see mashpdf has these
two modules.
So I'm going to import the pdf2text module.
So from mashpdf let's import pdf
2text.
Now we can call pdf2
text dot convert.
Run the program and
here's the output.
So this verifies that we successfully published our package to pypi and
then installed it and used it.