Let me publish our packages to
pype your repository. It's really
important to document our code so
other people know how to use
it.
For example, think of the math module.
Let
me import this on the top.
import math and then
call any of its methods.
We see this little documentation here.
This is what we refer to as intelligence.
So VSCode
has this intelligence feature which
basically reached the documentation for
this method and displays it in
this little tool tip window. In
contrast. our convert function has no documentation. So
if we call it here.
it's not clear what this function does
that this is a very basic function.
But in a real application. we could
have a function with one or more parameters.
So people who use these
functions need to know what
these parameters are. what this function
does and what it returns.
So this is the purpose of documentation. Now
. in Python. we have a
special format for documenting our code called
Doc String or Documentation String. It's basically a
string with triple codes that
we add right after declaration
of function or class or variable.
This is different from
using comments because we should
use comments to explain why
we have done things in certain ways.
So we shouldn't use a comment to
explain what the function does.
What it does should be
reflected in the documentation string.
How it does what
it does or why we implemented
in a certain way should come in
the comment. So let me show
you how to document this module using
dark strength. So when
we publish a module for other
people to use. we should document the
module itself as well as
every object in it. Any classes
. any methods in those classes
or any standalone functions in that
module should be perfectly documented. So here are
the first line of the module should
be a dark string. We use triple coats
to define a dark string.
Here we can have a one line
description that ends with a period. This
is for simple cases. but if you want
to explain more. you should use a multi
line doc string By convention. The first
line should be a short summary.
followed by a black
line and then a more detailed explanation
. So if you want to use a
multi line doc string. this is the convention you
need to follow. The first line
should be a short description. followed
by a blank line followed
by multiple lines of text. But
if you're dealing with a simple case.
you can simply use a
one line dark string
that changes into something more
meaningful. Like this module provides functions
to convert a pdf to text. Now
. I wanted to document the convert function.
So right after the
declaration. we add triple coat. pay attention to
indentation and do it exactly like
what you see in this video. So
here we need a
short summary like convert the
given. Pdf to text. Next
. we need to have a blank line.
If you want to explain this
function in more details. we can do that here.
In this case. we don't need
it. So the next part is parameters. Currently
. we don't have any parameters.
But let's say we have this
past parameter here.
We need to explain what this
parameter is. what its type is
and what we use it for. So
pass of type string colon. the
past to a pdf file. Now
. if you have more parameters.
we will list them here. one on each line
. Next minute. a black line followed by
returns. What do we return here. Let's say
we return is strength.
and that is the content of
the pdf file. As text save
the changes via Scott automatically.
formats are coat. And
by the way. when we're dealing
with multiple in dark strings. we
can put the first line on
a new line. It's more of a
personal preference. I personally think
this is cleaner because we
have this triple double quotes on
the top and bottom of our dog
string. Let's save the changes now
to demonstrate what the consumer
of this module will see. Let's
go back to our project. And here
in the route I'm going to add and
you file app that pie. Let's
say we're going to consume this module.
So from March Pdf
. we impart pdf to text.
Now here you
can immediately see the documentation for module. This
module provides functions to convert
to PdF to text. so that's
the first benefit. Now pdf to text dot
convert again. Look at our documentation. Here's
a short summary of our function.
Convert the given PDF to text. You
can see the parameters.
The return time and so on. So
back to our module here
we currently have only a
single function. If we had classes again.
we'll have to
document them. So. as an example.
I'm going to define a class here
class converter. and
then I'm going to put this function
inside of the converted class. So let's
select it. And in that it here Now
we need to add the first parameter
that is self save the changes. So
here's our converted class. Right after declaration. we
need to add a dark string
that summarizes the behavior of this class
. In this case. we can go
with something like a simple converter for
converting PdF to text. Well
. we ended here. Now I know
that this may look a little bit
repetitive. but if you're providing code
for other studios. this is really
important.
Please document your code, because
nobody likes to use a libraty
that is not well documented.