in this
section you're going to learn how to
build a simple Web application using a
super popular Web framework called Django. I
love their tagline,
The Web framework for perfectionists with
deadlines.
And that's absolutely true.
If you're a perfectionist and
want to build a real enterprise
Web application that is fast, secure,
and scalable, Jangle is your best friend.
Here's
some of the popular websites that
are built with Django like Instagram. Spotify
. YouTube. Washington Post.
Dropbox and so on. So
in this section we're going to use
Jango to build a simple imaginary video
rental application called lately. So here
we have a list of movies.
Each movie has properties like
title genre. number in stock and daily rental
rate. We can click on
each movie to see more details
Now I know this is not
a fascinating looking application because our
focus in this section is not
to build a full featured application that
looks fancy.
We just want to learn how jangle works.
So I'm
gonna walk you through the process
of building applications with Django.
So
in this application we have these two pages.
We also have
an API that is available at api/movies.
So this API returns the list of our movies as JSON.
Now
if you're not familiar with APIs, don't worry
you're gonna learn everything from
scratch.
So in this section will build this application and
more importantly deploy it to
a cloud platform called Harajuku.
So you will see the process of
building a simplified web application from
A to Z.
Are you excited?
I hope you are.
And let's
get started.