Earlier we built a view function to
respond to requests sent to
this end point, slash movies.
Currently we're only
displaying this hello world message.
That's pretty boring.
So over the
next few lectures we're going to modify
this page and display the list of
movies in our database.
So here's the movie class we
created earlier.
As you can see we derived this class from the
model class in Django.
But why?
Because this
model class gives us a
bunch of method for creating, retrieving,
updating and deleting objects from our database.
So
if you want to store a movie object in our database,
we simply call
one of these methods called save.
That save method will internally
take care of generating the
right sequel statements to update our
database.
This is what we call a database abstraction API.
So this model class gives us an API
which is short for Application Programming
Interface and this API
abstracts away the complexity
of working with the database.
So now let me show you how to use this
API to get the list of movi objects from our database.
So
in our movies uplet's open up the views module.
Here's the index view function that we created earlier.
Currently we're
returning this Hello World.
Now we're going to use our model API
to get all the movie objects from our database.
So first
on the top from the Models module in
the current folder.
let's import the movie class Now
. In this function.
we simply write movie that objects
data.
With this statement we can get all the
movie objects in our database.
So when we call this at some
point, Django is going to
generate a sequel statement like
this.
Select star from movies
underline movie.
We also have a method for filtering
records.
So that is movie dot objects dot
filter.
Here we can pass arbitrary keyword arguments like
give me all the movies
with release year set to
1984.
When we
call this, at some point,
Django is going to generate a sequel
statement like this:
select star from movies underline movie
where release year equals blah blah blah.
We
also have a method for getting a single object.
So movie dot
objects dot get and here
we pass a keyword argument.
Let's say we want to get
the movie with id equal to 1.
We also have methods for
saving movie objects or deleting them
from our database.
So these methods represent our database abstraction
API that simplify a lot of cases.
Now sometimes
we're dealing with complex queries.
If these methods don't do what
we need, we can always send
raw sequel statements to our database.
Now
that aside.
In this demo let's call the
all method to get the list of movies from our database.
So movies.
Now I'm going to use
a list comprehension to get the title
of these movies.
So m dot title for
em in movies.
So now we have a
list of strings.
We can join these strings using a comma
as a separator like this.
So a
string of comma dot join. So
this will combine all the elements in
our list and return a string. We
can store that here in output.
and finally. instead
of this hello world.
we can send the output. save
the changes back in the browser.
Let's refresh. There
you go. So just before
recording this video. I added another
movie hangover. So this verifies
that we could successfully get all
the movies from our database.
But we don't want to display them like this.
We
want to render them using some html markup.
And that's what I'm gonna show you next.