In this material you're going to learn
how to return HTML Content from your
view functions.
So here on the top, you can see we're
importing this render function.
We use this function to
render a template.
So in our index view let's
delete line 8.
We don't want
to format the result as a string.
So we have the list of movies.
Now instead of returning an HttpResponse,
we want to call the render function.
The first parameter here is
the request.
So we pass this request object that we get
here.
The second parameter is the name of
our template.
We haven't created this yet
but for now let's just pass
index dot html and
the third parameter
which is optional because
it has a default value of None is the
context object which is basically
a dictionary that we use to
pass data to our template.
So in this case we want to
pass the list of movies
to render as html.
So
here we pass a dictionary.
In this dictionary we add a
key called movies and
we set this to
our movies object.
Now finally
we need to return the result of the render function.
Save
the changes. Okay.
The next step is to create our template.
So
here in the movies up,
let's add a new folder.
By
convention we should call that
templates because that's
the name that django looks for. Okay.
In
this folder let's add a new file index
dot html.
For now let's just render something
really basic to make sure
all the plumbing is working.
So
let's add an h1 Hello World. Okay.
Save the changes.
Now back in the browser.
Let's refresh this
page.
Okay. All the plumbing is working.
So now let's
render the list of movies in this HTML template.
Now
back in VSCode.
Look at the language that is currently selected to edit
this document by default.
This is set to django html
which brings a bunch of
snippets for quickly generating some Django
code.
You're going to see this in a minute.
but let's temporarily change
this to HTML.
So click this and type
HTML.
Now here I want to show you a powerful
feature that is not available
when using Django HTML as
the language to edit this file.
And that feature is called Zen
coding.
With that we can quickly
generate some HTML markup.
See
what I'm going to do.
Let's say we want a table with the class table,
inside this table
you want to have a thead section, and
inside the thead section
we want a tr,
inside this
tag we want to have
three th tags, so th times
three.
Press the tab.
There you go.
This is
what we call Zen coding.
So the first column
is the title of the movie.
The second is genre. Then
we have stock. Let's add one
more column and call it daily
rate. So this is our table heading now
. Let's create our table body.
So one more time t body
inside this tag. we want to
have a TR with four TD tax
. So TD times four tab. There
you go.
Now we want to
render this tr dynamically.
So basically
we want to iterate over all
the movies that we get in this
template and for each movie
we want to render a table row.
That's where we use Django template syntax.
So in Django
templates we can execute some
logic using template tags like
this:
So we open a curly brace.
Add a percent and
also close it with a percent.
Now in between these
braces we can write some
logic like an if statement
or a loop.
So here we want to use a for loop for movie
in movies.
Now earlier we used a context object to
pass a dictionary to this template
and in the dictionary we had
a key called movies.
That is why we can access this object
here.
Now writing logic using template tags can be
a little bit tedious.
So that's where we switch the language from
HTML to django html which
brings a bunch of snippets for automatically generating
some code.
So let's delete this line and type for.
Look
at these items here.
Anytime you see an item with this square icon,
that
represents a code snippet.
So here I can press enter and
this automatically generates a code
snippet for four loop. So
here we can type for movie press tab,
now we
are in the second place holder movies. Now
press tab.
Now we are in the third place holder.
and this is
where we want to render our table row.
So I'm
going to select this tr and
move it right
here.
Now let's also indent it.
There
you go.
So this is what we call a template tag and
we use it to execute some logic.
Now here
in our tr you want
to render some content inside
each td tag.
So we use another syntax with
double curly braces to render
the value of a variable.
So
in this case we want to render movie dot title.
Similarly we
want to render movie that genre. Next
is stock. so movie that number in
stock.
Unfortunately we don't have intelligence here.
So that's
something that you'll have to live with.
And finally we want
to render movie dot daily underline
rate.
So essentially in Django templates we have two
special notations:
one is double curly braces for rendering a
value and
one is curly brace followed by a percent to
execute some logic,
use that to execute loops as
well as conditional statements.
And finally you can see that
our for loop is terminated
with an end for template
tag.
So save the changes.
Back
in the browser.
Refresh the page and
here's
our imaginary table of movies.
Currently it has no styles
but if you inspect
any of these elements. you
can see that here we
have an HTML table now
back in this template on the top.
Let's remove this heading. We
don't really need this.
Save the changes and one
last thing before I finish this lecture.
Let's open up the views
model.
Look at this red underline.
Pylint
is complaining that the movie
class has no objects member.
Basically
the reason this is happening
is that Pylint is not familiar with
django object.
But this is pretty easy to fix.
We need to
install a package called Pilot Django.
So
let's open up a new terminal window and
run pipenv install pylint-django.
Okay.
The packages installed.
Now the next step is to
create a file in the
root of our project. So let's
collapse this folder.
Here in the root let's add a
new file.
We're going to call that .pylintrc
So this file has no name,
it only has an extension .pylintrc
This is the configuration file for pylint.
Here we need to tell
pylint to load this plug in
that we just installed pylint-django
So we set load dash
plug ins to pilot dash Jango
save the changes.
Now back in the views, you can
see the compilation error is gone.
And one more thing before I
finish this lecture.
Here we passed index dot html as
the name of our template.
While this works there is a problem with
this approach that he may face
in a real enterprise application.
Let
me show you.
So temporarily I'm going to change this to index2.
Obviously we don't have this file on disk, so we're
going to get an error.
Back to the browser.
Let's refresh this
page.
We got this error: TemplateDoesNotExist.
Now
if you scroll down here.
we can see the parts that
django searches for to find this template.
So here we
have three paths.
The first one is for the admin app.
So
admin/templates/ index2.html.
The
second one is for the auth app.
So here's the auth app.
It
looks in the auth app/templates/index2.html.
Now the source code
for these two apps is not
part of our project but they
actually exist in our virtual environment.
So here is the path to our virtual environment, somewhere
here we have this directory site packages slash django
slash contrib slash auth and so on.
Now
the third path here is for our movies app. So vidly
slash movies slash templates slash index2.
Why
does this matter?
Well in a real project we're going
to have multiple apps.
As you can see when we try to render
a template Jangle looks at
the templates folder of all the
installed apps in the order.
So here in
our settings module you have seen
the list of installed apps before.
So
we have admin, auth and so on.
So when Django
tries to find a template,
it starts here on the top.
It
looks at each app,
If that APP has a templates folder,
it
will search the templates folder of that
app to find the given template.
And
that means if we
use a general name like
index.html, it is possible that django loads
the index.html of
another app that is installed first,
not the app that we are currently working with.
So as a best practice
we should give a name space to these templates.
Here's how we
do it.
In our templates folder we
add another folder movies.
That
is our name space.
Now we move index.html inside
this folder.
Move.
And then
in our code we always prefix
our template name with movies slash
Well that depends on the
app you're currently working with.
So
all the templates for the movies APP
should be prefixed with movies slash.
Now save the changes.
Back in the browser.
Refresh
the page.
Problem is solved.
So this is our table, but
that looks pretty boring.
In the next lecture, I'm going to show you
how to install
Bootstrap and give this page
a nice and modern look.