In this lecture we're going to add
bootstrap to our vidly application.
In case
you're not familiar with Bootstrap,
it's basically a very popular CSS
framework that gives our applications a
modern look and feel.
It's responsive
and mobile friendly right out of the box.
So we don't have to do any extra
work.
So head over to get bootstrap dot com,
then go to the documentation page.
Here we can find
the instructions to add boots
draft to an existing website. So
basically. we have to add a CSS file.
And here's the U
R L of debt CSS file in the cloud.
You can also download it
and add it as a static
file in your project. We should also
load a bunch of
JavaScript files now. below that
. you can see the starter template.
So let's copy this
template. Now back in our project in
the templates folder of our movies App.
Inside the Movies folder
. Let's add and you file.
We're going to call that base that
HTML. So this is the basic template
for all the pages in our movies.
App. Let's face the
start. a template that
was just copied. Okay. now
here on the top.
Let's change the title to widely and
in the body section.
Let's remove this H one
. Instead. We want to define
a placeholder for other templates. So
when we render the list of movies.
that template is going to return an HTML
table. We want to render
that HTML table right here. So
we need a placeholder for our
views to render their templates in
. And then it's pretty easy to
define here we can type block again
. This is one of the code
snippets that is available when using Django HTML
as the language to edit this file.
So let's press enter
now. Here we have multi curse or editing.
So whatever we type comes after
block and end block. we're going
to give this block and name
. Let's call it content.
Now. press the escape button and
remove the second content here.
We don't really need to
add that to end block tag.
So this is our content area
. Save the changes. Now.
let's go back to our index template. We
can open the fight here or let
me show you a short cut. If
you're on Mac press command on P.
if you're on Windows Press
Control and P here. We can easily find
the files in our project.
So let's search for index at
HTML. There you go.
Now on the top. we
need to use another
template tag called Extent. So
we jangle html selected as
the language for this file. Let's
type extends press enter.
What is the template that
we're extending that is based that html No
. Where should we put this table.
We should put it in the content block that
was just defined. So one more
time We use the block template
tag. As you can see again.
we have multiple cursors activated
. Suppress the escape button
a couple of times. Now
you have only a single cursor.
So let's type content
. That's the name of our block.
Now we need to move our table in
between the block tax.
so I'm going to select this line
and press Ault and
down Arrow to move it
down like this. There you
go. Now let's also invent this table tag
that is better. Save the
changes back in the browser. Let's
refresh this page. We've got
a template load error because Django
cannot find are based
at the html template Once
again. look. here are the path
it's searching for. so it's looking for
admin slash templates slash base html. Similarly
. we have another path for
us app and one for the
movies. App Now look at the past
that is used for the movies app that
is. Movies slash templates slash base that HTML
. But as I told you as
a best practice. we should name space or
templates. So in this case.
it's based on HTML doesn't
really exist in this folder.
It's under the movies folder
inside the Templates folder. So to
fix this problem. we need to go
back on the top and use our name
space. that is. Movies slash save the
changes back here. Refresh.
The problem is gone.
and our page looks a littlebit better.