Now let's take this page to the next level.
Let me show you how to add a
bootstrap navigation bar on the top. So and
bootstrap documentation on the left side.
Look at components. Here
. We have various components.
like alert badges and so on. In
this list. you can find nav bar. Okay
. And on this page you can
see various examples of a bootstrap navigation
bar so we can have a
navigation bar with drop down lists. If
you scroll down. you can
see a very simple navigation
bar called Brandt. And below that.
you can see the
HTML markup to render
this navigation more. So let's
copy this Now back to our based on
HTML right after the body tag. Let's
paste this navigation bar and
then change nav bar too quickly. Save
the changes back here. Let's refresh. So
here's our navigation bar. That is better.
Now this table is currently taking
the entire width of the page.
Let's make it center. So
back to based on html.
we should wrap this content
block inside of a main
element with the container class
. So. in bootstrap.
you want to create a main
tag with the class container. And
then we want to
put this block inside of
the main task. Save the changes back
in the browser. Refresh.
There you go. That is better. Also
let's add the vertical borders to this table.
So back
to our template index at HTML.
Here's our table. Let's
add another class table. dash bordered
. save back in
the browser refresh. So that
looks better. Also.
I'm going to add another class
table. dash. hover. And with this we
get Let's refresh.
We get this nice effect here
. so our application looks better now.
But there is a problem. This base
template that we defined that
contains this navigation bar exists in
the movies. App. What if we had
several other apps in this project. We
don't want to redefine this bootstrap
template in every single app. So
in the next lecture. I will show
you how to share a base template across multiple apps.