In this lecture you're going to learn
how to share a base template across multiple apps.
So currently. in our movies app.
we have this base template. We
want to take this out of this
app and put it somewhere central. So
let's collapse this full there and create a
new folder in the root.
We're going to call that templates. Now
let's go to the movies app
and get this base template and
move it into the
new templates folder. So drag
and drop move Beautiful. Now
let's go to the index
template of the movies App. Currently
. we're referencing the base template
in the movies app. but this template
is no longer there. So let's remove the
prefix or name space. Save the changes back
in the browser.
Let's see what we get. So
Django cannot find this
based on HTML template. And
if you scroll up. you can see
the paths that jangle search for to
find this template. As you can
see in this list. Jenko by
default only looks inside the installed apps
. So currently. the installed
apps that have templates are admin
. auth and movies. But this templates folder
that we just created doesn't belong
to any apps. So we need
to tell Django to search in
this folder as well. So let's
open up our settings file
that is inside the widely app
. Or we can press command
on P on Mac or control P
on windows and search for settings pie. Now
. in this file. somewhere we have the
templates settings. There you go. So look at
these properties. The back end
is set to jangle the
template that back ends the jangle jangle templates
. So this is the engine
that comes with jangle that processes are
template files. This is the engine
that is aware of those double curly
brace syntax or the template tax. Okay. Now
. the second property here
is the directories that Django should
look for to find templates.
This is set to an empty list
by default. So we'll have to
add our new templates folder here. Below
that. we have up directory set to true.
And this is telling
Django to search in the
templates folder of the installed apps
. And finally we
have this context processors. So
by default we have
four context processors. The first
one debug adds debugging information to the context
object that is passed from
the view to the template. The
second processor. It's called Request and this adds
the request object to our
context so we can access it
in our templates. Similarly. we have another context
processor us. and this is
used to bring information about the
current user in our templates.
And finally we have messages and
this is used in scenarios where
the user creates a new movie and
we want to display a message like
the new movie was created successfully. So
back to the business Here.
here. we need to add our new templates
folder. So this is the
code that money too. right. We
need to go in the OS module.
From there we go to the
path module. Here we have
a function Join for joining
multiple paths. We want
to get the base directory
of this application. This is
a known predefined variable in
Django applications. Now we
want to join this with
the templates folder that we just created. Save
the changes. So with
this jangle will start searching
here. and if it can't find a template.
then it will look at the
installed applications. So back in the browser. Let's
refresh.
There you go.
Now we have a base template that
we can share across multiple applications.