Now our video application currently only displays the list of movies.
It
would be nice if we could click
on a movie and see its details. So
the first thing we need to do is
to define a u R L that takes
a parameter like movies slash one where one
is the id of a movie.
So that can be s code
in our movies. APP. Let's open
up your else dot pie Here
. We need to define a
new U R L pattern. So let's
call the path function as the
first argument you're going to pass
a string like this.
We use angle brackets to define a
parameter. Let's call that movie. Underline it now
to refresh your memory. Earlier.
I told you that the main Euros module
in our project hands off
any or else that starts
with movies slash to this Urals module in
the movies App. Let's take a look.
So here in
the vidly folder. let's open up Urals. that
pie. So here we
define a Ural pattern. So
we're telling Django that any
girl that starts with movies Slash
should be handed off to
the Urals module in the
movies app. Now back
to the movies app when
we add a parameter here
that represents a u R
L that looks like this because
all the Urals were working within
this module. Start with movies slash. Okay
. now we need to map
this to a view function. So views
. Let's call that detail. Currently.
we don't have that. but we're going to
create it soon. Now. as a best practice.
we should also give
you the name. These names
are useful in situations where we
have multiple references to a u R L.
Let's say slash movies
slash one Now.
for whatever reason. we decided to
change this u R l
to something like this. Let's
say old system slash movies slash one. If
you have multiple references.
multiple hard coded references to
you are like this. Then we'll
have to update all those references to
the New York girl. So that's
why we use names here. These
names should uniquely identify you are
less so in our 10 place. Instead
of hard coding these Urs.
we reference them with their names and
then in the future. if you want to
change the u. R l. we can change
it in a single place. I'm going to
show you that later in this section. So
back to the business.
Let's call this detail and
also as a best practice.
it's better to name space this name
. Some movies underline detail and movies
underlying index. So this
is our neural pattern. Now
let's go ahead and create
this view function. So if
you're on match press command and P.
if you're on Windows Press Control P
and search for views and the movies app
Okay. now let's add a new view function
. We call that detail.
It takes a request and
also a parameter called movie_id because in
our URL pattern
we use the keyword movie
id So when we
send a request to let's say
movies/1, django will automatically extract
one. and then it
will call this view function
and pass one as an
argument for movie I D
. Okay. so for now.
let's just return and http response
with this movie. I d save the
changes back in the browser. Let's head
over to movies slash one. So
we get one here.
Let's change this to two beautiful. Everything
is working. However.
I can pass a non numeric
value like a and
that also gets passed as
the movie idea. But as you
know in our model. our movie
ids are integers. Look. here's our movies table
. The first column is I D.
And it's an integer. So
by default. Django uses an
integer for primary kids. But we
can always change that if
you want to. So back
to the U. R L s module here.
I'm going to use a type converter
to convert this value
to an integer. So we
prefix that with int colon. Save the
changes now back in the browser. If
you pass a as the movie I d.
Let's see what happens. Django
cannot find that page. So this
is some level of protection. We
can ensure that we
only get numeric values for
our movie id parameter.
Now let's change this back to
one. Beautiful.
So in the next lecture, we're
going to get the movie object with this id and
render it on this page.