So here's our detailed view function and
this function we get the movie
id.
So we can use our movie model to
get the movie with the given id.
It's a movie.objects earlier
you saw that all methods for getting
all the movies from the database. We
also have another method
for getting a single movie
. I hear we pass a
keyword argument like I d equals movie
i D. We also have
a known keyword PK. which
is short for primary key. You can
use either I d or P. K
So we get a movie
with this I d. Now
we need to put this in a template.
render it and return the result. So
here we return rent there
we pass a request object
. Then I'm more template is
going to be movies slash detail dot
html See the convention I'm following.
so I'm naming my templates based
on their view functions. Okay. So back
here finally we need to pass our context object.
which is a dictionary here
. We're gonna have a key called movie.
and we set it to this
movie object. Save the changes. Beautiful
. Now let's create our template.
So in the
template for their Inside the Movies folder.
Let's add and
your file detail dot html in
a stand plate on the top.
First. we need to extend the
base html template. Then we
need to define a block. So block the
blocks were going to use
is the content block. So here
I'm going to press the escape button
a couple of times to disable multi
cursor editing and type content. Now
. in this block. I want
to render a description list tag so
temporarily I want to change
the language of this file from
django dot html to HTML.
You also have a
shortcut for that. So you
can press shift command and
pee on Mac or shift
control p on windows here
type language and the
first item is change language
. Mod enter.
Let's change this to HTML. Okay
. Now. when we change the language to HTML.
you can see we don't get this syntax
highlighting. So these tags are not recognized Now
they want to create a d l tag.
Inside this tag. we
want to create a d.
T. And next to that. we
want to have a d.
D. So in this case. DL is
short for description list.
In the description list. we have one
or more pairs of DT and DD.
which are short
for term and description.
Now we want three of these
. so I'm going to
wrap these in parenthesis. then
multiplied by three tab. Beautiful. So
the first term went out. Here is
the title of the movie below that
will render the actual value.
So double Curly braces movie
the title. The second term is genre. and
similarly. we're going to
define it here. Movie. that
genre. And finally. let's add Stark so
movie that number and stuck save
the changes are formatting
is completely messed up. So
let's change the language back to
jangle html one more time. Change
language to jangle html. Now
I have to manually fix this formatting like
this. Okay. Yeah. Now let's test our
new view. So back in the browser.
let's refresh this
page. And here's how a description list is
rendered because also. add this
in a table that's a matter of personal preference