So our application is working out to this point.
But what if I pass an
invalid movie idea here. Let's say 10 we
get an exception of
type does not exist. That
is not good. So the common
pattern to handle these situations is
to return an http 404 error. 404
is the standard http error
that says the page or the
resource we're looking for
does not exist. So to
fix this problem. we need
to handle this exception and return
an http 404 error. So we wrap this
and a try block and
then catch the exception. So
here we accept.
The exception is of type does
not exist. and this
exception class is part of
our model. So movie dot
does not exist.
Let's have a quick look at
this class one more time.
so I'm going to go in the models
module.
Here's our movie class.
We derive this from the model
class in Django.
This Model class defines this exception,
DoesNotExist, and that
is why it's inherited in
our movie class as well as
any other models in our project. So
we handle this exception. and here will
return a 404 error.
So on the top from
django dot http module.
we need to import http four
or four class now
back to our view of
function. When we catch this exception. we
should raise the HDD before of our exception. So
instead of returning.
we're going to raise http four
or four because this is an exception
class that we need to raise. So
save the changes.
Back in the browser.
Let's
pass an invalid movie idea here.
and we get a
page not found with a status code 404.
Now
back to view function.
Every time we have to get a single object and render
it, we'll have to follow this pattern.
We have to add this try statement,
get the movie,
render it and
then catch an
exception of type DoesNotExist and
then raise an
Http404 exception.
In a real application where
you have a lot of view functions
like this detailed view function. this pattern
ends up being so repetitive.
So that's why we have a shortcut for
that in Django. Because.
as I told you before. Django is
focused on productivity so
we can build applications with
less code. So on the top. Here we
have this module. Django. that shortcut from
this module. Let's import get object or
four or four. This is a function.
This function implements
this pattern so we don't have to
repeat it in every view function. So
now we can simplify this
view function like this. We
remove. try and accept
statements. Now. instead of getting
a single object using the get method.
we're going to use the shortcut
function. That was just important. So but
still it is recall. Get object or
four or four. We passed the primary key.
and this function will
automatically raise a four or four exception.
If this movie doesn't
exist now. save the changes back
in the browser refresh.
Oops. I missed the
first argument.
So here this function should know
what kind of model to work with.
So earlier we used the
Movie class, the Movie model,
but currently when calling this function
we haven't specified this model.
So this function doesn't know
what model it should query.
So as the first argument we need to
pass our model class. that is movie. Okay
Now save the changes and
refresh this one more time,
now we get a Page not found error