All right.
Now let's modify this page and
add a link to each movie.
So we
can navigate and see its details. So
here on index dot html.
this is where we are rendering our
movies. Here's our first column
where we render the movie
title. Let's add an HTML anchor
here. So here
we set a trap to slash movies slash
. Now we want to render
the idea of the movie dynamically. So
once again we use
double Curly braces movie dot
Heidi and then we
move movie that title right
between the anchor tax. Save the
changes back here. Let's go to the movies
Page Refresh. So now we
have the links here. Beautiful.
We can click and
see the detail for each movie.
However while
this implementation works, it's not
the best way to reference URLs.
Because earlier I told
you that tomorrow it is possible that
we change all these URLs
to something like this old
system slash movies.
Now technically we should not change
URLs because a URL is a contract of
an application.
So if we change URLs any applications that
depend on those URLs are going to break.
But you know
the real world is unpredictable.
so sometimes these things
happen.
So let me show you
a better way to reference the URL.
Back to  our URLs module.
Earlier we
assigned a name to each URL.
Now we can reference these
URLs using their names.
So back in the index at
HTML. let's delete what we have in
the h ref attribute.
Here we're going to use the
url template tag.
So we had curly
braces. Percent and type. You are. This
is our URL template tag.
With this tag
we can get an actual URL like this.
So first we
pass the name of our URL, in this case movies_detail,
and then optionally we
can pass any parameters if
they exist, In this case we want to pass movie.id.
Save the changes.
Back to the movies page.
Refresh.
We still get the same result. Beautiful.
Now let's
take this to the next level.
Back to the urls module.
Earlier
I told you that it's a
good practice to prefix all these names
with the name of our app like movies underline.
We did that,
so Django wouldn't accidentally pick
a URL with the same name from
a different app.
Just like how we name spaced our views.
So
this was a good practice.
However let me show you a better way.
Here
we can set a known variable, app underline
name, to the name of this app, lets say movies.
Django
is aware of this variable name.
Now when we set this
app name here we don't
have to repeat movies underline
in multiple places.
Now here we have only two URL patterns.
It's
not a big deal.
But if you have a large number of URLs this
is going to get a little bit messy.
So let's delete
this and also here. Now
we go back to
our index dot html and
instead of using an underline, we use a colon.
When
Django sees this it knows that
we're talking about the movies app
and in that app we should have a URL named detail.
But
this will only work
if we set the app
name variable to movies.
So as you learn about Django. you
realize that there are various ways to
write less code. But of course that
means there are a lot of conventions
that you have to learn about. So
for sure there is a learning curve at the beginning.
But once you learn these conventions
you can quickly build applications
and deliver a lot in less time