In this lecture we're going to learn
how to build an API or
an Application Programming
Interface for our vidly application.
With this API other
websites or mobile apps can work with our data.
In practical
terms that means we're going
to expose new endpoints that start
with API, for example api/movies, so
other websites or mobile apps
can send an http request
to this end point and get the
list of our movies in JSON format.
That is pure data.
There is no HTML markup.
So
they can get the list of our movies and
do whatever they want with it.
Pretty
much most of the popular websites
that you're familiar with like Facebook, twitter,
YouTube, yelp and so on
all these websites have APIs,
so you can work with their data in your apps.
This
is the benefit of publishing APIs.
Now in this
lecture. we're not going to look at
consuming a piece that's a different topic
. But you're going to learn how
to publish a piece so others can consume
Europeans.
Now when it comes to building APIs
in Django applications,
there are basically two popular frameworks:
One of them is django-tastypie
which is currently at
version 0.14 and
surprisingly it's
beta but it's been actively used in production on
several websites.
In fact it's been around for a long time since
2010.
I have personally worked with it and
I've been really
happy.
It has a very nice design and
that's the framework that I'm going
to show you in this lecture.
There is another framework that
is called djangorestframework or DRF.
This framework is a little bit more feature rich and
you may want to
use it in a large enterprise application.
But compared to
tasty-pie it's a little bit more complex to use.
That's why in
this lecture I'm going to use tasty-pie.
So back
in V s coat under terminal.
let's install Django
Dash tasty pie. All
right.
Now we need to create a new app in this project.
So python
manage.py startapp and
we're going to call that app api.
So this app is
purely responsible for exposing api end points.
Let's
go ahead. Done.
Now we need to register this
in the list of installed apps So let's
go to settings that pie here
somewhere. We should have the installed apps.
There you go. So
we need to reference the conflict class
in this app. That is a P
dot apps that AP I config. Let's
just quickly double check to make
sure regard it right. Some in
the list of files Here's our AP AP
in this app. We have
this apps module and here's the
name of the class.
Admit reference AP conflict.
Okay.
so save the changes.
Now in
this app we're going to add a new model.
So let's
open up the models module.
In
the world of APIs we
refer to our models as resources.
You
would have heard the term REST full API.
REST stands
for Representational State Transfer.
It's a technical jargon
for a bunch of conventions
that define how applications should
talk to each other over http protocol.
Now
in the REST world we have these URLs.
URL stands
for Uniform Resource Locator. So
with this URL we can locate the movies.
Movie here
is a resource.
So essentially in the REST world
we're exposing
some of our resources
using URLs or Uniform Resource
Locators.
So back to the models module we
need to create a movie resource.
So class movie
resource. You could also call it movie. but
it's better to add resource here
to differentiate this from the movie
model we have in the movies App.
Because that movie class
is part of our data model. We use
that to get data from our database. but
this is a movie resource. which is
different from that. We use this to represent
the concept of a movie
in a restful API. You're
going to see that shortly.
So we should derive this class
from the ModelResource class in django-tastypie.
So on the top from tastypie dot
resources we need to import the ModelResource
class and then at that here ModelResource.
Now
tastypie looks for an inner class in this class
called meta.
So here we add another class
meta.
This class defines some metadata about
our movie resources.
So there are a couple of
attributes that we need to set here
that tastypie looks for and
by
the way you don't have to memorize any of these,
you can always come back to
tasty pies documentation.
So the first attribute is
queryset and
we need to set this to the quarry for getting
the list of all movies.
So on the top from
our movies app dot models module we
need to import the movie class and here
we're going to say movie dot objects dot all.
Now
this all method simply returns a qyery.
It's not going to
go in the database and
get the list of all movies.
It simply returns
a query.
This query will be executed at some point
in the future.
This is what we call lazy loading.
So
this query object is a lazy object.
Now the
second attribute that we need to
set is resource_name,
and we set this to movies,
and this determines what our endpoint
will look like.
So we use movies here and
that means later we'll
have an API available at
api/movies.
Okay.
So
we're done with our models.
The next step is to generate our
URL endpoints.
So let's go to
our main vidly app here and open
up the U. R. L s module. Currently
. we have two Ural patterns.
Earlier. we told Django that anywhere
else that starts with movies
should be delegated to this
module.
We're going to take the same approach.
So let's
create another path and
tell Django that
any URLs that starts with api slash,
we
want to hand it off to a different module.
What is that module?
Well here we need to import our
MovieResource model.
So from api.models let's
import the MovieResource model.
Next
we need to create an instance of this class.
So let's call
that movie_resource.
Now
this object has a property called
urls.
We don't see that here in intelligence.
But this attribute returns
the URLs for this MovieResource based on the
resource_name that we set here.
Okay.
So
let's delete line 21.
Back to our include function.
Here we pass movie_resource.urls.
Save
the changes.
That's all we had to do to create an API
to expose our movie objects or
more accurately movie
resources.
So to recap we installed tasty
pie.
We created a new app called api.
In that
app we added a new model that
represents our movie
resources and
finally we registered a new
URL pattern in urls.py.
Now let's test our
API.
So back here.
Let's head over to api
/movies.
There you go.
So all
our movie objects are serialized as JSON.
Here
in this JSON object
we have this property meta.
This
object has a few properties
that is used for pagination.
You
can see currently we have a total
of two movie objects in our database.
Below
that we have these objects property
which is set to an array of
movie objects.
And here are our movie objects that
were retrieved from the database.
So more accurately referred
to each of these objects as a movie resource.
This is the
public representation of a
movie in our application.
Now
currently this public representation
looks exactly like our
movie model in the movies app.
So all the properties we
had there also exist here.
But this may not always
be the case in a real world application.
For example let's
say in our api,
we don't want to expose this property date
created.
Let's say this is purely used internally by
our application.
So back to our api app.
Here
in the meta class,
we can set this attribute, exclude, we
set it to a list and
in this list we specify the
properties or the fields that
wewant to exclude, in this case date
underlined created.
Save the changes.
Back
here.
Let's refresh.
Now that property is
gone. Beautiful.
We also have this property resource_uri
that only exists in our movie resource objects,
and
this returns a url that
we can access to get more details about
this movie.
So that is set to /api/movies/1,
where one is the id of this movie.
So if
you head over to this address, we
can see the properties of this movie object only.
So
in this lecture
we built a fully function api
with only a few lines of code.