In this lecture you're going to learn
how to install Django and create your
first Django project.
So here on the command line or terminal
let's create a new directory called vidly, that
is the name of our imaginary video rental application. Okay.
Now let's go in this directory and
install Django using
pipenv.
So pipenv install django
and let's set the version to 2.1,
to make sure we're
using the exact same version.
So there are no surprises later on
as you go through the videos.
Okay. let's go ahead. Beautiful.
Now we need to activate our virtual environment.
That is pretty easy.
So pipenv shell. Okay.
As you can see, the virtual environment
for this project is activated.
Beautiful.
So next we're going to use
a tool called Django Admin
for creating a new Django project. So let's
run django-admin startproject.
I'm going to call this project vidly, and
we want to create it in the current directory.
So let's add a
period at the end.
When we run this command, django
admin is going to create a
basic website with some boilerplate code.
You're going to see that in a second.
So let's go ahead. Beautiful.
Now let's open this in VSCode.
So code period.
All right.
Here's what we got.
Django Admin created this vidly
directory as well as this
manage.py file.
We
use this manage.py
to perform some administrative tasks, such
as starting our web server, or
migrating our database,
populating
it with data and so on.
You're going to learn about these as we go through
these tutorials.
Now what is this vidly directory and why
do we have two vidly directories, the outer one and
the inner one?
Well the other one is the one that we created and
that's the container for this project.
The inner one is simply a
package that is essentially the core of our project.
It has a
bunch of settings and
that's where everything gets started.
So
what do we have here?
We have __init__.py.
We have
seen this before.
This tells Python to treat this directory as
a package.
Below that we have settings up I
and in this file we have
various configuration settings for our project. Next
we have urls and this is
where we define various urln points
for our application.
And finally we have wsgi
which is short for
Web server Gateway interface. The
purpose of this file is
to represent a standard interface between
applications written in python and Web servers.
That is
an advanced topic and goes beyond
the scope of this tutorial.
So for
now don't worry about it.
Now we're going to use this manage.py to
start our development Web server.
So open up manage.py.
Now with our python code open In VSCode,
we can select our Python interpreter.
So click this python on
the status bar.
This is the Python interpreter that is installed globally.
We need to change this to the Python interpreter installed in
our virtual environment that is this one here. We
get this familiar message:
Linter pylint is not installed.
So
let's go ahead and install that.
All
right.
Now in this terminal window with
vidly Virtual environment activated,
let's run python or python3 manage.py runserver. Now
by default this is going to
start a development server on Port 8000.
If you have an application that
is already listening on that port, you
can specify a different port number here.
In this tutorial, I'm
going to go with the standard port.
so let's run this. Okay.
You get this warning:
you have 15 unapplied migration(s).
Don't worry about that.
We're going to get to that shortly.
So as you can
see, we have a web server
listening at this address and
we can stop it at any
time by pressing control z.
So
now let's navigate to this address.
All right.
Here's
our first Django project. Beautiful.
Over the next few lectures we're
going to modify this application bit by bit and
implement our imaginary video rental application.