All right.
So we have done so much in this half.
We have created our movies page,
we added navigation,
here we can see the details about the
movie,
we also published an api.
However our
homepage is broken.
So if we head over here, we
got a page not found.
So at the beginning of this section, just
after we created our Django project,
we had a beautiful homepage here.
What happened to that?
Well Django displays that automatically
until we register a newurl pattern.
So
here in our main urls module
initially we only had this
admin url pattern.
The moment we register a
new url pattern,
Django stops displaying that default homepage.
And the HTML for that homepage
is not stored anywhere in this project.
So
we need to manually create a new homepage.
And that's pretty easy.
Let me
show you.
So here in our vidly folder, let's
add a new file, views dot
py.
In this module we're going to define a view
function called home that takes a request.
And
here we simply render a template and
return it.
So on
the top first from django.shortcuts we
need to import the render function.
And then
here we return render.
As the first argument
we'll pass our request then as a
template we pass home.html.
And here we
don't need to pass a context object
because we're not going to display any
data on our homepage.
So delete.
Now
we need to map this view function
to a url endpoint.
So
back to urls module.
First we need to import our
views module.
So from the current folder,
let's import views.
Next we add a new url pattern.
So path.
We
pass an empty string to represent the homepage.
We map this
to views.home. Okay.
Now
finally we need to create the template.
Here we have two options: One
option is to add the templates folder
in this vidly folder,
just like how we added templates to our movies app.
But if you
do so, we should also register
this folder as an app in
settings.py because by
default this is not registered as
an app.
It kind of looks like an app,
but it's not an app.
So if
you look at settings.py,
here in the list of installed apps
we don't have an  app that represents vidly.
So
if you want to register this as an app,
we need to add a configuration class
just like the movies and api apps.
So we need to add a
file called apps.py and
in that file we need to create a
class called VidlyConfig.
After we installed the
vidly app, Django will be
able to find the templates in
this app. Okay?
So this is one option.
The other option is
to put all this general templates
like home page, about page,
contact page and similar pages inside the
main templates folder in this project.
The
approach you choose It's more of a personal preference.
I personally have
tried both and
sometimes I go back and forth between these two
approaches.
But there's really no practical differences between
these two approaches.
Yes, we can sit down and argue for one hour about
the differences between these approaches
at a theoretical level, but
in practice these arguments are useless.
So to keep things
simple, I'm going to add ourhome template
in the main templates folder.
So new file home.html.
Now
here first we need to extend our base dot
HTML template.
Then we need to define a block called
content.
And in this
block I simply want to add
a link to our movies app.
So let's add an anchor with
href set to and
here we're going to use the
url template tag.
So url, enter.
What is
the url that we want to render?
Well that is movies
colon index.
So once again we're referencing
a url by its name.
Save the changes.
And
it's better to a indent this to make it cleaner.
And one last
thing before we test the result,
let's add a label here Movies.
Now save the changes.
Back in the browser.
So
here's our new homepage.
I know it doesn't look fascinating,
but it
gets the job done.
So we can navigate to the movies page and
see the list of movies.