This vidly application we have built is useless,
if it's going to sit on our
machine.
So we should upload or
deploy this somewhere where
other people can use.
So in this lecture I'm going to show you
how to deploy
this application to a very popular
cloud platform called
heroku.
heroku is not the only platform for
deploying Django applications.
You can also use Google Cloud
Platform, Amazon Web services or AWS, Microsoft
Azure and so on.
The steps that I'm going to show you to deploy this
application,
some of them are specific to heroku.
So if
you want to deploy this application to
a different cloud platform, some of these
steps are going to be different.
So the first thing I
want you to do is to
open up your browser and
head over to heroku.com.
Now
go ahead and
create a new account.
It's going to take only a few seconds and
you don't need to provide a credit card to sign up.
So you can try it
first and if you like it,
you can upgrade to get additional capacity.
The
next thing I want you to do is to install heroku cli.
So
search for heroku cli.
CLI stands
for Command Line Interface
and it's basically a program that we
run on the command line on the terminal
and with this program we're going
to perform some administrative tasks
such as logging into our
account, settings some configuration, looking at the logs
and so on.
So on this page you
should be able to find heroku cli
for your operating system.
So you can see we have
various implementations for Mac, Windows
Linux and so on.
And the third thing I want you to install is git
which is the most popular Version Control System.
So with
that we can version our code.
So we're going to check our code into
a repository and
every time we make changes to our code we're
going to commit that code to our repository.
And with this we can
look at the history of changes to our code.
We can see who has
made what changes when.
It's really really powerful.
Now
the explanation of git is beyond the
scope of this tutorial that requires its
own tutorial or course.
But in this tutorial you're going to learn the basics.
So
to download git,
head over to git-scm.com.
Here go to downloads
and download git installer for your
operating system.
So positive video.
Now do these three
steps.
When you're done, come back continue watching.
All
right.
First let's make sure that
you have installed all the prerequisit properly.
So
here on the terminal,
let's run git --version.
So I have installed git version 2.19.
And also
heroku --version.
Currently
I have heroku version 6.13.
But there's an update available.
I'm not going to worry about that in this tutorial.
So let's go ahead and prepare
this application for deployment.
Now first you need to install
a package called gunicorn
which is a popular Web server for
python applications.
Because the Web server that we have used so far is
purely a simple, lightweight, development server,
we're not
going to use that in a production environment.
In case you're not familiar with
the term production environment
that is basically the environment where
our customers access our application.
In this case it's
going to be an application in heroku.
We can also have a
testing environment where we give
our application to a limited number
of users for testing.
So back to the business.
Let's
install Unicorn.
So pipenv install gunicorn.
Make sure to spell it properly.
All
right.
Next in the root of our project we
need to add a new file.
So here in the root let's
add a new file Procfile.
Make
sure to spell this properly.
So P is capital and this
is really important.
So Proc which is short for process file.
This is a special file that
heroku looks at to start our
application.
In this file we should write:
web collon gunicorn vidly
dot wsgi.
What is
going on here?
Well with this we're telling heroku that
we need a web process, that is
a kind of process used for Web
applications.
And to start that process,
we need to load
gunicorn that is our Web server.
And here is the name of
the module that gunicorn should
use to start our application.
In
this case that is vidly.wsgi
So here's our vidly folder
that is our vidly package.
In
this package we have
this module wsgi
which is short for
Web Server Gateway Interface.
So
save the changes.
Now the next step is to prepare the static files
for deployment.
Static files are like CSS files, images,
JavaScript files and so on.
Now in this application we don't
currently have any static files.
But this admin interface that
we have used so far,
has a number of static files that give
this application this look and feel.
So we need to bring those
static files into our current
project and deploy them to heroku.
So back in VSCode.
First we need to go to vidly and
open up the settings module.
Now
let's go to the bottom.
Here we have a variable STATIC
URL.
Next to that I'm going to define another variable STATIC
underlying ROOT.
Now we could put this variable anywhere
in this module.
It doesn't have to be right after STATIC_URL.
But to keep our code clean and well organized,
I decided to put that
here.
Now we should set this variable to the path to
a folder that contains our static files.
Now
currently we don't have that folder here.
So let's
add that to the root of our project.
So here a
new folder static.
Now we
want to get the complete path to
this folder and put it here.
We
don't wanna hard code that like C drive backslash whatever.
Because
this can change on different
machines where we deploy our application.
So earlier we set the path to the templates folder.
Let's scroll up.
So here
it is.
Look at this templates variable.
Here we
set the path to the
templates folder using this expression.
So
using the joint method
of the path class in os
module.
We're joining the base directory
which is the path to
this project, with the templates folder.
So I want to
copy this and then back
here.
Paste it here and
then change templates to static.
All right.
Now let's save the changes.
Open up the terminal window.
Run python manage.py collectstatic.
This comment will look
at all the installed apps.
It will get all their static files and
copy them into
our static folder.
Let me show you.
So let's go ahead.
As
you can see 119 static files were copied
to our static folder.
Let's have a quick Look here.
So
here's our static folder.
Let me close that
and zoom in.
So here we
have this admin folder
and inside this folder we have all
the static files for the admin app.
So as you can see we
have quite a few number of CSS files as
well as fonts, images and JavaScript files.
Now in
our movies app we could also have
a bunch of CSS files, images, JavaScript
files and
then when we run collectstatic they will all end
up inside the static folder. Okay?
Now
to serve this static files in heroku,
we should also install a
package called White Noise.
This step is specific to
Haruko,
so if you want to use a different cloud platform,
you may not necessarily have
to do this.
So one more time open
up the terminal and
run pipenv install whitenoise.
Now
here on pypi.org
let's search for white
noise.
Here's the package.
So this package is
used for serving static files.
Let's go here and
find their documentation.
Now
let's go to using white noise with Django.
On
this page you can see the steps that
you need to follow to use this package.
So first it's telling us
to set the STATIC_ROOT variable which
we already did.
Now this documentation is suggesting to use
the folder staticfiles.
We call it static.
It doesn't
really matter.
Now the second step is to enable white
noise by adding it in
the list of middleware.
So
in our settings file we have
this variable middleware which is set to
a list of middleware objects.
These middleware objects are used as
part of processing the http requests that
we receive
in our web server.
So here we need to install this middleware: white
noise dot middleware dot white noise middleware.
With
this middleware,
we'll be able to serve static files.
So when
there is a request for a
static file like a CSS file or
an image,
this middleware will kick in and
do all the hard work.
So basically we need to copy this line and
put it right below security middleware.
So
back to the settings module.
Here's our middleware variable. The
first middleware is for security.
Right after that. we
need to add the white noise middleware.
So
copy,
also add a comma at the end.
Save the changes. Done.
So with these changes,
we have prepared our application for deployment.
In the next lecture, I will show you
how to deploy this application to heroku.