So to declare application to heroku, we need
to add it to a git repository.
A git repository is basically a
database that contains our source code
and all its versions.
So every time we change our code, we
commit it to this repository.
Now this repository is
local on our machine.
So as part of
the deployment process, we need to
set up another git repository in
heroku that mirrors our local repository.
When
we are ready to deploy, we push
the changes from our local repository to
the repository in heroku.
Now heroku has a process that
sits in the background
It's constantly watching this git repository.
Whenever
it detects changes in this repository,
it will check out the latest
source code from this repository and
copy it to the right folders.
That
is a big picture.
Now let's see this process in action.
So
the first step is to add
our code to a git repository.
So here
on the terminal run git init.
With
this we're initializing a git repository in the current folder.
Now
here you see this message
re initialized existing git repository, because
I already created a git repository
early on when I created this project.
So this is a command that
you run only once the very first time
you want to initialize a git repository.
Now every
time you make changese to your code,
you run git add period.
This adds all the modified
and new files in the current directory
and all its subdirectories to
the staging area and prepares them
to be included in the next commit.
So let's
go ahead.
Now all these files are in the staging area
and they will be included in the next commit.
So now
to commit, we run git commit -m
for adding a message to this commit,
we're going to say initial
commit.
Next time we change our code,
we make small changes
and do a commit to git.
In that comment we should give a proper label
to that commit, so we know
what changes we made.
Did we
fix a bug?
Did we add a new feature?
What did we do?
With this
we can build a history of changes to our code
which is very valuable.
So now we committed all these files in git.
So
our local git repository is now updated.
Beautiful.
Now
we're done with all the git work.
Next we need to create a heroku app
using heroku cli.
So first we need to
login.
So run heroku loggin.
Type
your email, programwithmosh@gmail.com.
Obviously you're going to use your own not mine.
Then
enter your password. Okay. You
can see I'm logged in as programwithmosh@gmail.com.
So
next we run heroku create
to create a new heroku app.
So
heroku created an app and
it give it a random unique name.
In this case my app is limitless-crag-
337 Whatever.
On your machine is going to be different.
We can also give a name while creating heroku app.
For example
heroku create vidly,
but that name has to be unique.
And
here you can see the address of your app in the cloud.
So
currently if you head over to this address,
we see this
default page because we haven't
deployed our application yet.
Now
when we run heroku create,
three things happen:
First heroku
creates this app at this address.
Second it creates a
git repository at this address,
so it's git.heroku dot
com slash the name of
our application dot git.
And
third it tells our current local git repository in
this folder about this new remote git
repository.
So now to deploy our application, all
we have to do is to run git push heroku
master.
This will push the changes in our local repository in
the master branch to the heroku repository.
Now
let's see what happens.
So
all our code is now pushed into heroku.
heroku detected a
python app.
It's installing Python version 3.7.1.
Then it detected the dependencies of
our application from our Pipfile.
In this case we have a dependency to
django, whitenoise and a
bunch of other packages. So
heroku is automatically downloading and
installing them from pypi.
Next
it's installing our SQLite database.
Now as
I told you before SQLite is
a very simple and lightweight database.
We
shouldn't really use it in a cloud
environment because it doesn't have security and
it cannot serve multiple users.
But for the purpose of this tutorial. it
gets the job done.
In a real application you should use an enterprise database
engine like mySQL, Postgres, Microsoft sequel
server and so on.
But that's a topic for a different video.
So
now you can see our application
is deployed to heroku and
here is the address of our application.
Now for some reason
that I don't know
this address magically changed while I
recording this video.
Let's not worry about that and go ahead.
Next we need
to tell heroku to allocate one
Web server to this application.
So
we run heroku ps:scale web=1
we're allocating one Web server
through this application.
In the
future if you have apopular application
with thousands or hundreds
of thousands of users,
you can simply come back and allocate
more Web servers by increasing this number.
Okay.
we're done.
Now finally we can open our application
by running heroku open.
This
simply opens a Web
browser pointing to our application.
Now
by default you're going to
get this error DisallowedHost.
This
is to prevent a common security attack called http Host
header attacks.
The explanation of that
goes beyond the scope of this tutorial.
You can read about it on your own.
But to fix this problem, we
need to come back here.
Open up our settings file and
search for allowed hosts.
Here
in this list we need to add
the address of our website.
That
is this address here.
So this web page is telling us
you may need to add 'mighty-oasis ...
whatever that is, on
your machine is going to be different.
So let's copy the string and
add it here.
So note that this is a string. Okay.
Save the changes.
Now as I told you before every time you change your
code, you need to commit your
code to your local repository and when
you're ready to deploy, you need
to push it to heroku.
So
back in the terminal.
To commit our code to our local repository,
type git add period.
git commit. give
it a proper descriptive
label like "Add Heroku app
to allowed hosts."
Now
our local repository is updated.
Before we get ready to deploy, you
might have to make several changes.
Different developers in our team might
make tens or hundreds of commit.
Now when we
are ready to commit, we simply
run git push heroku master.
Alright.
heroku went through all these steps one more time.
Now let's
get back here and
refresh this page.
There you
go.
This is our vidly application in heroku.
Let's go to
the list of movies.
So our SQLite databases also deployed.
In my local database I had two movies,
that's why they also
exist in the production environment.
But these two databases are different
So here in our production environment
we can head over to admin and
log in with the same credentials and
then go to the list of movies
and add a new movie here.
We
also have a fully working restful API
that we can
access at slash api slash
movies.
So here are the movies in our database represented
as JSON.
And that concludes our Django tutorial.
I hope you learned a lot and thank you for watching.