In Django a project can contain multiple apps.
These
apps don't represent an entire application.
They represent a
small part of an application that
is focused on one functional area.
For example let's say we're going
to build a website like Amazon. Amazon
has a lot of different functional areas,
such as customer service, orders,
shipping and so on.
Each functional area includes a
bunch of highly related functions.
So with this architecture we
can break down a large
complex project into smaller, more
manageable and more maintainable apps.
Also we
can reuse these apps in other Django projects.
For
example we can build an app
that represents a blog and then
reuse this app in any
websites that needs a blog. Okay.
So in this lecture we're going
to create a new app called Movies. In
this small app we're going to
have all the functionality for displaying the
list of the movies as well as
the details for a given movie. So
let's open up a terminal window.
First we need to stop our
development server so control c. Now
here. let's run python. Manage that
pie. Start up and we're going
to call that app movies.
All right. let's go
ahead.
So this created a
new directory here, movies.
Don't worry about the issues here.
The reason you see this is because
I added this project under source control.
You're
not going to see this on your machine
and don't worry about it.
So what do
we have in this directory?
We have a directory called Migrations. We're
going to look at that shortly.
Below that we have our __init__ file
and again this tells Python that this is a package.
So potentially
in the future we can distribute
this package on pypi.org,
so other developers can download
this package and added to their
applications.
Below that we have admin and this
is where we define how
the administration area for managing the
movies will look like.
Next We have apps.py.
Now
the name of this file is
a little bit confusing because here we are
within the boundary of one app.
So why do we have a
file called apps.py.
But basically we use this to
store various configuration settings for this app. A
better name would be config.py.
So I'm not sure why
Django developers name this file apps.py.
But
that aside, after that we have models.
And here we
define classes that represent the domain of this app.
For
example in the domain of movies.
we could have classes like movie, genre
and so on.
Below that we have tests.py
and this is where we
write automated tests for this app. And
finally we have views.py
and this is where we define our
view functions.
What is the view function?
Well here's
an example.
Let's say we head over to our website slash
movies.
when we send a request to this end point, Django
is going to take this request,
pass it to a function which we call
a view function.
That view function takes our requests and
returns our response.
That response could be simple
plain text like what you see here,
it could also be an HTML, JSON
XML, image and so on.
So a view function or
view in short is a function
that takes a request and returns
a response.
Now if you're familiar with MVC Architectural pattern,
here in Django we have a
variation of this pattern called MTV
or Model View Template.
The views in Django are
like controllers in MVC.
If you're not familiar with this concept don't
worry.
Let's move on.
So views.py is the module
where we define our view functions,
and that's what I'm gonna show you next.