All right.
Now let's create our first view or view function.
So here
in the movies app, let's
open up views.py and
define a function called index. Now
this name is arbitrary,
we could call it anything, but usually we
use the word index for
naming the function that represents the
main page of an app.
For example here in our
movies app when we send a
request to this address to this
end point, our index function
is going to get called. So
Index represents the main page of an app.
Now
all our view functions should
take a parameter called request.
Again the name is arbitrary
but the object that is passed to
this function is an http request object. We
are not going to call this function.
Django will take care of doing this.
So when
we send an http request on an endpoint,
Django will figure out
based on some configuration
what view function should be called.
You're
going to see that in a minute.
Now in every view function, we
should return an http response.
So on
the top first let's import
the http response class from
django.http module so
import HttpRequest. Okay.
Now in this function
we're gonna return an HttpRequest
object.
Here I'm going to pass some plain text
like Hello World and
save the changes. Okay.
This is our first view.
Now we need to map this to URL.
So back in the movies app, let's
add a new file,
by convention the
name of this file should be urls.py.
So
make sure to spell it properly. In
this file we're going to create
a variable called urlpatterns
that we should set to a list.
Okay. This is one of the conventions that
Django expects us to follow.
In this list we add objects
that map url end points
to our view functions.
And
for that we use the
path function in django. So on
the top from Django
that you or else let's
import the past function. So
we call the path function
here to create a path object.
As the first argument we should
specify a url end point.
Here I'm going to use an empty string.
And this will represent the
root of this app.
For exampl in our movies app,
we're going to have url end points like this:
movies/
that's the root url.
We're gonna have movies/1
/detail
here I'm assuming one is the id of a
given movie.
So here an empty string represents the
root of this app.
Now don't worry about the movies prefix.
We're
going to add that in the next step.
From the perspective of this app
we don't care what the prefix is,
because we should design these
apps for reusability,
so maybe another developer wants to
download our app from pypi.org
and put it under a
url like
movies_collection this app shouldn't care
where it's hosted.
So here we use related urls
else. Okay?
Now let's delete these.
So
this is the root of this app.
Now we need to map this to a
view function.
So we need to import the index function that
we created earlier.
That is in our views module.
So look.
The views module is here.
So you might think we
can import the views module like this. Now
while this is possible in pure python world,
this will
not work in Django because
of how Django loads these modules.
Also there is a problem with
importing the views module like this because
it is possible that the
application that hosts this APP is
dependent on a module called views,
so with this
statement we'll end up importing
the views module that is
in the path,
that is different from the views module we have inside
of this directory.
So here we should use a related imports
statement.
So from period
to represent the current directory import the
views module.
That is better.
Now back
to the path function as the
second argument we need to pass a
reference to the view function that is views dot
index.
Note that I'm not calling this function, I'm
simply passing a reference to it.
At run time, when
the user sends an http request
to this end point, Django will
take care of calling this function
and give it an http request
object. Okay?
Now also as a
best practice we should name this url end points.
So here
we pass a keyword argument name we set it to
index.
So save the changes.
We
define this variable urlpatterns that contains one
or more path objects that
map url end points to
view functions.
We refer to this as a URL configuration.
So every app should have a URL configuration.
So
we're done with configuring urls  for this app,
But our main app, the
vidly app has no knowledge
of the movies app. So
if you head over to
local host for 8,000 slash movies, nothing
is going to happen.
Our Django application is not aware of that. So
we have to go to the
main app that is vidly, see
once again here we have urls.py that defines the
you're configuration for our main app.
So see here
we have urlpatterns.
By convention django looks
for this variable when starting our Django Project.
So make sure to
spell this variable exactly as you see here.
Now here
in this module we have
a path that maps anything
that starts with admin to
admit.site.urls
So every django project
comes with an administrative panel
that is a separate, independent
app on its own.
We're gonna look at that in the future.
So here
in this list we need to add a new path object.
We're going
to tell our vidly app that any path that
starts with movies should be handed off to
the url configuration in the movies App. So
here on line 17 from django.urls we
should import another functional
that is called include. And
here we call that function and
pass a string that specifies
the name of the module that
contains the url configuration
for the movies app, that
is movies.url
So
look.
we have this movies directory,
inside of this directory we
have urls.py.
That is why here
we need to pass a string movies.url,
But we
don't add dot py because
Django will automatically append the
extension and load this module.
So with
this line whenever we send
a request that starts with movies,
django would chop off the prefix,
that is what we
have here, and send the remaining string to
this module, movies.url.
That is the
reason in the url configuration for
the movies app, we use
an empty string to represent the
root of this app. Okay.
So back
to urls.py.
Let's save the changes and restart
our Web server. So here
on the terminal. let's run Python
three. Manage that pie run server
. We got this error: no
module named movies that you are. Actually
. I made a mistake.
I should have passed movies that
you are else. We have
an s at the end. So
once again. let's run
our Web server. Beautiful. Now
if you head over to the home page of our website,
you're going to see
a "page not found" error.
Don't worry about that.
We're going to fix that shortly. But
if you head over to slash movies,
you're going to see the Hello
World message and
this verifies that was successfully mapped
a url end point to a view function