The next step is to create the
models for this movies app. These
models are Python classes that
we use to represent our application
data.
So here in our movies app,
we're going to have models like
genre and movie.
Let's go ahead and create them. So
here in the movies directory,
let's open up models.py.
Here I'm going to
create a class called Genre
and we should derive
this class from models dot
model.
What is going on here?
So in Django
we have this package, jango.db, this
package encapsulates all the functionality around working with
databases.
Now in this package,
we have a module called
models and
in this module we have a class called Model. This
class encapsulates a lot
of functionality for storing a
model object in a database
or retrieving model objects, filter
them and so on.
You're going to learn about them soon.
So by
inheriting our genre class from the
base model class in Django, our
genre class will also
inherit all that functionality; which
means we don't really have to
write any code to store genre
objects in a database.
Django will automatically take care
of that.
So think of the concept of genre.
What attributes should a genre have?
Well in a basic implementation
all we need to know about the
genre is its label or name. Is
this an action movie or comedy or what.
So here I'm
going to define a class attribute
called name and
we set it to an instance
of a field class in Django. So
in the models module, we have
a bunch of field classes. For
example we have CharField
to represent a database field
that can contain textual data.
We also have Integer
Field.
We have FloatFilled BooleanField
and so on.
So here I'm going to set this to an
instance of the CharField class and
here we should pass a keyword argument max_length.
Let's
set this to 255 characters.
With this we can ensure
that no genre can have
a name longer than 255 characters,
and this is one way to
prevent security attacks in our application.
So
a hacker cannot attempt to create
a genre with a name that
is two billion characters long.
So we enforce a limit here.
So
Here's our genre class now.
Similarly we need to create a
movie class.
So once again class movie.
We
derive this from models.Model.
Now
What attributes of a movie do we need to know?
Well in our
imaginary video rental application,
we need to know the title
for each movie,
the year it was published,
the number of these movie
DVDs we have in the store
or in the stock, as well as
the daily rental rate.
So let's go ahead and create these attributes.
We
set the title two models the Char Field
. Once again. we have
to set max length for consistency
. I'm going to set
this to to 55 next
week. Another attribute release year. We're
going to set that the
models that energy are filled. Now
let's create number in stock again
. We said this two
models not in anger filled and
finally daily. Great. Let's
say that two models that float field so
we can store values like $2.95.
Now
each movie needs to be
associated with the genre.
How
do we do that?
Well here we should
add another attribute genre and we
set it to an instance of
models dot ForeignKey.
Now
with this we can create
a relationship between movies and genres.
So as the first argument,
we need to pass the genre class because
we want to add a relationship
between the movie and the genre classes.
Right?
Now as the second argument, we need to pass a
keyword argument that is on_delete and
with this we tell Django
what should happen when a
genre is deleted.
For example if you have a genre called
comedy and we have five
movies in this genre, what should
happen if you accidentally or deliberately delete the
comedy genre?
In this tutorial let's assume that if the genre
is deleted, all the movies associated
with it should also be deleted.
This
is what we call cascading.
So here we set on_delete
to models.CASACADE.
So
let me zoom out so you
can see the complete code.
So
after this point these are the
two model classes that we need in
the movies app.
In the future we can come back and add additional classes or
modify the existing ones.
The next step is to tell Django to
synchronize our database with the models
we have defined in the movies app;
And that's the topic for the next lecture.