So we have created our model classes.
Now we should be able to store
our model objects in a database.
How?
That's pretty
easy.
Look at this file here, db dot SQL light three.
This is a blank SQL database that
Django admin automatically created for US.
SQL light is
a very simple, lightweight database
that we often use in
small applications like applications that
we run on mobile devices.
But it's not suitable
for an Enterprise Web application
that is supposed to serve
thousands or even millions of
users.
So it doesn't have features
like security and concurrency.
In those situations we use
databases like mySQL, sequel
server by Microsoft, article, postgres and so on.
The good thing is that
django supports all these database engines. For
now we're going to go with
this simple SQL light database and later
in the future I'll show you how
to replace this with a mySQL database.
Now what I want you to do
is to open up a browser and search
for db browser for sqlite.
This is a simple application
that we use to open a sqlite database.
So
let me quickly show you.
Here it is.
So here you can create
a new database or
open an existing one.
I'm
gonna open the sqlite database in our project.
So let's
drag and drop it here.
There you go.
So currently we have
no tables here and that means
we have to create a couple of
tables in order to
store movies and genres in
this database.
Having said that, when using Django we
don't have to manually design these tables.
We can have Django automatically
create them for us based on our models.
So every
time we create new model classes or
modify existing ones,
we tell Django to
compare our model classes with
our database.
Django will look at our database,
it will figure out what
tables and columns we have.
Then it will calculate the difference between
our model classes and our database tables.
And based
on that, it will create a migration.
A migration is
essentially a python file that includes some code.
When we
run that, it will synchronize
our database with our model classes.
Let me show you.
So let's open up a terminal window and
run python manage.py  makemigrations.
Now it tells us that no
changes are detected because by default django
is not aware of our model classes.
So the first step is
to register our movies
App with Django. Let me
show you how to do that.
So here in our project inside
the vidly package, open settings.py.
As
I told you before, this file contains
various configuration settings for our
application.
One of the settings is installed apps
and these are the apps
that are installed by default.
So the
first one is admin.
and this creates an administration panel for
us.
You're going to see that soon.
We have auth which is
an authentication framework, with this we'll
be able to authenticate users and
see if they have permission
to perform various tasks.
We
have content types which is
a framework for creating generic relationships
between model classes.
We'll look at this in the future.
Below
that we have the sessions app
which is a framework that allows us
to temporarily store data
about the current user.
Next
we have the messaging framework
and we use that in situations where,
let's say the user creates a new movie
then we redirect them
and display a message like
"the movie was successfully created".
And
finally we have staticfiles
which is used for managing static
files like CSS files, images and so on.
Now
in most applications we need
pretty much all these install apps.
But
if you don't need any of these apps in your application,
you can simply come back
here and delete that app.
Now in this demo we need to register
our movies app here, So Django
can keep track of our model
classes in that app.
So back to our movies folder.
Here we have this file apps.py.
Earlier
I told you that here we
can have various configuration settings for
the movies app.
So look at the name of this class: MoviesConfig.
This class is in the apps module of
the movies package.
So to register the movies app with
django, we need to provide the
complete path to this class.
So
back to settings.py.
Here we add movies
that's our package,
then we go to the apps module and
finally MoviesConfig
Save the changes.
Now
back in the terminal.
Let's run the makemigrations command one
more time. Okay.
This time django detected
that there are some changes in
the movies app, so it created a
migration that is inside movies slash migrations
slash this file.
Let's have a quick look at this migration.
So here we have a class called Migration
and in this class
we have a couple
of operations for bringing our
database up to date with
our current model classes. So
here's the first operation for creating a model.
You can see
the name is set to genre
and here are the fields of the
genre.
So we have id and name.
Now in our code we
only specified the name field,
we didn't add the id field.
Django
automatically takes care of that.
So it ensures that every object has
an id property that uniquely identifies that object.
Similarly
we have another create model operation for
creating the movie table,
and in this table we're going to have these
fields: id which is added automatically,
plus all these
fields that we defined in our code.
Now
this migration is not executed yet.
It simply describes the
operations that need to be performed
on the database to bring it
up to date with our current model classes.
So
the next step is to run this migration.
Now
let me show you something.
Let's run python manage dot
py runserver.
Earlier
you saw this error:
You have 16 unapplied migrations.
That basically means we have
migrations that need to be executed. Earlier
we had 15 migrations.
Now after adding these two classes we
have a new migration, so we
have a total of 16
unapplied migrations.
So let's stop the
server with control and c
and run python manage
dot py migrate.
This will
run all depending migrations on our database.
Let's
go ahead. Beautiful.
You can see all these migrations are
applied.
So as you can see, each of these migrations is
prefixed with the name of the
app that contains it.
So here
we have a migration for our contenttypes app.
Here's another
migration for our auth app.
Below that we have three migrations
for our admin app.
So each app can have its own models and
migrations.
Now after all these migrations, you can
see the migration in our movies app.
Now
if you open our sqlite database one more time,
you can see we
have a total of 13 tables.
Each of these tables is
prefixed with the name of the app that contains it.
So here are
the two tables for our movies app.
We have movies underline genre
and movies underline movie.
So the table names are
in singular.
Of course it's done by convention.
and we can always
override that in the future if you want to.
Now let's expand
the movie table.
So we can see we have these columns:
id, title, release_year and so on.
So we didn't have
to manually create any of these tables.
Django automatically created this
for us.
Also we have this table django underlined
migrations,
Django uses this table to keep track of
the migrations that are applied on the database.
So let's
go to browse data tab
and from the list of tables
select jangle migrations.
You can see these are the migrations
that are currently applied on our database.
If you scroll down,
you can see here we have migration for our movies app.
and this
is the name of the migration.
And here's a daytime that
this migration was applied.