Let's go through this workflow one more time.
So here in our movies app, let's
open up models that pipe.
Here's our movie class.
I'm going to add a
new attribute called Date Created So
date underline created.
We said this to models that
daytime field. and here we can optionally supply
at default value.
Now here we can import the
daytime class from Python Standard Library and write
some code like this daytime.now. But
the problem with this approach is
that this daytime object is not aware
of Time zone.
A better approach is to use the time zone object
in Django because that object is
aware of the time zone. And later
in the future. when we display
this daytime value to the user. that
object will automatically take care
of translating that daytime to
the user's time zone.
So I still eat this on
the top from django dot you
tilt. Let's import the time zone class
now down upon him.
we said the default argument
two time zone dot Now note
that here I'm not calling this method.
I'm simply passing a reference
to the now method. If I
call this method when I create a migration. the current data
would be hard coded in our migration.
Let me show you what happens.
So here
I'm going to call this method.
Save the changes.
Now we
need to create a migration.
So here on the terminal. let's
run python. Manage that pie. Make
migrations.
We got a
warning:
"It seems you set a fixed datetime value
as a default for this field."
What does this mean?
Well
we'll have to look at
this migration Migration number two and
it's called Movie Date created. So let's
go to our project here
in the Migrations folder. Let's
have a look at this migration. So
in the list of operations.
we have this operation for adding a
field to an existing table.
Here's the name of our model
or table. and this is
the name of the new field
. and you can see it's
type is set to datetime field
So far so good.
But look at the default value. It's
hard coded here. and that is
the current daytime on my machine
. We don't want this to happen.
We want this value to be calculated at
one time when we insert a
new record in this table. So
to fix that. we need
to come back to our
movie class. And instead of
calling the now method. we
simply pass a reference to it. Save the
changes. Now we need to
create a new migration. So
let's open up the terminal
and run python. Manage the
pie. Make migrations one more time. All
right.
Now we have migration number three. Let's
take a quick look at this migration.
There you go. So
here we have an operation of type alter
filled. So this operation
is going to go to
the movie table.
an alter a field called Date created
. and this is how it's going
to alter this field. So it's going
to set the default to django
that you tells the Time zone
that now.
So note that the current daytime is
not hard coded in our migration.
Okay?
So
let's go ahead and apply these
to migrations to our database. and by
the way. make sure to never
delete any of these migrations. Otherwise
. you're going to run into all sorts
of issues because the purpose of each migration
is to take the database
one step forward. When you
delete one of these migrations.
there would be a missing step. So
do not ever.
ever. ever. ever. ever delete a
migration here.
So back in the terminal.
Let's run
Python managed that pie migrate. Okay
. the 2nd and 3rd
migrations are applied. Beautiful. Now
. here in our database.
you can see our movie table as
this new field date created. Beautiful.
Now
one more thing before I finish this lecture.
As you have seen
each migration is essentially
a python class that determines
how our database should be updated.
Now
when we run the migrate command,
Django is going to look at
these migrations that are not applied
and based on the operations that
they define, It's going to
generate some sequel statements to
send to the database.
If you're curious what sequel statements are
sent to the database, you can
use the sequel migrate command.
Let
me show you.
So let's say we want to know
what sequel statements are
generated as a result
of applying these third migration.
So here on the terminal,
we run python manage
dot py.
Instead of migrate, we're going
to pass sequel migrate,
and then we specify our
app, in this case the movies app.
So we're going this
app and pick a specific migration.
So here
in the movies app,
inside the migrations folder, we
have three migrations and
they are prefixed with a number that
uniquely identifies each migration.
So I'm going to pick the
first migration.
So back to the terminal.
Let's
add triple 0, 1.
All
right.
This is the exact sequel statement
that is sent to the database.
So
for creating the movie's table,
we have this create table
statement.
Here is the name of the table.
Next to that you can see
all the columns, their types and so on.