All right.
Our database is in a good shape.
Now the next step is to allow
the staff at our imaginary video rental store to
populate the list of movies.
So we need to create an administration
panel for them.
However when using Django,
we don't have to do
this manually.
So all Django applications come with a powerful administration
interface.
Let me show you.
So first let's open up
the terminal and run our development server.
So
python. manage that pie run server.
Okay.
Now back to the browser.
Let's
head over to slash admin.
Look.
This
is the entrance to our administration panel.
So by default we
get this log in screen.
This is coming from the auth app that is installed by
default.
Earlier we talked about this settings dot
py.
You saw the list of installed applications.
The
second app here is the auth app.
So this is the app that
knows all about authenticating users.
And this logging screen
is implemented inside of that app.
So as you can see
that app is a small, reusable
package that we
are using in this project.
By the same token, we can create small,
reusable apps that other people
can use in their projects.
Now
back to our login screen.
Currently we don't have any users in our database
So the next step is to create a super user.
Back
in the VSCode.
I'm going to open a new terminal window,
so we don't have
to stop our server and restart it.
So let's click
this.
Now Let's run python manage dot
py createsuperuser.
Let's
enter a user name,
I'm gonna use admin.
with this
email address and
finally a password.
Now
if we use a weak
password like 1234 and one more time,
this is going to complain, telling us
the password is too short or too common whatever.
So here we can bypass the validation and go ahead or
create a stronger password.
What is demo, I'm going to go with
1234.
So yes.
Okay.
Super user created successfully. Beautiful.
Now back
to our log in screen.
Let's log in with admin and 1234.
Okay.
So here's our administration panel.
We
can manage the list of groups and users.
So we can put users
in different groups like admins, moderators, guests and
so on.
So let's go to the list of users.
Here
we get this beautiful table that
shows all the users in our
database.
We can sort this list by various columns.
We
can filter them.
We can search for users and so on.
Now
back to the main page.
Currently we can only manage the
users and groups.
We cannot manage our custom models like genres
and movies.
But we can easily bring them here
with only a single line
of code.
Let me show you.
Back in our movies app.
Here
we have this admin file and this
is where we register the models that
we want to manage using our administrative interface.
So
let's open this file. Alright.
Here we
need to import our genre and movie classes.
So from
the models module in the current folder.
Remember this
period indicates the current folder, we
need to import the genre and movie classes.
Now Finally we're gonna
say admin that site that
register genre and
let's duplicate this line and register the movie
class.
So with these two lines we're telling Django to
register these models in the administration interface.
So
let's save the changes.
Back in the admin.
Let's refresh
the page.
Now we have these two models in our
movies app.
So let's go to the list of genres.
In
this list we have one genre
that is genre object one.
What is that?
Well before recording this video,
I created a
genre record in the database.
So here
you can see that in our genre table
currently we have one record with
id 1 and name Action.
I created this just
before recording this video.
So this 1 that you see
here is the id of a genre record.
Now this table
is not very user friendly.
It would be better if you had two columns,
id and name, and we could see
the name of each genre right here.
So in the next lecture I'm going to show you
how to customize this administration interface.