So the reason our genre is
displayed as genre object one
is that this is the default
representation of a genre object as
a string.
So one way to fix this problem is to override the
stair magic method in the genre class.
Let me show you. So
back in VSCode.
In our movies app.
Let's open up
models dot py.
So here's our genre class.
In
this class we can override the
str magic method to specify the
string representation of a genre object.
So
let's define a method called str.
These
two underscores represent a magic method. So
as the first parameter we need to add self.
Now here was simply
return self dot name. So
we want to use the name of a
genre to represent it as a string.
Save
the changes.
Back in admin.
Refresh the page.
Now
you see the actual name of the genre. Beautiful.
let's take this to the next level.
Let's say we want to add another column here
to see the id of the genre.
For that we need to go to our
movies app and open up
the admin dot py module.
Earlier
we registered the genre class with admin.
Now
to customize how we work
with genres in our admin panel, we
need to create another
class called genre admin.
Now
to customize the list of genres in admin,
we need to create another
class here called genre admin.
Let me show you.
So
define a class called genre admin.
The name
doesn't matter,
but by convention we use
the name of our model plus
admin.
Now we should derive this class from admin
dot model admin class.
So
on the top,
look,
We're importing this admin module in
this module we have this class ModelAdmin
which is the representation of
a model in the admin interface.
Now by deriving this
class from model admin, we're going
to inherit all those features and
then we can override some of them.
For example here we
can set list underline display attribute to
the list of fields that
we want to show here in
this table.
So back here.
We set this to a tuple
and in this tuple we specify all
the fields that we want to display.
So
we want to display the
idea field followed by the
name field.
Save the changes.
Now when registering this
genre we should also
pass this genre admin model.
Save the changes one more time.
Back on admin.
Let's refresh
this page.
There we go.
We have two columns: id, name.
Beautiful.
So let's go ahead and add a new genre
here.
Here's our genre form.
Currently we only have one
field name.
id is not here because its value is automatically
generated by our database.
This way we can ensure that every
genre has a unique identifier.
So let's
create a new genre, comedy.
Now let's save this. Okay.
So here's our second genre. Beautiful.
Now here on
this side map, let's go to our movies app.
In this app we
have the list of genres and movies.
Let's look at the
list of movies.
Currently we have no movies here.
So let's add a new
movie.
I'm going to call this Terminator,
release
year I guess 198 I don't know five,
Let's
say we have five DVDs of this movie in the stock,
and the
daily rental rate is 1.95 and
below that we have this
drop down list to select a
genre.
So I'm gonna set this to Action.
See we
get all this for free.
We didn't have to manually create this form.
Django
automatically created it for us
and that's the beauty of using Django.
Also
below that we have a Date created.
So here we have the date component
followed by the time component.
Here we have a calendar.
We can select
the date from.
Its really powerful.
That's one of
the reasons I love Django.
Now Earlier when we
added this date created field,
we set a default value for
it based on the current datetime
and you can see that populated here.
Now let's say we don't want to
have this field on this form.
We can easily
hide it.
Let me show you how.
So Back to
our admin module.
That's similar to genre admin.
We're going to
create a model admin for our movie.
So let's
create another class movie admin
and we derive this from admin dot model admin.
Here
we have a couple of attributes that we can override.
We can use fields to
specify the fields that we want to show on our form.
So we set
this to tuple.
Let's say we want to display the title and
genre fields.
Or we can use the exclude attribute
to specify the fields that we wanna exclude.
Once again we
set this to tuple.
In this case I want to exclude date
underline created.
Now because this tuple has only
one item, we need to
add a comma here otherwise Python
thinks this is a string that
we have wrapped in parenthesis.
So
here's our movie admin model.
Now we need to pass it while registering
the movie class.
So MovieAdmin.
Save the
changes.
Back to the admin.
You can see the date
created field is no longer here.
So there are various ways to
customize the admin interface.
Now let's go ahead and create our
first movie.
So one more time.
Terminator,
10,
1.95 and
by the way look at the
type of these fields.
So here we have a numeric field because
we set the type of this field to a float.
Now finally
let's select the genre to Action and
save the movie.
Now
here on the list of movies, once again
we have the general representation of
a movie as a string.
so let's go ahead and add three columns
in this table.
Back to admin module.
In
the movie admin class.
I'm going to override the list. Display
. Attribute. Let's set this to
a topple with three values. Title
number in stock and daily
rental. Right. Save
the changes back here. Refresh.
Oops.
Our Web server crashed.
So let's go back to
VSCode and look at
the terminal to see what happened.
We
got this error:
The value of 'List_display[2] refers
to 'daily_rental_rate', which is
not a callable, an attribute
of 'MovieAdmin'.
So it looks like I made a mistake here.
The name of this field is actually daily rate. so delayed
. Save the changes and let's
try it one more time. All
right.
So we've successfully customized the movies table.
So we're done with the admin panel.
The next step is to
display the list of our movies
in the public area of our website.