Any section you're going to learn about machine learning
which is a subset of AI
or Artificial Intelligence, it's one
of the trending topics in
the world these days and
it's going to have a lot of applications in the future.
Here's an example:
Imagine I ask you to write a program to scan
an image until if it's a cat or a dog.
If
you want to build this program using
traditional programming techniques, your program
is going to get overly complex.
You will have to come up with lots
of rules to look for a specific curves, edges and colors
in an image to tell if it's a cat or a dog.
But if I
give you a black and white photo,
your rules may not work, they may break.
Then
you'll have to rewrite them.
Or I may give you a picture of a cat or
a dog from a different angle
that you did not predict before.
So solving
this problem using traditional programming
technique is going to get overly
complex or sometimes impossible.
Now to make the
matter worse, what if in the future
ask you to extend this program such
that it supports three kinds of animals:
cats, dogs,
and horses.
Once again you'll have to rewrite all those rules.
That's
not going to work.
So machine learning is a technique to solve these
kind of problems.
And this is how it works:
We build a model
or an engine and give it
lots and lots of data.
For
example we give it thousands or
tens of thousands of pictures of
cats and dogs.
Our model will then find and learn
patterns in the input data,
so we can give it a new picture
of a cat that it hasn't seen before and
ask it, is it a cat or
a dog or a horse?
And it will tell us with a certain level of accuracy.
The more input data we give it,
the more accurate our model is
going to be.
So that was a very basic example.
But
machine Learning has other applications in
self driving cars, robotics,
language processing, vision processing,
forecasting things
like stock market, trends and
the weather, games and so on.
So that's the basic idea about machine learning.
Next we'll look at machine learning in action.