So this is a very basic implementation of building and training
a model to make predictions.
Now to simplify things
I have removed all the code that
we wrote in the last lecture for calculating the
accuracy because in this lecture we're going
to focus on a different topic.
So
basically we import our data set,
create a
model, train it and
then ask it to
make predictions.
Now this piece of code that you see here
is not what we want to run
every time we have a new user or
every time we want to make
recommendations to an existing user because training
a model can sometimes be really time consuming.
In this example
we're dealing with a very small
data set that has only 20 records, but
in real applications we might have
a data set with thousands or
millions of samples.
Training a model for that might take seconds,
minutes or even hours.
So that is why model persistence
is important.
Once in a while we build and train our
model and then we'll save it to a file.
Now next time
we want to make predictions,
we simply load the model from the file and
ask it to make predictions.
That model is already trained.
We
don't need to retrain it.
It's like an intelligent person.
So
let me show you how to do this.
It's very very easy.
On
the top from sklearned dot
externals module,
we import joblib.
This joblib object has methods for saving
and loading models.
So after we
train our model,
we simply call joblib
dot dump and
give it two arguments:
our
model and
the name of the file in which we want to store this
model.
Let's call that music-recommender
dot joblib.
That's
all we have to do.
Now temporarily I'm going to comment out this
line.
We don't want to make any predictions.
We just want to store our trained
model in a file.
So let's run this cell with
control and slash.
Okay. Look.
In the output we have an array
that contains the name of our model file.
So
this is the return value of the dump method.
Now
back to our desktop.
Right next to my notebook,
you can see our joblib
file.
This is where our model store.
It's simply a binary file.
Now back to Jupiter notebook.
As I told you before in a
real application we don't want to
train a model every time.
So
let's comment out these few lines.
So I've selected this
few lines,
on Macwe can press command and slash,
on
windows Control Slash. Okay.
These lines
are commented out.
Now this time instead of dumping our model, we're
gonna load it.
So we call the load method.
We don't have the
model.
We simply pass the name of our model file.
This
returns our trained model.
Now with
these two lines we can simply make predictions.
So earlier
we assume that men between 20 and 25,
like hip hop
music.
Let's print predictions and
see
if our model is behaving correctly or not.
So control
and enter.
There you go.
So this is how we persist and load models.