Earlier in this section I told you that
decision trees are the easiest to
understand and
that's why we started machine learning with decision trees.
In this section we're going to export
our model in a visual format.
So
you will see how this model makes predictions.
That
is really really cool.
Let me show you.
So once
again I've simplified this code.
So we simply import our
data set,
create input and output sets,
create a model and
train it.
That's
all we are doing.
Now I want you to follow along with me, type
everything exactly as I show you in this lecture.
Don't worry about what
everything means.
We're going to come back to it shortly.
So on the
top from sklearn import tree.
This object has a method
for exporting our decision tree in
a graphical format.
So after we train our model
let's call tree dot export underline
graphviz.
Here are a few arguments we need
it to pass.
The first argument is our model.
The
second is the name of the output file.
So here we're going to use keyword
arguments because this method takes so
many parameters and we want to
selectively pass keyword arguments without worrying about
their order.
So the parameter we're going
to set is out_file.
Let's set
this to music-recommender
dot dot.
This is the dot format which
is a graph description language.
You'll see that shortly.
Now
the other parameter we wanna set
is feature underline
names.
We set this to an array of two strings,
age and gender.
These are the
features or the columns of our data set.
So
they are the properties or features of our data. Okay?
The
other parameter is class names.
So class underline
names.
We should set this to the list of classes or
labels we have in our output dataset like hip hop,
jazz, classical and so on.
So this y
data set includes all the genres or all the classes of
our data but they are repeated a
few times in this data set. So
here we call y.unique.
This returns
the unique list of classes.
Now we should sort this alphabetically.
So
we call this sorted function and
pass the
result of y.unique.
The
next parameter is label.
We set
this to a String all.
Once again Don't worry
about the details of these parameters,
we're going to come back to this shortly.
So
set label to all.
Then rounded to
True.
And finally filled to True.
So
this is the end result.
Now let's run this cell using control and
enter.
Okay. Here
we have a new file music-recommender.dot.
That's a little bit funny.
So we want to open this file with
VSCode.
So drag and drop this
into a VSCode window
Okay.
Here's a dot format.
It's a textual language for
describing graphs.
Now to visualize this graph we
need to install an extension in VSCode.
So on the left side
click the extensions panel and
search for dot
d o t.
Look at the second extension here.
Graphviz or dot language by
Stephanvs.
Go ahead and install this
extension and
then reload VSCode.
Once you do that, you
can visualize this dot file.
So let me close this tab.
All right.
Look at this dot dot dot here on the right side,
click
this.
You should have a new menu "Open Preview to the Side",
so click
that.
All right here's the visualization of
our decision Tree.
Let's close the dot file.
There
you go.
This is exactly how our model makes predictions.
So
we have this binary tree
which means every node can have a
maximum of two children.
On top of each node we
have a condition.
If this condition is true, we
go to the child node on the left side,
Otherwise we go to the child
node on the right side.
So let's see what's happening here.
The
first condition is
age less than or equal to
30.5.
If this condition is false, that means
that user is 30 years or older.
So the genre of the music
that they're interested in is classical.
So here
we're classifying people based on their profile.
That
is the reason we have the world class here.
So a user who
is 30 years or older belongs
to the class of classical or
people who like classical music.
Now what if this condition is
true?
That means that user is younger than 30.
So
now we check the gender.
If it's less than 0.5 which
basically means if it equals
to zero then we're dealing with
a female.
So we go to the child node here.
Now once
again we have another condition.
So we're dealing with a female who
is younger than 30.
Once again we need to check their age.
So
is the age less than 25.5?
If
that's the case then that user likes dance music,
Otherwise
they like acoustic music.
So this is the decision tree
that our model uses to make predictions.
Now if you're wondering
why we have this floating point numbers like 25.5?
These
are basically the rules that our
model generates based on the patterns
that it finds in our data set.
As we give our model more data,
these rules will change.
So they are not always the same.
Also
the more columns or more features we have,
our decision tree
is going to get more complex.
Currently we have only two features age
and gender.
Now back to our code.
Let me quickly explain
the meaning of all these parameters.
We set filled to True,
so
each box or each node is filled with a color.
We
set rounded to True,
so they have rounded corners.
We
set label to all,
so every node has labels that
we can read.
We set class names to the unique list
of genres and
that's where displaying the class for each node right
here.
And we set feature names to age and gender,
so we can see the rules in our nodes.