A machine learning project involves a number of steps.
The first step
is to import our data which
often comes in the form of a csv
file.
You might have a database with lots of data,
we can
simply export that data and
store it in a csv file for
the purpose of our machine learning project.
So we import our
data,
next we need to clean it and
this involved tasks such
as removing duplicated data.
If you have duplicates in the data, we
don't want to feed this to our model because
otherwise our model will
learn bad patterns in the data and
it will produce the wrong result.
So
we should make sure that our input
data is in good and clean shape.
If
there are data that is irrelevant,
we should remove them.
If they are duplicated or
incomplete,
we can remove or modify them.
If our
data is text based like
the name of countries or genres
of music or cats and dogs,
we need to convert them to
numerical values.
So this step really depends on the
kind of data we are working with.
Every project is different.
Now
that we have a clean data set,
we need to split it into two segments:
one
for training our model and
the other for testing it to
make sure that our model
produces the right result.
For
example if you have 1000 pictures of cats and dogs,
we can
reserve 80% for training and
the other 20% for
testing.
The next step is to create a model and
this involves selecting an algorithm to analyze the data.
There's
so many different machine learning algorithms out there
such as decision trees,
neural networks and so on.
Each algorithm has pros and
cons in terms of
accuracy and performance.
So the
algorithm you choose depends on
the kind of problem you're trying to solve
and your input data.
Now the good news is that we don't have to explicitly
program an algorithm.
There are libraries out there that provide these
algorithms.
One of the most popular ones which we're going to look at
in this tutorial is psychic learn.
So we build a
model using an algorithm,
next we need to train our
model.
So we feed our training data.
Our
model will then look for the patterns in the data.
So next we
can ask it to make predictions.
Back to example of cats
and dogs, we can ask our model is this a cat or
a dog.
And our model will make a prediction.
Now the prediction
is not always accurate.
In fact when you start out, it's
very likely that your predictions are inaccurate.
So we need to evaluate
the predictions and
measure their accuracy.
Then
we need to get back to our model and
either select a different algorithm
that is going to produce a more accurate resolve
for the kind of problem we're
trying to solve or
fine tune the parameters of
our model.
So each algorithm has parameters that
we can modify to
optimize the accuracy.
So these are the high level steps
that you follow in a machine learning project.
Next we look at the libraries and tools for machine learning.