In this lecture we're going to look
at the popular Python libraries that we use
in machine learning projects.
The first one is numpy which provides
a multidimensional array, very very popular library.
The
second one is pandas which is
a data analysis library that
provides a concept called data frame.
A data frame is
a two dimensional data structure
similar to an Excel spreadsheet.
So
we have rows and columns.
We can select data in a row or a
column or
a range of rows and columns, again very
very popular in machine learning and data science projects.
The
third library is MattPlotLib which is
a two dimensional
plotting library for creating graphs and plots.
The
next library is Scikit-Learn which is
one of the most popular machine
learning libraries that provides
all these common algorithms like
decision trees, neural networks and so on.
Now
when working with machine learning project,
we use an environment called Jupiter for
writing our code.
Technically we can still use VSCode or any
other code editors, but
these editors are not ideal for machine learning
projects because
we frequently need to inspect the data and
that is really hard in environments
like VSCode and terminal.
If
you're working with a table of
10 or 20 columns visualizing this
data in a terminal window is really
really difficult and messy.
So
that's why we use Jupiter,
it makes it really easy to inspect our
data.
Now to install Jupiter, we're going to use a platform
called Anaconda.
So head over to anaconda
dot com slash download.
On this page you
can download anaconda distribution
for your operating system.
So
we have distributions for Windows, Mac and Linux.
So let's go ahead and install anaconda
for python 3.7.
Download.
Alright.
So here's Anaconda downloaded on my machine.
Let's double click
this.
All right.
First it's going to run a program to determine
if the software can be installed.
So let's continue.
And
once you can
continue,
continue, pretty easy,
continue
one more time,
I agree with the license agreement. Okay.
You can use the default installation location,
so don't worry about that.
Just
click install.
Give it a few seconds.
Now the
beautiful thing about Anaconda is
that it will install Jupiter as
well as all those popular
data science libraries like numpy,
pandas and so on.
So we don't have to manually install these using pip.
All right.
Now as part of the next step,
Anaconda is suggesting to install Microsoft
VSCode.
We already have this on our machines,
so we don't have to install
it.
We can go with continue and
close the
installation.
Finally we can move this to trash because we
don't need this installer in the future.
All
right.
Now open up a terminal window and
type jupyter with
a white space notebook.
This will start the notebook server on your machine.
So enter.
There
you go.
This will start the notebook server on your machine.
You can
see these default messages here.
Don't worry about them.
Now It
automatically opens a browser window pointing to
local host port 8888.
This
is what we call Jupyter Dashboard.
On this dashboard we have
a few tabs.
The first tab is the files tab and
by default this
points to your home directory.
So every user on your machine has
a home directory.
This is my home directory on Mac.
You can see here
we have a desktop folder
as well as documents, downloads and
so on.
On your machine you're going to see different folders.
So somewhere on
your machine, you need to create a jupyter notebook.
I'm going to
go to desktop.
Here's my desktop.
I don't have anything here and
then click new.
I want to create a
notebook for Python three.
In this notebook we can write
python code and execut it line by line.
We can easily visualize
our data, as you will see
over the next few videos.
So let's
go ahead with this.
All
right.
Here's our first notebook.
You can see by default it's called Untitled.
Let's change that to HelloWorld.
So
this is going to be the HelloWorld of
our machine learning project.
Let's
rename this.
Now If you look at your desktop, you
can see this file, HelloWorld.ipynb,
this is a Jupiter notebook.
It's kind of similar to
our py files where we write our python code, but
it includes additional
data that jupyter uses to execute our code.
So
back to our notebook.
Let's do a print Hello
world.
And then click this
run button here.
And here's the result printed
in Jupiter.
So we don't have to navigate back and forth
between the terminal window.
We can see all the result right here.
Next
I'm going to show you how to
load a data set from a csv file in jupyter.