Alright.
In this lecture we're going to
download a data set from a very popular
website called kaggle.com.
kaggle is basically
a place to the data science projects.
So the first thing you need to
do is to create an account.
You can sign up with Facebook, Google or
using a custom email and password.
Once you sign up, then
come back here on kaggle dot com.
Here in the search bar search
for video game sales.
This
is the name of a very popular data
set that we're going to use in this
lecture.
So here in this list you can see the first
item with this kind of reddish icon.
So let's
go with that.
As you can see this data set includes the
sales data for more than 16,000 video games.
On this page you can see
the description of various columns in this data
set.
We have rank, name, platform, year
and so on.
So here's our data source.
It's a CSV file called
vgsales.csv.
As you can see there are over
16,000 rows and 11 columns in
this data set.
Right below that you can see the first few records of this
data set.
So here's our first record.
The ranking for this
game is one.
It's the Wii sports game for Wii as the
platform.and it was released in the year 2006.
Now
what I want you to do
is to go ahead and download
this data set.
And as I told you before
you need to sign in before you
can download this.
So this will give you a zip file.
As
you can see here.
Here's our CSV file.
Now
I want you to put
this right next your jupyter notebook.
On
my machine that is on my desktop.
So I want to drag and drop this
onto the desktop folder.
Now if
you look at the desktop,
you can see Here's my jupyter HelloWarld
notebook.
And right next to that we have vgsales
dot csv.
With that we go back to our
Jupiter notebook.
Let's remove the first line and instead
import pandas as
pd.
With this we're importing Pandas module and
renaming it to pd so we don't have to
type pandas dot several
times in this code.
Now let's type pd dot
read underline csv and
pass the name of our csv file.
That is vgsales
dot csv.
Now because the csv file is in the current folder right
next to jupyter notebook, we can easily load it otherwise
we'll have to
supply the full path to this file.
So this
returns a data frame object
which is like an Excel spreadsheet.
Let me show you.
So we store it here. and
then we can simply type df to inspect it.
So one
more time. let's run this program.
Here's our data frame
with those rows and columns.
so we have rank, name, platform
and so on.
Now this data frame object has lots of attributes and
methods that we're not going to cover in this tutorial.
That's really beyond the
scope of what we're going to do.
So I leave it up to you to read
pandas documentation or
follow other tutorials to learn about
pandas data frames.
But in this lecture I'm going to show you some of the most
useful methods and attributes.
The first one is shape.
So shape.
Let's run this one more time.
So
here's the shape of this data set.
We have over 16,000
records and 11 columns.
Technically this
is a two dimensional array of 16,000 and
11. Okay?
Now you can see here we have
another segment for writing code, so we
don't have to write all the code
in the first segment.
So here in the second segment we can call one
of the methods of the data frame.
That is df dot describe.
Now let me run this program.
You can see
the output for each segment right next to it.
So
here's our first segment.
Here we have these three lines and this
is the output of the last line.
Below that we
have our second segment, here
we're calling the described method and
right below that we have output of this segment.
So
this is the beauty of jupyter.
You can easily visualize our data
doing this with VSCode and terminal windows
is really tedious and clunky.
So what does this describe method returning?
Basically it's returning some
basic information about each column in this data set.
So
as you saw earlier we have
columns like rank, year and so on.
These are the columns with numerical values.
Now for each column,
we have the count which is
the number of records in that column.
You
can see our Rank column has 16,598 records.
whereas the Year column has 16,327 records.
So this shows that some of
our records don't have the value for
the year column.
We have no values.
So in a real data
science or machine learning project,
we'll have to use some techniques to clean
up our data set.
One option is to remove the records that
don't have a value for the year column.
Or we can assign them
a default value.
That really depends on the project.
Now another
attribute for each column is mean.
So this is the average of
all the values.
Now in the case of the Rank column, this value
doesn't really matter.
But look at the year.
So the average
year for all these video games
in our dataset is 2006,
and this might be important in
the problem we're trying to solve.
We
also have standard deviation
which is a measure to
quantify the amount of variation in our set of values.
Below
that we have min.
As an example the minimum value
for the Year column is 1980.
So
quite often when we work with a
new data set, we call the described method
to get some basic statistics about our data.
Let me
show you another useful attribute.
So in the next segment
let's type df dot values.
Let's
run this.
As you can see this returns a two dimensional array.
This square bracket indicates the outer array and the
second one represents the inner array.
So the first element
in our outer array is an array itself.
These
are the values in this array
which basically represents the
first row in our dataset.
So the video game with
ranking one which is called Wii Sports.
So
this was a basic overview
of pandas data frames.
In the next lecture I'm gonna show you
some of the useful shortcuts of jupyter.