In this section I'm going to show
you some of the most useful shortcuts in
jupyter.
Now the first thing I want you to pay attention to is
this green bar on the left.
This indicates that
this cell is currently in the edit mode, so
we can write code
here.
Now if we press the escape key,
green turns to blue and
that means this cell is currently in
the command mode.
So basically the activated cell can
be either in the edit mode or
the command mode.
Depending
on the mode we have different shortcuts.
So here we are currently
in the command mode.
If we press h we
can see the list of all the keyboard shortcuts.
Right
above this list,
you can see Mac OS modifier
keys.
These are the extra keys that
we have on a Mac keyboard.
If
you're a Windows user,
you're not going to see this.
So as an example here
is the shape of the command key,
this is control,
this
is option and so on.
With this guideline you can easily
understand the shortcut associated with each command.
Let me
show you.
So here we have all the commands when
a cell is in the command mode.
For example we have this command:
open the command palette.
This is exactly like the command
palette that we have in VSCode.
Here's a shortcut to
execute this command that is
command, shift and f
Okay?
So here we have lots of
shortcuts.
Of course you're not going to
use all of them all the time, But
it's good to have a quick look here
to see what is available for you.
With
these shortcuts you can write code much faster.
So let me show you some of
the most useful ones.
I'm gonna close this.
Now
with our first cell in the command mode,
I'm going to press
b and this insert a new cell
below this cell.
You can also go back to our first
cell.
Press escape.
Now the cell is in the
command mode.
We can insert an empty cell above this
cell by pressing a, so either a
or b, a for above
and b for below. Okay?
Now
if you don't want this cell,
you can press d twice to delete it.
Like
this.
Now in this cell I'm going to print a hello world
message.
So print hello world.
Now to run the code in this cell,
we can click on
the run button here.
So here's
our print function and
right below that you can see the output
of this function.
But note that when you run a cell, this will
only execute the code in that cell.
In other
words the code in other cells will not be executed.
Let
me show you what I mean.
So in the cell below this cell, I'm
going to delete the call to the describe method.
Instead I'm
going to print ocean.
Now
I'm going to put the cursor
back in this cell where we
print the hello world message
and run this cell.
So
you can see hello world is displayed here,  but
the cell below
is still displaying that describe table.
So we don't see
the changes here.
Now to solve this problem we
can go to cell menu on the top and
run all
cells together.
This can work for
small projects but
sometimes you're working with a large data set.
So if you want to run all these cells together,
it's going to take a lot
of time.
That is the reason jupyter saves the
output of each cell.
So we don't have to rerun that code
if it hasn't changed.
So this notebook file that we have here
includes our source code
organized in cells as well as
the output for each
cell.
That is why it's different
from a regular py file where
we only have the source code.
Here we also have auto
completion and intellisense.
So in this cell let's
call df data frame dot, now
if you press tab,
you can see all the attributes and methods
in this object.
So let's call describe.
Now with the cursor on the name of the method,
we can press shift and
tab to see this tool tip that
describes what this
method does and what parameter it takes.
So here in front
of signature you can see the describe method.
These are the
parameters and their default value.
And right below that
you can see the description
of what this method does.
In
this case it generates descriptive statistics that summarize
the central tendency and so on.
Similar to
VSCode we can also convert
a line to comment by pressing command
and slash on Mac or
control slash on windows.
Like
this.
Now this line is a comment.
We can press the
same shortcut one more time
to remove the comments.
So
these were some of the most useful shortcuts in Jupiter.
Now over
the next few lectures we're going to
work on a real machine learning project.
But
before we get there let's delete all the cells here,
so we start with
only a single empty cell.
So here in this
cell first I'm going to
press the escape button. Now the
cell is blue.
So we are in the command mode and
we can delete this
cell by pressing d twice.
There you go.
Now
the next cell is activated and
it's in the command mode.
So let's
delete this as well.
We have two more cells
to delete.
There you go.
And the last one like
this.
So now we have an empty notebook with a single cell.