Over the next few lectures we're going to
work on a real machine learning project.
Imagine
we have an online music store.
When our users sign up we
asked her age and gender
and based on their profile we
recommend various music albums they are likely to buy.
So
in this project we want to
use machine learning to increase sales.
So
we want to build a model.
We feed this model with some sample
data based on the existing users.
Our model will
learn the patterns in our data so
we can ask it to make predictions.
When
a new user signs up we tell our model
hey we have a new user with
this profile,
what is the kind of music that this user is interested in?
Our model will say jazz or hip hop or whatever.
and based
on that we can make suggestions to the user.
So this is the problem
we're going to solve.
Now back to the list of steps in a machine learning
project.
First we need to import our data.
Then we
should prepare or clean it.
Next we select a machine learning algorithm
to build a model.
We train our model.
And ask it
to make predictions.
And finally we evaluate our algorithm to
see its accuracy.
If it's not accurate, we either fine tune
our model or
select a different algorithm.
So
let's focus on the first step.
Head over to bit.ly/
music-csv.
This is a very basic csv
that I've created for this project.
It's just some random made up
data.
It's not real.
So we have a table with
three columns: Age, gender and genre.
Gender
can either be one
which represents a male or zero
which represents a female.
Here I'm making a few assumptions.
I'm
assuming that men between
20 and 25 like hip
hop, men between 26 30 like
jazz and after the age
of 30 they like classical
music.
For women I'm assuming that
if they are between 20 and
25 they like dance music,
If they're
between 26 30 they like acoustic music and
just like men after the age
of 30 they like classical music.
Once
again this is a made up pattern.
It's not the representation of the reality.
So let's go ahead and
download this csv.
click on
this dot dot dot icon here and
download this
file.
In my downloads folder here we
have this music that csv.
I'm going to drag and drop
this onto desktop because
that's where I've stored this
HelloWorld notebook.
So I want you to put the csv file right next
your jupyter notebook.
Now back to our
notebook.
We need to read this csv file.
So just like
before first we need to import
the pandas module, so
import pandas as pd.
And
then we'll call pd dot read underline csv
and the name of the file is music dot
csv.
As you saw earlier this returns a data frame
which is a two dimensional array
similar to an Excel spreadsheet.
So
let's call that music_data.
Now let's inspect this music_data to make sure
we loaded everything properly.
So run.
So
here's our data frame. Beautiful.
Next we need to prepare or clean the data.
And that's the topic for the next lecture.