The second step in a machine
learning project is cleaning or preparing the
data and
that involves tasks such as
removing duplicates, null
values and so on.
Now in this particular data set we don't have to do
any kind of cleaning because
we don't have any duplicates and as
you can see all rows
have values for all columns.
So
we don't have null values.
But there is one thing we need to do.
We
should split this data set into
two separate data sets, one
with the first two columns which we
refer to as the input set and
the other with the last column
which we refer to as the output set.
So when we train a model
we give it to separate data sets:
the input set and
the output set.
The output set which
is in this case the genre column contains the predictions.
So we're telling our model that
if we have a user was 20
years old and is a male,
they like hip hop.
Once
we train our model, then
we give it a new input set.
For
example we say Hey we have
a new user who is 21 years
old and it's a male,
What is the genre of the music that
this user probably likes?
As you can see in our input set
we don't have a sample for a 21 year old male.
So we're
going to ask our model to predict that.
That is the
reason we need to split this
data set into two separate sets:
input and output.
So back to our code
this data frame object has
a method called drop.
Now
if you put the cursor on
the method name and press shift and
tab you can see this tool tip.
So this is
the signature of this drop method.
These are the parameters that
we can pass here.
The parameter we're going to use in this lecture is columns
which is set to None by default.
With this parameter
we can specify the columns
we want to drop.
So in
this case reset columns to an array
with one string, genre.
Now this method doesn't
actually modify the original data set.
In fact it will
create a new data set but without this column.
So
by convention we use a
capital X to represent that
data set.
So capital X equals this
expression.
Now let's inspect X.
So as you can see our input set or X includes these
two columns: age and gender.
It doesn't have the output or
predictions.
Next we need to create our output set.
So
once again we start with
our data frame music_data.
Using square brackets we can
get all the values in a
given column, in this case genre.
Once
again this returns a new data set.
By convention we
use a lowercase y to represent that.
So that
is our output dataset.
Let's inspect that as well.
So in this data set
we only have the predictions or
the answers.
So we have prepared our data.
Next we need to create a model using an algorithm.