The next step is to build a
model using a machine learning algorithm.
There's
so many algorithms out there and
each algorithm has its pros and cons
in terms of the performance and accuracy.
In this lecture we're
going to use a very
simple algorithm called Decision Tree.
Now
the good news is that
we don't have to explicitly program these
algorithms.
They're already implemented for
us in the library called
scikit-learn.
So here on the top from
sklearn.tree let's
import the DecisionTreeClassifier.
So sklearn is the package that comes with scikit-learn
library this is
the most popular machine learning library in
Python.
In this package we have a module called tree
and in this module we have
a class called DecisionTreeClassifier.
This
class implements the decision tree algorithm.
Okay?
So now we need to
create a new instance of this class.
So at the end,
let's create an object called model
and set it to a new instance of DecisionTreeClassifier
like this.
So
now we have a model.
Next we need to train it, so it learns patterns
in the data.
And that is pretty easy.
We call model dot
fit.
This method takes two data sets:
the input
set and the output set.
So they are
Capital X and y.
Now finally
we need to ask our model to make a prediction,
so we can ask it
What is the kind of music that a 21 year old male likes?
Now
before we do that
let's temporarily inspect our
initial data set. That is music data. So
look what we got here.
As I told you earlier I have
assumed that men between 20 and 25 like
hip hop music.
But here we only have three samples for
men aged 20, 23 and 25.
We
don't have a sample for a 21 year old men.
So if you ask our
model to predict the kind of music
that a 21 year old man likes? we
expected to say hip hop.
Similarly I've
assumed that women between 20
and 25 like dance music.
But
we don't have a sample for
a 22 year old female.
So once
again if you ask our model to
predict the kind of music that a
22 year old woman likes?
we expected to say dance.
So
with these assumptions,
let's goahead and
ask our model to
make predictions.
So let's
remove the last line.
And instead we're
going to call model.predict.
This
method takes a two dimensional array.
So here's
the outer array.
In this array each element is an array.
So I'm going to pass another array here and
in this
array I'm going to pass a new input set,
a 21 year
old male, so 21 comma one.
That
is like a new record in this table. Okay?
So
this is one input set.
Let's pass another input set for a 22
year old female.
So here's another array.
Here
we add 22 comma zero.
So we're
asking our model to make two predictions at the same time.
We
get the result and
store it in a variable called
predictions.
And finally let's inspect that in
our notebook.
Run.
Look
what we got.
Our model is saying that a 21
year old male likes hip hop and
a 22 year old female
likes dance music.
So our model could successfully make
predictions here. Beautiful.
But wait a second.
Building a
model that makes predictions accurately,
it's not always that easy.
As
I told you earlier after we build a model
we need to measure its
accuracy and
if it's not accurate enough,
we should either fine
tun it or
build a model using a different algorithm.
So
in the next lecture
I'm going to show you
how to measure the accuracy of a model.