In this lecture I'm going to show you
how to measure the accuracy of your models.
Now in order to do so,
first we need to split our data set into
two sets:
one for training and
the other for testing.
Because
right now we're passing
the entire data set for
training the model and
we're using two samples for making
predictions.
That is not enough to calculate the accuracy of
a model.
A general rule of thumb is to allocate 70
to 80% of our data for training and
the other 20
to 30% for testing.
Then instead of passing only
two samples for making predictions,
we can pass the data set
we have for testing,
we'll get the predictions and
then we can compare
these predictions with the actual
values in the test set.
Based on that we can calculate the accuracy.
That's really easy.
All we have to do is to
import a couple of functions and
call them
in this code.
Let me show you.
So first on the top from
sklearn.model_selection
module, we import a function called train
test split.
With this function,
we can easily split our
data set into two sets:
for training and testing.
Now right here after we define X and
y sets we call this function.
So train test
split.
We give it three arguments X, y
and a keyword argument that
specifies the size of our test
data set.
So test_size, we
set it to 0.2.
So we are allocated 20% of
our data for testing.
Now this function returns
a tuple,
so we can unpack it into four variables right
here.
X_train,
X_test, y_train and
y_test.
So the
first two variables are the
input sets for training and
testing and
the other are the output
sets for training and testing.
Now when
training our model,
instead of passing the entire data
set we want to pass only the training data set.
So X
_train and
y_
train.
Also when making predictions instead
of passing these two samples
we pass X_
test.
So that is the data set that contains input
values for testing.
Now we get the
predictions.
To calculate the accuracy,
we simply have to compare
these predictions with the
actual values we have in
our output set for testing.
That is very easy.
First
on the top we need to import a function.
So from
sklearn.metrics import
accuracy_score.
Now at
the very end we call this function.
So accuracy score
and give it two arguments: y
underline test which contains the expected values and
predictions which contains the actual values.
Now this function returns an
accuracy score between 0 to 1.
So we can store it here and simply
displayed on the console.
So let's go ahead
and run this program.
So the accuracy score
is one or 100%.
But if you run this one more time, we're
going to see a different result because
every time we split our data
set into training and test set,
we'll have different data set
because this function randomly
picks data for training and
testing.
Let me show you.
So put the cursor in the
cell.
Now you can see this cell is activated.
Note that if you
click this button here,
it will run this cell and also insert
a new cell below this cell.
Let me show you.
So if I go
to the second cell press escape button.
Now
we are in the command mode.
Press d twice. Okay.
Now
it's deleted.
If we click the run button, you
can see this code was executed and
now we have a new cell.
So
if you want to run our first cell multiple times,
every time we have to click
this and then run it and
then click again and run it.
It's
a little bit tedious.
So I show you a shortcut.
Activate the
first cell and press control and enter.
This
runs the current cell
without adding a new cell below
it.
So back here.
Let's try it multiple times. Okay.
Now look, the accuracy dropped to 0.75.
It's
still good.
So the accuracy score here is somewhere between
75% to 100%.
But let me show you something.
If
I change the test size from 0.2 to 0.8,
so essentially we're using
only 20% more data for training
this model and
we're using the other 80% for testing.
Now
let's see what happens when we
run the cell multiple times.
So control
and enter.
Look.
The accuracy immediately dropped to
0.4.
One more time.
Now 46%, 40%.
26%, It's really really bad.
The
reason this is happening is because
we are using very little data for
training this model.
This is one of the key concept in
machine learning:
The more data we give to our model and the cleaner
the data is, we get the better result.
So if you have duplicates,
irrelevant data or incomplete values, our model will
learn bad patterns in our data.
That is why it's really important to
clean our data before
training our model.
Now let's
change this back to 0.2.
Run this
one more time.
Okay. Now the accuracy is one, 75%.
Now we dropped to 50%.
Again the reason this is happening is
because we don't have enough data.
Some machine learning problems require
thousands or even millions of
samples to train a model.
The more complex the problem is,
the more data we need.
For example here
we're only dealing with the table of three columns,
but if you want
to build a model to tell if a
picture is a cat or a dog or
a horse or a lion
will need millions of pictures.
The
more animals we want to support,
the more pictures we need.
In the next lecture we're gonna talk about model persistence.