So I've got a few questions for you, 'cause
I wanna see if you have been really paying attention to
this video or not.
You better have. so here's the first question. for each question
I want you to pause the video, think about the answer for
a few seconds, when you're ready continue watching.
So here's the first question:
What is an expression?
An expression is a piece of code that produces a value.
Here's an example of an expression.
What do you think is the value of this expression?
Well here we have this string,
We're multiplying this by 3.
So the result will be a string of three asterisks like this.
Here's another question.
What is a syntax error?
A syntax error is a kind of error that is due to bad syntax
or bad grammar in the code. and finally the last question.
What does a linter do?
A linter is a tool that checks our code for potential errors
mostly in the category of syntactical Errors.
So if you have grammatical issues in our code, the linter
will tell us before running a program.
Okay, that's it for now.
If you like more quizzes and programming exercises look at
the link below this video and if you have enjoyed this video,
I hope you have, please support me by giving a thumbs up,
Please like this video and share it with others. In the next
section, We're gonna look at the rules of python.