So this environment you see here is what we call python interpreter,
which is basically a program that executes python code.
We can type our python code in a file and give it to this
interpreter or we can type our code directly here in this
interactive shell.
So here we can write an expression like two plus two in programming
and expression is a piece of code that produces a value so
here when we What's two plus two we get a value that is why
we refer to this piece of code as an expression.
So enter we get for let's try a different kind of expression.
Let's see if 2 is greater than 1 we get true, which is an
example of a Boolean value.
You're going to learn about this Boolean values in the next
section. Now, what if we type 2 is greater than 5 enter we
get false.
So in programming we have true and false.
False which are similar to yes, and no in English.
Now what if we type 2 is greater than what we don't add a
second value here.
Just press enter.
We got a syntax error in programming syntax means grammar.
So just like we have the concept of grammar in the languages
that we speak.
We have the exact same concept in programming if we write
a sentence that is not grammatically correct chances are
some people may not understand that sentence.
So in this example, we have this expression, which is incomplete.
It doesn't have the right grammar or syntax.
That is why python interpreter is complaining by returning.
An error.
So this interactive shell is a great way to quickly experiment
with a bit of python code, but that's not how we build real
world applications to do that.
We need a code editor and that's what I'm going to show you
in the next lecture.