All right, once again,
it's time for another quiz,
let's see if you have been really
paying attention to this tutorial.
So here's the first question.
What are the built
primitive types in Python?
We have strength numbers and booleans
numbers can be integers,
float's or complex numbers.
Here's the second question.
You have this variable fruit set to apple.
What do you think we will see on the
terminal when we print fruit of one?
Well, he was in square brackets,
we can access individual characters,
the index of the first character is zero.
So this expression returns the second
character, which is Pete,
what if you had a colon,
a negative one here?
Well, using the syntax,
we can slice a string are start,
index is one and our end index is negative
one, which refers to the first
character from the end of the string.
Now, when slicing a string,
the character at the end index
or negative one is not included.
So with this expression will get all
the characters starting from the second
character, which is pee all
the way until we get to eat.
So the result of this
expression is keep out.
Here's another question.
What is the result of this expression?
Well, this is what we call the modulus
operator, and it returns the remainder
of a division, which is in this case one.
And finally, the last question,
what do you think we will see
when we print Bull of Boss?
Well, earlier, I told you about falsey
values in Python, so number zero,
an empty string and the non-allergic,
these are all falsey values.
Anything that is not falsey
is considered Truthy.
Here we have a string
that has five characters.
It doesn't matter what
those characters are.
This is not an empty string.
So it's not falsey, it's Truthy.
So when we converted, using the bool
function will get the boolean.
True.
And this brings us
to the end of the section.
In the next section, you're going to learn
the fundamentals of computer programing.
I hope you have enjoyed this section.
And thank you for watching.