So these are the variables
from the last lecture.
I've got a question for you.
There are four things that I've
consistently used in this program.
Can you spot them?
If you want?
You can positively think about this for a
few seconds and then continue watching.
So here are those four things,
the first thing is that all my variable
names are descriptive and meaningful.
So Students Count represents the number
of students for a course or course.
Name clearly explains that this
variable holds the name of a course.
One of the issues that I see a lot among
beginner programmers is that they use
mystical names for their variables,
something like this season
as a short four course name.
When someone else reads this code,
they have no idea what's the N stands for,
or they use variable names like C one.
When I look at that code,
I wonder where you see two and what
is the difference between C1 and C2.
So these variable names are very mystical.
That's a bad practice.
Make sure your variable names are always
descriptive and meaningful because this
makes your code more maintainable.
Now there are times that you can use short
variable names like X, Y, Z if you're
dealing with things like coordinates.
So that's an exception.
Now,
the second thing that I have consistently
used in this code is that I have used
lowercase letters to name my variables.
So here we don't have course name all
in capital or in title case,
all letters are lowercase.
Right.
Let's delete this.
The third thing that I've consistently
used here is that I have used
an underscore to separate multiple words,
and I've done this to make my variable
names more readable because in Python we
cannot have a space in variable names,
so we cannot have course name.
And if you put these two words together,
it's a little bit hard to read.
That's why we use an underscore.
And the fourth thing that I have used
consistently here is that I have put
a space around this equals sign.
Again, that's one of the issues
I see a lot among beginners.
They write code like this.
This is a little bit ugly.
This is what we call dirty code,
dirty, stinky, smelly.
You should write code that is clean
and beautiful so other people can read it
like a story, like a newspaper article.
You should be formatted properly.
And that's why we have peppered in Python.
Now, the good thing is,
if you forget these rules,
when you save the changes,
all the pep aid kicks in and it
automatically reformats your code.
But that aside, you should always give
yourself the habit of writing clean code
without relying too much on the tooling.
So these are all the best practices
about naming your variables.
Next, we're going to look
at string's in more detail.