mhm. Yeah. So
here we have this course
variable set to Python programming. As
I told you before. whenever you
work with texts. you should surround
your text with quote.
You can either use double quotes or
single quotes. That's more of
a personal preference. but quite
often we use double quotes. We also have
triple quotes. and we use
them to format a long
string. For example.
if you have. let's say a
variable message. That is the message we want
to include in the
body of an email. You
can use triple quotes to
format it like this. Hi
. John. This is Marsh from code with
marsh dot com. Blah. blah. blah. So
that's when we use triple quotes. Now we
don't need this in this lecture.
So delayed. Let
me show you a few useful
things you can do with strength. First
of all. we have this
built in function in python. forgetting
the length of strength.
What is the function. A
function is basically a
reusable piece of code that
carries out a task as a metaphor.
I think of the
remote control of your T V on this remote control. You
have buttons for different functions
like turn on. turn off
. change the channel and so on.
These are the built in functions in
your T V in Python
and many other programming languages
. We have the exact same concept.
So we have functions that
are built into the language
and the platform. You can reuse
these functions to perform various tasks. So
here we can use the
built in Len function to get
the length of a string.
which means the number of characters in
that string. Now. whenever you
want to use a function. you
should use parenthesis. Now we say we're
calling this function.
which basically means we're using this
function now. Some functions take additional data
. which we refer to as arguments.
These arguments are
input to these functions. so this
land function takes an
input on an argument. Here
we pass our course variable.
and this will return the
number of characters in this string.
So let's print
that and see what we get. Run the
program. We get 18 because we
have 18 characters here. Let's look
at another example. If you
want to get access to a
specific character in the string.
you use the square bracket
notation So here we add course square
brackets. To get the first character.
you use the
index zero. So in python. like
many other languages. strings are zero index
. which means the index of
the first character or the first element
is zero. So now
when we print this. we'll
get P. Okay. Now
. you can also use
a negative index like minus
one. What does that mean. Well. if
zero represents the first character here
. what do you think.
Negative one real presence that
takes us back to the end
of the string. So that returns the
first character from the end
of the string. Let's run
this program. You will see
you will get G. There
you go. Using a similar scene tax. you
can slice strength. let me show you. So
I'm going to duplicate this
line and remove negative one
. Now let's say we want
to extract the first three characters in
this string. So here
we need to indexes the
start Index colon. the and the index. So
at this point returns a
new string that contains the
first three characters in this course variable. That
will be P Y and T.
So the index of
these characters are 01 and two. So that
means the character at the
end index is not included
. Okay. let's run the
program and make sure we
get the right result.
There you go. P Y t. Now
. what if we don't
include the end index. What
do you think we're going to get.
It's common sense. We
start from Index zero and
go all the way to
the end of the string.
So this will return a new string. That
is exactly the same
as the original string. Let's
take a look. So we get python
programming now. What if we don't include
the start index.
but include the end index. What
do you think we're going to
get once again. It's common sense
. So by default.
Python will put zero here. so it
will start from the beginning of the strength.
So when I run this
program. we should get P y t one more time. There
you go. And finally. as the last
example. If we don't include the start and
the end index. this will
return a copy of the original
strength. Let's look at this. So we
get python programming now
you don't have to memorize
any of these. Just remember. we
use the land function to get
the length of a string. We use
bracket notation to get access
to a specific element or
a specific character.
and we use this notation to