Mhm. Yeah. So
we have this string here.
Python programming. Now let's say
we want to put a double
coat in the middle of the
string. There is a problem here. Python interpreter
sees this second string
as the end of the
string. So the rest of
the code is meaningless and invalid
. How do you solve this problem.
Well. there are two ways. One
way is to use single quotes for
our strength. And then we
can use a double coat in
the middle of the strength.
But what if. for whatever reason
. perhaps. for being consistent
in our code. we decided
to yours Double cuts.
How can we add another
double coat in the middle
of the string. Well. we
can prefix this with a backslash. Backslash
in python strings is
a special character. We have
a jargon for that called escape character. We
use it to escape the character after. Let
me show you what I mean.
So let's print this
course I run this program. What's
going on here. We don't
have the bag slash because we
use that to escape this
double coat and basically displayed
here. So backslash is an
escape character and backslash double coat is
an escape sequence in python strength.
We have a
few other escape sequences that
you should be aware of. Let
me show you. So in Python.
we use high sign
to indicate a comment.
A comment is like additional note
that we add to our program.
It's not executed by Python interpreter
. Okay. so here
are the escape sequences You
have seen backslash double code. We also have
a backslash single code so we
can use that to add
a single code. Here. Let's
run the program here it is beautiful. We
also have double backslash.
So if you want to
include a backslash in your strings. you
should prefix it with another backslash.
Let me show you
. So when we run this.
we get Python one backslash programming
and finally we have backslash in which is
short for a new line.
So now if I add a
backslash in here. see what we
get. We get a new line after
python. so programming will end
up on the second line. So