In this next hour,
we're going to look at a few useful
functions available to work with strings.
So earlier you learned about
this built-In land function.
This function is general purpose,
so it's not limited to strings.
Later, I will show you how to use this
function with other kind of objects.
But in Python, we have quite a few
functions that are specific to a strings.
Let me show you.
So here, if we type coarse dot see
all these are functions available
on strings now in precise terms,
refer to these functions as methods.
This is a term and object oriented
programing that you will learn
about later in the course.
For now, what I want you to take away is
that everything in Python is an object
and objects have functions we call methods
that we can access using the DOT notation.
So here course is an object.
We use the DOT notation to access its
functions or more accurately, methods.
Let's take a look at a few of these
methods we have up here
to convert a string to uppercase.
Now let's print this and run the program.
Here is what we get.
Beautiful.
That note that the methods that you
call here return a new string.
So the original string is not a factor.
Let me show you.
So print course,
run the program one more time.
Look, this is our original string, right?
So, of course, the upper returns
and new string, a new value.
We can store it in a variable like course
underlying capital
like this.
Now, to keep this demo simple
and consistent, I'm going to revert
this back and use a print statement.
We also have the lower method
to convert a string to lowercase.
We also have title which will capitalize
the first letter of every word.
So if our string was like this,
when we call the title method, we get
Python programing, as you see here.
OK.
Another useful method is strip,
and we use it to trim any white space at
the beginning or end of history string.
This is particularly useful when
we receive input from the user.
Let me show you.
So let's imagine
the user entered a couple of white
spaces at the beginning of this string.
When we call coarse that strip,
those white spaces will be removed.
Take a look.
So note that in the first three examples,
we have those white spaces,
but in the last one it is removed.
So a strip remove the white space from
both the beginning and end of a string.
We also have a L strip,
which is short for left strip and our
strip, which is short or right strip.
So it will remove the white
space from the end of history.
If you want to get the index
of a character or a sequence of characters
in your string, you should
use the find method and.
So, of course, that find
so as an argument here to pass another
string, we can pass a character
or a series of characters.
Let's find the index of Pro
Rhondda, the program.
So the index of Pro is nine.
So if you start from zero here all the way
to nine, this is the index of pro, OK.
Now, as I told you before,
Python is a case sensitive language,
so if I pass a capital P here,
obviously we don't have these
exact characters in our string.
So let's see what we get.
We get a negative one,
that means this string was not
found in the original string.
Another useful method is replace,
so we call replace with this,
we can replace a character or a sequence
of characters with something else.
So let's say we want to replace
all lowercase PS with J.
With this, we get Jitendra programing,
whatever that means.
And finally,
if you want to check for the existence
of a character or a sequence of characters
in your string, you can
use that in operator.
Let me show you.
So print.
Right, an expression
like this pro in course.
So this is an expression,
as I told you before, an expression is
a piece of code that produces a value.
So this expression checks to see
if you have a pro in course.
The difference between this expression
and calling the find method is
that the fine method returns the index
of these characters in our stream.
But as this expression returns, a boolean.
So it's a true or false.
Let me show you sort of run the program.
We get the boolean.
True.
And finally, we have the knot operator
and we use that to see if our string does
not contain a character or
sequence of characters, so.
Let's change this to Swift.
Not in course when this
expression is evaluated.
What do you think we're going to get?
Well, we don't have swift in this
string, so not in will return.
True.
Let's take a look.
There you go.
So these are the useful string methods.
Next, we'll look at numbers.