mhm. Yeah. In
Python. we have three types of numbers.
Two of these you
have already seen before.
They are integers and floats
. We also have complex numbers. so
complex numbers in math are
in the form A plus
B I where I is the imaginary number
. If you're not familiar with this concept.
don't worry. This is something that
is used a lot in
mathematics and electrical engineering. If
you want to use python to
build Web applications. you're never going
to use complex numbers. But let
me quickly show you the scene tax
for representing complex numbers instead of
I we use J.
So here is an example one
plus two j. So X now is a complex number
. And by the way. as I told you before.
this is just a comment or
an additional note in our program.
When we run this program
. anything after this high
sign will be ignored. So
these are the three types of
numbers we have in python. For all
these types of numbers.
we have the standard charismatic
operations that we have in mass.
Let me show
you. So we have addition. subtraction
. multiplication division. But we
actually have two different types of divisions.
Let me show you. First
. let's run this program.
So with this division operator. which
is a slash. we get
a floating point number. If
you want an integer.
you use double slashes. Let
me show you. So double slash run
the program. We get three. Okay
. We also have module is which is
the remainder of a division. And finally. exponents
. which is left to
the power of right. so
10 to the power of
three will be 1000. These
are the standard arithmetic operators. Now. for
all these operators. we have
a special operator called Augmented
Assignment. Operator. let me show you. So let's
imagine we have X set to 10
. We want to increment x by.
Let's say three. We
can write an expression like this.
X equals X plus
three. Or we can
use an augmented assignment operator
that is a little bit shorter.
So we write X plus
equal three. These two statements are
exactly the same.
Now. here I am using addition
. As an example. you can
use any of these operators here