all right. Now let's take a look
at another useful built in function in
Python. We use the input function to
get input from the user
as an argument that pass
a string. This will be a
label that will be displayed in
the terminal. You will see
that in a second. So let's
add X colon. Now this function returns
a string so we can store it in
this variable. Now let's imagine that why
should be X plus one. Save
the changes now.
Don't run this program using the
code Runner extension because code runner by default
runs your program in the output window.
which is read only so
you won't be able to
enter a value. So open up
the terminal using control and backspace once
again. If you're on Windows Type python.
if you're on Mac or Linux type
Python3 and app.py. So
here's our label. Let's enter
a value like one. We
got an error type error.
What is going on
here. Well. when we receive input
from the user,
this input always comes as a
string. so this expression at runtime will
look like this string one plus
one. Note that the number
one is different from string
one because these are two different types.
Now when Python sees
this expression it doesn't know
what to do because two
objects can be concatenated if
they are of the same type.
So here we need
to convert this string one to
a number. In Python we have
a few built in functions for
type conversion. We have int for
converting a number to an integer.
We have float. we
have bool and str or string. Now
in this case we don't need
to convert X to a string because X
is already a string. If you don't believe me.
let me show you. So
I'm gonna comment out these few lines. Now
let's print type of
X. So type is
another built in function We
pass an object as an
argument and it returns its
type. Also. I'm going to
comment out this line because
that's the bad boy We don't want
to execute this. Save the changes. back
in the terminal. Let's run
this program one more time. Enter
one. Look. This is what the type function
returns. Now don't worry about the class
We'll talk about
classes later in the course.
so the type of X is a
str or string. So let's
do it this line.
To fix this problem we
need to convert X to an integer. And
then we can print both X and y using a
formatted string.
Remember. So we had an f quotes
like here we add a
label like X. Then we'll add
a field. So here we
wanna print the value of
X variable. After that.
we add some more text
and finally want to print
the value of why. Let's
run this program one more time. So here
in the terminal. let's enter one. And
here's the result. X is 1
and y is 2, beautiful. Now
all these built in functions
are self explanatory. The only
tricky one is bool. because in
python we have this concept of
truthy and falsy values. These are
values that are not exactly a
boolean True or False, but
they can be interpreted as
a boolean True or
False. So here are
the falsy values in
python: empty strings are considered falsy,
so they're interpreted
as a Boolean False. Number
zero is also falsy.
We have an object called
None which represents the
absence of a value. We'll
look at this later in the course.
So whenever we use these
values in a boolean
context we'll get False.
Anything else will be True.
Let me show you a few examples. So
in this interactive shell in Python
let's convert number
zero to bool. That's Falsy
So we get False. What
about bool of one? We get True. If
you pass a negative number
we'll also get True. If
we pass a number larger
than one like five, we
still get true. So we
only get false when we
try to convert zero to a boolean.
Now with strings
I told you that an
empty string is falsy So
here we'll get False. Anything else is
True. So even if I have a string that
is "False" we'll get True because this
is not an empty string.
It's a string with a few characters,
That's why it's evaluated as True.