In this section we're going to look
at classes which are extremely important in
python programming or in programming in general. So
let's start with an example.
I'm going to define a list
of numbers like this. Now you have
learned that when we use the dark notation.
we get access to
all these functions or. more accurately. methods enlist
objects. so every list
object in python has these
methods now. Wouldn't it
be nice if we could
create an object like shopping cart. And this
object would have methods like add. remove. get
total like this. Or as another
example. Wouldn't that be nice if
we could have a point. Object with
methods like Draw. move or get
distance to get the
distance between this point and
another point. That's when classes come to
the rescue. So a
class is a blueprint for
creating new objects. Throughout the course. you have
heard the term class.
for example. Let's define a
variable and set it to an integer.
and then print it's
type. When we run this program.
what do you see here
. A class of aunt.
So in Python we have
a class called Aunt for creating managers. Similarly
. we have classes
for creating billions. lists. dictionaries
and so on.
So every object that we have in python is created
using a class which is
a blueprint for creating objects of
that type. In this section.
you're going to learn how to create custom
classes like customer shopping. cart point
and so on. Now.
before we get started. let's define
a few terms. Once again. a class is
a blueprint for creating new objects. An
object is an instance of a class. As
an example. we could have
a class called Human. and
this class would define all
the attributes of humans. Then
we could create objects like John. Mary
. Jack and so on.
So this is a difference between classes and
objects. Now a lot of
people use these terms interchangeably
. but technically a class
and an object are different. So
now you know what classes are
and how they're useful. In the next
lecture. I'm going to show you how
to create a custom class in Python