This class will be built in the last
lecture has a tiny problem.
Let me
show you.
So here we have a cloud object I want to
call Cloud that at past python. Repeat
this a couple of times and
then change this to an R p
G s P.
Now. if we print cloud of
python all in uppercase. we
get three. So our
program is working. However. if
I access the underlying
dictionary in this class. our
program is going to crash.
Let's take a look. So
we got an exception of
type key error because we
don't have this key in our dictionary.
Everything stored as
lower case.
So the problem with this class is
that it gives us access
to the underlying dictionary that
is used to keep track of the count of tags.
To
fix this problem we need to
hide this attribute from the outside so
we cannot access it.
How do we do this? Very easy.
So
back to our class put the cursor on
this attribute and press F2.
This is
used for renaming objects in VSCode.
Now to make this
private or inaccessible from the outside you
need to prefix it with two underlines.
Now when you press
enter you're going to see an error on the bottom right corner of
the screen is going to tell
you that the re factoring library rope
is not installed. Go ahead and
install that and then try this
again. Now we can see all occurrences of
self attacks. is renamed to
self dot Double underscore tags
now back to where we use a
tag cloud object. If we use the DOT
operator so cloud dot we
no longer have tags here.
We also don't have double
underscore tags. So if you print this. we
get an exception of type attribute. error tag
. Cloud object doesn't have this attribute. So
this is how we can
make certain attributes or certain methods
in a class private. If it
prefix them with double under squares
they're considered private.
Having said that technically these
members are still accessible from the outside,
it's just a little bit harder
to access them.
So the point of this practice is not security.
It's
more of a warning or alert to
someone who is using this class, it's
telling the consumer of this class:
Hey, don't touch this, this is private.
But
let me show you
How you can still access this?
I'm
going to delete all this code.
Every class or every object
has this property called Underscore Underscore dict.
This
is a dictionary that holds
all the attributes in this class.
Let's take a look.
France. So
in this class. we have this attribute called
Underlying tag. Cloud double underlines tax. So
when Python interpreter runs this go.
it automatically renames
this attribute and prefixes it
with the name of its class
. So technically we can still access it.
Let me show you. I'm going to copy this
name and then print
cloud dot This attribute. Let's take
a look. We get an empty dictionary.
So
in python unlike languages like C Sharp or Java, we
don't really have the concept of private member's.
These private
members are still accessible from the outside.
Using double underscores
is more of a convention to prevent
accidental access of these private members.