There are times that you want to
have control over an attribute in
a class.
For example: Here we have this product class in
the constructor.
We said the price attributes With
this implementation. we can
create a product object and
give it a negative price. And Python interpreter
will execute this without any problems.
This is not good. So
How can we prevent this?
How can we ensure that our products don't
have a negative price?
Here's one simple solution: We
can make this field
private and then define two
methods for getting and setting
the value of this attribute. So
we define a method
called get underlying price. Here
we simply return self that price and
similarly with define set
on the line price that
takes a value. Now here. First we
check. If value is less than zero. we
can raise an exception
of type value error. saying
price cannot be negative. Otherwise
. we set self that price to
this new value.
Now in another implementation instead
of raising this exception,
we could just ignore setting the
value if it's negative.
Now with these two methods in place
. we go back to our
constructor instead of directly setting the
price. Attribute. Recall Self that
set price and give
it this initial value. When
we run this program.
our data validation logic is going to
kick in. and it will throw an exception.
Take a look so
we got a value error because
price cannot be negative.
So
this was a simple solution.
But it's kind of ugly.
It's
what we consider unPythonic.
Pythonic is
one of those expressions that you hear
a lot in the python community when
we say this code or this implementation is not Pythonic, that
means it's not using Python's best practices.
It's not using
the Python language featuresto the fullest potential.
This
implementation is the kind of
code that the Java programmer, learning
python rights.
But in Python we have a better way to achieve
the same result.
That's when we use a property.
A
property is an object that sits
in front of an attribute and
allows us to get or set
the value of that attribute. Let
me show you
How to define a property here?
So in
our product class. after we
define these two methods. we
define a class attribute
with the ideal name. In
that case. we want
to call that price. Here
we call they built in property function. This
function takes four parameters
and all these parameters are
optional.
The first parameter is a function for
getting the value of an attribute.
The second parameter is
a function for setting the value of the attribute.
The third
parameter is a function for
deleting that attribute.
And the
last parameter is for documentation. In
this case. we need to
supply two arguments. The first one
is going to be get price
and the second is going to
be set price.
Know that I'm not calling these
methods. I'm simply passing
a reference to them. So
when we call the built
in property function with those arguments
. this function will
return a property object. That
property object will use
this function for reading the
value of the price attributes.
Now. by adding this
line. we can come
back to our product. Let's
set the initial price to 10 here.
When we use
the data operator. you can
see we have this price property
and we can use it
like a regular field so we
can simply print it here and we
see 10 on the terminal. and
also we can set it. But
if you set it to a negative value.
this will throw an exception. Let's
run our program.
There you go value error. So
a property looks like a
regular attributes from the outside. But
internally. it has two methods
that we call a getter and
setter. No. While this price property solved
our problem. the two methods that
we wrote are still accessible. So
if it I product dot you
can see we have get
price and set price methods. These
methods are polluting the
interface of our object as
a metaphor. Think of a remote
control with 50 buttons. Nobody likes
that kind of remote control.
It's so confusing. It's much better to
have a remote control with few
buttons that can do a lot. We
want our objects or our classes
to be the same. We want
them to have minimal number
of functions or methods exposed
to the outside. So to hide these one
solution is to come back and make
them private. But again.
this adds extra noise in
our code. There is a better.
shorter and cleaner way to
achieve the same result.
we can use a decorator. Remember decorators
Earlier we use a decorator called classmethod to
convert an instance method
to a class method. We
have another decorator for creating a property. So
instead of explicitly calling the property function to
create a property object,
we can apply the
property decorator to this method.
Then we
rename this method to the ideal name.
In this case we want to call it
price.
When Python interpreter sees this
code, it will automatically
create a property object called
Price. Similarly. we need to apply another
decorator to this method.
The name of that decorator starts
with the name of our
property in this case price and
then dot set her also. Similarly
. we need to rename this
method to price. So our implementation is
cleaner. It's less noisy.
We don't have to get underline and
set Underline. This is
much better now. How this
works internally is a little bit complicated.
and we're going to look at
that later in the future. For now.
all you need to take away is
that with these two decorators.
we can easily create a property. Now
there's one more place that we
need to modify here. and that
is our constructor because
we no longer have set
price. But the good thing is
that we can use our price property
like a regular attribute.
So we said self that
price to price with this new implementation. If
we try to create a
product with a negative price. our
code will throw an exception.
Let's take a look. There you
go. Value era now one last
thing before I finish this lecture
. When defining properties.
you don't always have to define a
getter and setter. In this case.
if we comment out
these few lines. we'll have
a read only property. so
we can only read the value
of this price. Once we set it,
we cannot change it.
so we can initially set it to. let's
say. 10. But if
we try to update it
later. we'll get an exception.
So if it's a product that
price to two and
run this program. we get
an attribute error because
we can't set that attribute.
So this is all about properties.