So in the last lecture
we defined this Mammal object.
Now
let me show you a couple
of useful built in functions.
We
have this function is instance and it
tells us if an object
is an instance of a given
class. So if you pass em and
mammal here. obviously this M object is an instance
of mammal. So when
we print the result. we
should see True. What if you pass animal
here. Let's run the program. We still get
true because mammal inherits from animal So an
instance of the mammal class is also an
animal.
Now let me show you something interesting.
This
animal class that were defined
here inherits from another class
called object, even though
we didn't add that here.
So we have a class called
object and that is the base class
for all classes in python.
So every class that we have directly
or indirectly derives from the object class.
Let
me show you.
So that's still at this and go
back to line 18.
Let's see if I
am is an instance of object.
Run
the program.
We get true.
So mammal inherits from
animal which inherits from object.
We also have this
built in function for creating an empty object.
Now
if we inspect this object you
can see all these magic methods.
These are the magic methods that
every class in python has.
So if we type m
dot you can see our mammal
class or are mammal. Object also
has these methods because
it inherited them from the
base object class. We have
another built in function that
you might find useful
in certain situations and that
is is subclass. And with
this we can see if
a class derives from another class
. So let's see if
mammal is a subclass of
animal print. The result. obviously
we get true now.
If we change animal to object, we
still get true because
mammal indirectly derives or inherits
from the object class.