Now let's look at a good example of inheritance.
Let's imagine we
want to model the concept of a stream of data.
We
can read a stream of data
from a file,
from a network or
from the memory.
All these streams have a few things in common.
We
can open them,
We can close them,
We can read data from them.
But How
we read data from a stream is
dependent upon the
type of the stream, because
reading data from a file is different
from reading it from a network.
So let's
start by defining a
base class called Stream. In
this class. I'm going to define
methods like open and close. So
do you find open now
Here. Let's say we need a flag
to know if the stream is open or
not.
So we can define a constructor. And
in this constructor we can set opened
flag initially to False.
When
we call the open method.
we can set this to True like
this.
Now what if we try to open a
stream that is already open?
That is an invalid operation.
So perhaps we want to raise an exception. So
we can check If self that opened. you
want to raise an exception.
What kind of exception. Well
we don't want to do a ValueError, because
here we're not dealing with a value.
In this example
we can create a custom exception called
InvalidOperationError;
We don't have this in Python.
In
this case we can
create a custom exception called InvalidOperation
Error,
because we don't have a built in exception in python that
represents this concept. So on the
top. let's create another class invalid
operation error.
So by convention all
custom exceptions should end with error.
Now
we want to derive this from the base Exception class
in python.
So every time you want to create a custom exception, you
should derive your class from the Exception class.
Now
here we don't need any code.
so we simply add a past statement
back to our open method.
If this dream is already open. we
want to raise an invalid operation error. and
here we can give a
friendly message like stream is
already open. So this is our open method
. Now let's define the close method
that's going to be very similar. So
to save time. I'm going
to copy this four lanes and
rename this method to close.
Now here we want to check
if the stream is already closed.
You want to raise an
invalid operation error. So if
not self that opened. we
should raise this exception and change. Their message
to stream is already closed. Finally
here with that open to thoughts.
So
these are the common features that
we need in every street.
Now
let's go ahead and
implement a file stream.
Actually
I have a type two e here.
Sorry about that. So
we define another class file stream. which in
hurts from our stream class. As
I told you before. how we read
data from a file is different from
how we read it from a network.
So I'm going to define a method called
Read and for simplicity. Let's
just print reading data from a
file. save the changes. Now
let's duplicate these few lines and create a
network stream class network stream. and
we should also change the
message to reading data from
a network.
This is a good example
of inheritance because
first of all we don't have
a multilevel inheritance, We only have
one or two levels depending on
how you want to calculate it.
So we have the Stream class on
top of our hierarchy and
below that we have two
sub classes: File and network stream.
It's okay
if we add another level of inheritance here,
but we shouldn't go
beyond that.
Also as you can see we don't have multiple
inheritance,
so our sub classes don't have multiple parents