So in the last lecture
you learn about abstract base classes.
As
another example,
here I have defined an abstract base class called
UIControl.
This class has an
abstract method called Draw.
And as you can see this
method has no implementation.
So this class only defines
the contract or
the interface that all its derivatives
should follow. Okay?
Now here we have two
classes that derive from UIControl:
one is TextBox
and the other is DropDownList.
Both these classes implement
the draw method.
Here we simply print TextBox and
in the DropDownListown class
we print DropDownListown.
So nothing new so far.
Now here we
also have a function called
draw that takes a
UIControl object and
calls the draw method on it.
So
with this I can create
a DropDownListown object drop
down list and pass
it to this draw function.
like this.
This should be perfectly fine because it drop
down list is an instance of the UIControl class.
To
verify this let's call isinstance function and
passed the studio object as
well as the control class
and then print the result on
the terminal for now. I'm going
to comment out this line.
so save the changes
and run the program.
We get true. So it
dropped down. This object is
an instance of UI control
. and that means wherever
we expect a UI control
object. we can pass any
of it's derivatives like a
text box or drop down list.
Right. So let's
delay this line and
call the draw function with
this detail object. What do you say we
see a drop down list.
Now. What if you pass a text box
of dysfunction. Let's take a look.
So I'm going to create a text
box like this and
then pass it. There is draw function. Run
the program.
This time we get text box.
I want to
ask what is the point of this?
Well let's take this to
the next level and make it more interesting.
I want to change this
draw function.
So instead of getting a control object. I
wanted to get a list or a couple of controls.
So
let's rename this to controls and
he will use a for loop to
iterate over this Controls object. So for
control and controls. we
call the draw method
and each control object. Now
we're going to pass a
list of two objects. It
drop down list and
a text box. Let's run
the program and see what happens.
As you probably expect. we
get two messages dropped
on this and textbooks. So
using this approach,
we can render the user interface of
an application.
Imagine we have a form with a bunch of
text boxes,
drop down lists, radio buttons and so on.
We could have
a list of all these
objects and pass that list to
a function like draw and
that function would take care of rendering the
entire form.
What is interesting here is that
our draw function doesn't know
what kind of control it's working
with.
This is determined at runtime.
It simply iterates
over the list of controls and
calls the draw method of
each control objects.
This is what we call Polymorphism.
Parliament's
many more means form. so polymorphism means
many forms.
In this example, our draw method is taking
many different forms and
this is determined at runtime.
We
could be calling the draw method on
a text box or
a drop down list or
a radio button and so on.
So this is the classic example of polymorphism.