What you saw in the last lecture was
the classic example of polymorphism.
So
to achieve polymorphic behavior
we start by defining a
base class and
in this class we define
the common behavior or
the common methods that
we need in distributive
or children.
With this we
achieve polymorphic behavior in
our draw function online 22.
So depending on the type of
control object that we're working with at runtime,
this draw method takes a different form.
It might be
the draw method in the text box
or a drop down list
or radio
button and so on.
So this is how polymorphism works in
pretty much all languages that
support classes.
But because
python is a dynamically typed language,
we don't necessarily need
this UIControl as the base class here.
In
other words if you get rid of this class,
let's just
delete it for now
we should also delete it
from these two places.
With this
change we can still achieve polymorphic behavior.
Why?
Here's the reason.
Look at this controls parameter.
Nowhere
here we have specified
the type of this parameter, right?
This
is purely a label, a name.
we can pass any kind of
objects to this draw function.
As long as that object is
Iterable, Python will be happy because here online
15 we are looping over that object, so
that object has
to be Iterable.
So technically we can pass a string,
a list, a topple, a dictionary
anything that is iterable
here.
By the same token that iterable object,
its individual parts,
should have a draw method.
So
Python doesn't care if these
objects derived from the UIControl
class.
As long as these objects have
a draw method, python
will be happy.
This is what we call duck typing. So
if it walks like a duck and
quacks like a duck,
it is a
duck.
That is how python works.
Because python is
a dynamically typed language and
it doesn't check the type of objects,
it
only looks for the existence of
certain methods in our
objects.
In other words in this case on line 16, itt
only looks for the existence of the draw method.
So if
this object has a draw method,
Python assumes it's a UIControl.
It's exactly like saying if
it walks like a duck and
quacks like
a duck,
it is a duck.
So to achieve polymorphic behavior
we don't necessarily need
a base class like UIControl because
Python supports duck typing.
Having said that. having
that control as an abstract base
class is a good practice because
it enforces a common interface
or a common contract across
all its derivatives.
With this will make sure that
every kind of UIControl
will have a draw method.