So you have learned that
we use classes to bundle data and functionality
into one unit.
Now as you work on larger programs, you
may come across classes that
don't have any behavior.
They don't
have any methods.
They only have data.
Here's an example.
We
have this point class that has
two attributes X and Y.
It
doesn't have any methods Now.
With this we can create two point objects
Soapy Juan.
We said it two point of one
and two and p two the same. Now
. when we compare these
two objects and print the
result. we get false because these
two objects are stored in
different locations in memory. So
by default. Python compares objects based on
where they are stored in memory.
If two variables are
referencing the same object in memory.
they are considered equal. In
this example. our point objects are
in two different locations. even though
they have the same attributes.
So to prove this
to you. I'm going to call
this built in i d function. This
returns the address of the
memory location where an object is
stored. So let's look at
the address of P one and
also P two. As you can see.
these objects are
in two different locations in memory.
So to solve the issue
with comparing point objects.
we need to come back here and
implement a magic method. E Q. This
method takes self and other.
and here we should compare self
that eggs with other that eggs and self
taught wine with other than wine. Now. when
we compare these two objects P one MP two. we
get true. so the problem is solved.
However
writing all this code fordata classes is
a little bit tedious.
If you're dealing with classes that
have no behavior, no methods,
they only have data,
you can use a named tuple instead.
Let me show you how that works.
So let's delete these.
On the
top from the collections module. we
should impart the named topple function.
We
call this function.
As the first argument, we specify the
name for this new type you want to create.
so we're going
to call that Point.
So note that I'm passing a
string here.
Now as the second argument, we pass an
array of field names or attributes names.
We
want our point objects to
have two attributes: x and y.
So this returns a named tuple that
we can store here.
Note that I'm using Pascal
naming convention because
Point here represents a type, like
a class,
so we can call it to create a
new Point object.
However instead of passing these
arbitrary values here,
we should pass keyword arguments.
So
we said x 21 and Y 22 The
first improvement here is that
our code is more clear and
less ambiguous.
We don't have to wonder what are these
values.
The point is a simple concept,
it's easy to guess
that 1 and 2 represent x and y here.
But sometimes
when creating objects,
you might have to pass some magical values and
someone else reading that code,
they don't know what these values represent.
So
these keyword arguments make our code more clear.
The
second benefit is that
we don't have to explicitly implement
a magic method to compare two objects.
So if you
have two point objects with
the exact same attributes, we
can easily compare them and
we get
the result that we expect.
So if you're working with classes that
have only data and no method,
you might want to use a
name tuple instead,
you will write less code.
And
these named tuples are better than
regular tuples because here
we'll have attributes in this Point object
just like the attributes we
have in our classes.
So if we print p1 dot
x, we see one.
Just
be aware that
these named tuples are immutable
which means
once we create them,
we cannot modify them, We cannot mutate them.
So
if I said p one dot
x to a new value and
run the program.
we get an attribute error because we
can't set an attribute of a named tuple after we
initialize it.
So if you really need to modify one of
these values,
you need to create a new Point object.
So we
said P one to a
new point with exit to 10
and y set to 2.
So this is all about named tuples.