In the last lecture you learn about
instance versus class attributes.
We have the same concept around
the methods that we define in
a class.
so we have instance method
as well as class methods.
In
this example both these methods that
we have defined in the point
class are instance methods, so we
can call them using an
instance of the point class, using
an object.
Generally speaking, you use these instance methods
whenever we need an object reference.
For example when
drawing a point we really need
to work with a specific point object.
That is why this
draw method is defined as
an instance method. But there are
times that we don't really need
an existing object and that's
when we use a class
method.
For example let's say in our
program there are a lot of cases
where we want to create a point with
these initial values zero and zero. This
is one way to create a point object.
and that's perfectly fine. But
we can come up with a different
way to create a point object with
these values.
Like this: Point.
So
note that I'm using a class reference.
then dot 0.
In
this case zero is a
method that is defined at the
class level and when we call it,
it will return a
point object initialized with these values.
So
we can get this point object and
assign it
to this point Variable.
Now in this example we
refer to this zero method
as a factory method, because
it's like a factory.
it creates a new object. This
example is pretty basic.
Creating a zero point with
these initial values is not a big deal.
but there are times that
initializing an object can
be pretty complex. So every
time you want to create an object
of a given type. you might have
to pass some magical values here. and you
might have to repeat this in
several places in your program. In
that case. instead of
passing all these magical values
to create an object. you can define a
factory method that will
return an object with these
values. And this way you
can move this complexity of
creating this object into that factory method
. Okay. so let's
delete what we have online
10 and see how we can
define a method at the class
level?
so back to our point. Glass would
define a method. called it zero and
call its first parameter cls which
is short for class.
Again this is purely convention.
we can call this
anything but by convention whenever we
define a class method,
we call its first parameter cls.
And as you can guess,
this is a reference to the class itself.
So
here we are not working with a
point object or a point instance.
Now
to make this method a class method
we need to decorate
it with something like this:
at sign classmethod.
This is what we call a decorator and
it's a way to extend
the behavior of a method or a function.
We'll look at decorators
on how they work internally
later in this section. So
this is all you have to
do to create a classmethod in
python.
Now in this class method we
have a reference to our class.
So with that
we can create a
point object with initial values.
So
we call cls and give it these initial
values.
This is exactly like calling point
of zero and zero.
The difference is that if you use cls, at
run time when we call the zero method
Python interpreter will
automatically pass a reference
to the point class to
the zero method. Okay.
So we create a
point object and then return it.
Save the changes.
Now
when we run the program
we got a point with these initial values.