We also have magic methods for
performing arithmetic operations between
two objects.
For example what if you want to add these
two points together?
when you run this program, obviously
you're going to get an error.
So back in the list of magic methods
here we have numeric magic methods in this
category. If you scroll down.
you can see normal arithmetic
operators. so we have add. subtract. multiply and
so on. So in order
to add two points together. we
need to implement the ad matter.
Sir. Define ad
with two parameters. Self and other was
simply return and you point object with
these values. Self that X plus other
dot X. That's our
first argument and then self
good wine. plus other. That's why pretty
simple. right. So let's save the changes around
the program. We get this
new point object at this address
so we don't see the actual X and Y values of this point object
. because in this example.
I removed the stir magic method
. However. if you store
the result of this arithmetic operation
in another object like combined and
then print combined that X. you
can see we get 11.
which proves that we successfully added two points together.