We're goinna start this section
by exploring comparison operators. we use
comparison operators to compare values.
Here are a few examples.
So 10 is greater than three.
We get true.
So what we have here is a boolean
expression,
because when this expression is evaluated,
we'll get a boolean value
that is True or False.
Here's another example.
Ten is greater than or equal to three.
Once again, we get true.
We also have less than 10 is less than 20.
We have less than or equal to.
Here's the equality operator.
So 10 is equal to 10.
What about this expression?
What do you think we're gonna get?
We get False, because these values have
different types and they're stored
differently in the computer's memory.
And finally, we have
the not equal operator.
So now with this expression,
we should get True, beautiful.
We can also use this comparison
operators with strings.
Let me show you so we can check
to see if bag is greater than Apple.
We get True because when we sort
these two words back comes after,
So it's considered greater.
Now, what about this one
bag equals capital back.
Yet false, here is the reason:
every character you see here has
a numeric representation in programing.
Let me show you.
So we have this built
in function called ord.
Don't worry about memorizing this because
you're probably never gonna
use this in the future.
But let me show you the numeric
representation of the letter b.
So that is 98, in contrast,
Capital B is represented as six to six,
that is the reason these
two strings are not equal.
So these are the comparison
operators in Python.
Next, we'll look
at conditional statements.