mhm. Yeah. In
programming. we have this
concept called Nested Loops so
we can put one loop
inside of another loop. And with
this. we can get some interesting results.
Let me show you. So
I'm going to start with
this loop for X in range
five. Colin. Now inside of
this loop. I'm going to
add another loop. So for why
in range three. Colin And
then in our second loop.
I'm going to add a print statement here
. We can use
formatted strings to display coordinates
. Remember Formatted strings.
So we have f followed by
quote. Now. here we add parenthesis for coordinate
. First we want to
display X and then comma. followed
by Why. Let's run
this program and see what
happens. There you go. Pretty cool. isn't
it. So we get zero
and 00 and 10 and
two. Then we get one
and 01 and 11 and two
and so on. Now let me explain.
How exactly. Python
Interpreter. execute this code. So here we have
two loops. This is what
we call the outer loop. And
this is the inner loop.
So the execution of our program starts
here in the first iteration
of this loop X zero
. Now we get to this
statement which is a child of
this four statement because
it's indented four times. This
statement itself is a loop. So what we
have inside of this
loop will be executed three
times in the first situation. X is
zero because we're still in the
first iteration of the outer loop
. And why is also zero.
Because we're in the first iteration of
the inner loop. That is
why we get zero and zero
. Now we go to the
second iteration of this inner loop. In
this situation. why will
be one whereas X is
still zero. That is why
we get zero and one and
similarly in the third iteration of
our inner loop will get zero
and two in the terminal.
Now we're done with the execution of
the inner loop. So the
control moves back to our outer
loop. Here will be in
the second iteration. so X will
be one and then
we start here again. So
we have to execute this
inner loop three times in
the first situation. Why will
be zero and X is
one. So here we have one on zero.
Then we'll get one on one and
one and two. You got the point.
So this is all about