So you have learned that we use
for loops to iterate over iterable
objects. In python We have
another kind of loop that
is a while loop. And we
use that to repeat something as
long as a condition is true.
Here's an example. So
let's define a variable
number and set it to
100. Now we use while and here
we add a condition
as long as number is
greater than zero. We had a colon. Once
again we have indentation so
we can repeat one or
more statements. We can print this number and
then we can divide it by half.
So number equals
number. Use the integer division divided
by two. Or we can
use the argument and assignment operator
to shorten this code. like this. Now
let's run this program.
So here is what we get. Initially
. our number is 100
were divided by half. We
get 50 then 25 so on. So as
you can see in this example.
we are not iterating over
an iterable like a range
object or a string or
a list. We are evaluating a condition and
repeating a task. Let me show you
a real world example of a
while loop. In this interactive shell
Python is waiting for an input.
We can type something like two plus
two. It will evaluate it
and ask for the next input
we can add another expression like
10 is greater than two. So
these steps will continue until repress control
D So behind the scene
we have a while loop that
continuous execution until we press control D
That is the condition that causes
the while loop to terminate. Let
me show you how to build
something like this in Python. So
let's define a variable command and set it
to an empty string.
Now. here we need a
wide loop. We want this
wild up to execute as
long as command does
not equal to quit. So
command does not equal to quit Colin
. And so we want to
continuously get input from the user. So
we use the built
in input function. We add
a label like this.
get the result and story it
and the command variable. Now. at this point
. Python Interactive shell will
evaluate this command. We are
not going to do that in this
lecture because that's way too complex for
simplicity. We can just echo
back what the user entered so
print echo. And as
the second argument. we pass this command. So
this is our while loop.
It will execute until we type
quit. Now, As I told you before,
don't run this
program using the code Runner extension
because by default it
will run your program in the output window
which is read only. So
open up a terminal using
control and back tick and
run python or python3
app.py. So
here's our command. Prompt less
Type two plus two. It
echoes back. Let's type three times to There
you go. If a type quit.
our program terminates
. Now let's try it one more time.
What if the type quit
an opera case. The program doesn't terminate because
. as you learn before.
lowercase and uppercase characters have
different numerical representations. So quit in
lower case is different from
quit and opera case. Now
. To solve this problem.
an amateur programmer may do
something like this. and command does
not equal to capital quit. So
while command does not equal. quit in
lower case and quit in uppercase. continue getting
input from the user Let's
run this program in terminal and
see what happens. So one more time Python
apt a pie We type Quit beautiful. It
works with type quit and upper case.
That would work too
. But what if I type
quit with an uppercase Q and
lower case. U I t.
Our program doesn't terminate
. So this is a poor
way of checking for the quit command
. What is a better way.
Let me show you. So we don't need
this and operator here instead because
command is a string we
can call the lower method
. So whatever the user
types in first. well converted to
lowercase and then compare it with quit
in lower case. With this change.
it doesn't matter how
the user types the word
quit will always terminate the