Now the last thing I want to discuss
in this section is the concept of infinite
loops. An infinite loop is
a loop that runs forever
. So if I change this condition too
true. because true is always true. this
wild loop will run forever.
So to jump out
of this. we need a break statement.
So after we get the
input from the user.
we can get the command converted
to lowercase and see
if it equals to quit
. If that's the case.
we want to break now
. With this change. we no
longer need to initialize command to
an empty string.
Previously. we needed this because we
had a wild statement
like this while command does
not equal quit. So we had to
define this command variable.
And that's why we have city to
an empty string without this line. When Python
interpreter tries to execute this code.
it doesn't know what command
is. So now that
we have an infinite loop
. we no longer need to define command
and set it to an empty string. So
. in terms of functionality.
this program is exactly the same
as the program we wrote in
the last lecture just be aware of
these infinite loops because they run forever.
You should always
have a way to jump
out of them. Otherwise your program
will run forever. And this
can sometimes cause issues. because
if you're executing operations that consume memory at