So here's an example
from the last lecture. A
person is eligible for a loan
if they have high income on
good credit on.
but they're not a student now
. One thing you need to know
about this Boolean operators is that there
are short circuit. What do I mean by that. Well
. when Python interpreter
wants to evaluate this expression
. it starts from the first argument. If
this is true. it continues
the evaluation to see if
the second argument is also true.
So it continues the
evaluation all the way to
the end of this expression. However
. as soon as one
of these arguments is false. the
evaluation stops. Let me show
you what I mean. So if
I change high income
toe false when Python interpreter
sees this expression. it starts here. It
knows that high income is false.
so it doesn't matter what comes
after. The result of this entire expression will
always be false. because at
least one of the arguments or
one of the. uh. prints is false.
This is what we call short
circuiting. Just like the short circuit concept.
We have an electron
ICS so the evaluation stops as soon as
one of these arguments evaluates toe false. We
have the same concept with
the or operator. So if
I change these and operators toe or let's
see what happens with the or operator. we
know that at least one of
the arguments should be true. So
the evaluation stops as soon
as we find an argument that
evaluates to true. In this case.
when Python interpreter it
values this expression.
it seems that high income response
. So it continues the evaluation.
hoping that the next argument
will be true here.
Good credit is true. so
evaluation stops and the
result of this entire expression
will be true. So in python, logical operators are short circuit.