mhm. Yeah. there
are times that we may want to
repeat a task a number of times. For
example. let's say we send
a message to a user If
that message cannot be delivered.
Perhaps we want to retry three
times now for simply severe. Let's imagine this
print statement is equivalent to sending a
message in the real World program.
To send a message to
a user. we have to write 5
to 10 lines of code. Now. if
you want to retry three times.
we don't want to repeat all that code
that is ugly. That's when
we use a loop. We
use loops to create repetition. So here's
how it works. We start with four number
in. We have a built
in function called range. Now
. how many times we want to
repeat this task. Let's say three times
. So we call range and
past three as an argument now
similar to our if statements.
we need to terminate this
line with a colon enter. we get invitation
. So in this block we
can write all the statements that
should be repeated three times.
Let's do a print a
message like attempt. save the changes. run
the program. So we have
attempt printed three times. Beautiful
. Now what is this number.
Let's take a look. It's
a variable of type integer. so let's
pass it as the second
argument to the print function number
. Run the program.
This is what we get. 012 So
here we have a for loop.
This for loop is executed three
times in each iteration number will have
a different value. Initially. it will be zero.
In the second iteration
. it will be one. And finally.
in the last iteration. it will be too
. Now. here we can do something fun.
We can add one
to this around the
program and now the messages
that the prints are kind of
more meaningful or more user friendly
. like attempting number one attempting
number two and so on. We
can take this to the next level
so we can pass another argument here
. I'm going to add an expression
one more time number plus one. So
we'll get 123 Now I want to put this expression in
parenthesis. So let's select this. put
it in parenthesis. and then multiply it by
a dot. So here
we have a string that
is multiplied by a number.
The result will be that string
repeated that number of times.
Let's take a look. So
around the program. see. that's pretty cool. isn't
it. Now. let me show you
one more thing before we finish this
lecture. As you saw.
this range function generates numbers
starting from zero all the way
up to this number here. But
it doesn't include this number here.
We can pass another argument
. say start from
one and finish before four
. With this change. we don't need
to add one to number every time
because in the first iteration.
this number variable will be set to
one so we can simplify
our code and make it
cleaner. Let's run it
one more time. We get
the exact same result. We can also pass
a third argument as a step.
So I'm going to change the
second argument to 10 and passed to
as a step. Look at the result. These
are the numbers we get
135 and so on. So