mhm. continuing with
the example from the last lecture.
Let's imagine the scenario where
. after the first attempt.
we can successfully send the message. In
that case. we want to jump out
of this loop. We don't want to
repeat this task of sending a message three
times. Let me show you
how to implement this. So in
this demo. I'm going to simulate
the scenario where we can successfully
send a message.
So we define a variable successful
and set it to true.
Now here. after this
print statement will have and if
statement if successful. colon then
perhaps we can print successful now
here. We want to jump out
of this loop. For that. we use
the break statement. Let's find
this program and see what
happens. So there you go. After the
first attempt. we are successful and there
are no more attempts.
So once again. I want
you to pay great attention
to the indentation here because that's
one of the common
issues amongst beginners. So here's
our for loop.
These two lines are indented with
four spaces. and they belong
to our for loop in
every iteration. These two
lines will be executed now
. when we get to line four.
If this condition is true. then
these two lines will be executed.
Because both these
lines are indented below this. If statement
Now let's take this program to
the next level. What if we
attempt three times and we
still cannot send an email. Perhaps
we want to display a different message
to the user. We say. Hey. we
tried three times.
but it didn't work. So I'm
going to change. Successful to false. Now
at the end here we
can add an else statement. This
is what we call
a for else statement. What
we put under this else
statement will only be executed if
this loop completes without an early termination. So
if we never break out
of this loop, then the
else statement will be executed.
So here we can print a
message like attempt at three times and
failed. So run the program
. see what we get.
Three attempts followed by this message attempted
three times and failed. In contrast. if
you change successful too
true because we terminate this
loop using this break statement.
What we have in
the else block will not be executed.
Take a look. Run
the program. We have one attempt successful. done