So far we have written all our
code in one file app.py.
But that's not how we build real programs,
because a real program
can contain tens of thousands of lines of code. We
don't want to write all that code in one file.
That is like going to
a supermarket without any sections.
All products are
in one place.
Finding a product in a supermarket like that is
really hard. right?
That's why in supermarkets we have
various oils or sections or departments.
We have
the same concept in programming.
So as our program grows, we
should split our code across multiple files.
We refer to
each file a module.
So a module is a file that contains
some python code.
Now here's the question.
How do
we decide what functions or what classes
we should put in what
modules?
Once again let's go back to our supermarket example.
In
a supermarket each section contains
highly related products,
so when you go to the fruit sectionyou only see fruits.
You don't
see cleaning products there. right?
By the same token a module
should contain highly related objects.
These objects can be functions
classes, variables and so on.
So here. as an
example. I have defined two functions.
These functions have
no implementation. but they are both
highly related to the concept of
sales. We have calculate
tax and calculate shipping. So
let's go ahead and put these
functions in a separate module called Sales
. Here in the Project folder.
I'm going to add and you file and call
it Sales of Pie. This
is our sales module. Note that
in terms of naming convention just
like variables and functions.
we use all lower case letters. And
if you have multiple words to
separate them using an underscore No
. back to Abdel Pie.
Let's get all this card and
move it to sales module.
Okay. Now back to
that module we need
to import one or two
functions from our sales module.
There are a couple of different ways
to achieve this. You have
seen one way before. so we
start with from then.
we add the name of our
module. which is sales. Not that
it's not sales. That pie. it's
only the name of the file.
Okay. so from sales import
now. if you press control
and space here. you can
see all the objects defined
in this module. Currently. we
have these two functions. as well
as a bunch of variables that
python automatically creates.
We'll look at this later. so
let's say you want to
import the calculate shipping function. There
you go. Now we can
call this function just like a
function that we have defined in
our APP module. So calculate shipping
as simple as that. Now.
if you want to import multiple objects from
a module. you can separate
them using a comma. So here
we can also import calculate tags and then
call it here. Now there are some
tutorials out there that
teach you a shortcut to
import multiple objects. Using an asterisk.
While
this makes your code shorter,
is actually a bad practice. because
in that module you could have
several different functions or variables and
if you blindly import them
into the current module, some
of those objects may
overwrite the objects with the
same name in the current module.
So don't import
all objects like this only
important the stuff that you need. So
let's put. calculate. shipping and calculate tax here
. There is also another
way to import a module instead
of starting with From you
start with import. and then we
add the name of the module.
Now in this module we
have an object called sales
and we can use the
dot operator to access its members. So
our calculate shipping function is now
a method in this object. and
we call it like this.
So basically. you can either import the
entire module as an object
or you can import specific
objects from that module.
What approach you choose is purely your
personal preference, there is no right or wrong here.
There's not even
a performance difference because
whenever we wanna import one object
from a module that entire module needs to be loaded.
Now we can pick one object or every object in that module.