So these are the files or modules
we're currently having in this folder.
We
have app.py which is our main module
or the entry point
to our program.
As well as the sales module.
Now when
I run this program, you will
see a new folder here. So
python app dot py.
There
you go.
We have this new folder __pycashe__ and
in this folder we have
the compiled version of the
modules that we import into our program.
So currently
we have the compiled version of the sales module.
The
reason Python Stores this compiled
files in this folder is
to speed up module loading.
So next time we run our program Python
will look at the content of this folder and
if we do have the
compiled version of the sales module,
Python will simply load
that compiled version.
So it will skip that compilation step,
and this will result in
faster loading of the sales module.
Note that it only speeds up
the loading of this module, not
the actual performance of the application.
Now How does python
known If this compiled version
is up to date with the
latest code in the sales module?
Well it basically checks
the date time of these two
files, the compiled version as
well as the source code,
If the daytime of this source file is
newer, it realizes that our
source code is changed.
So
it will recompile it and
store it in this pycashe folder
So that's the basic idea.
Now this cpython-37 you
see in the file name here
represents the python implementation used
to compile this file.
So we have compiled this file using C
Python version 3.7.
In this file
we have python byte code.
Let me quickly show you. So
when we click this, by default
VSCode doesn't show the content
of this file because it's binary.
But if you click this link here
we can see the Python byte code representation of
ourselves module.
Now back to this
__pycashe__ folder,
note that we don't have the compiled version of
the app module because
python always recompiles
the module that we load directly
from the command line.
So in
this demo,
I passed the app.py as
the entry point to python,
and that's the reason
python didn't cash the compiled version of this module.