So here in app.py
I'm currently importing the sales module.
When
Python sees this,
it will look for a file called sales dot
py in the current directory.
If it doesn't find
this file,
it will look in a bunch of
predefined directories that
come with python installation.
Let me show you.
So
we have a built in module called path.
Let's import that.
In this module we have a variable path which
returns
the list of directories that
Python will look at to find a
module.
Let's print this on the terminal.
So
as you see, we get
an array of strings.
The
first element in this array
represents the current folder, so
on my machine that is mashfeghhamedani slash
Dropbox Courses Python blah blah blah.
On your machine
is going to be different.
After that we have Library Frameworks
Python.framework Versions 3.7 da da da da da.
This is going to be different
on your machine depending on
your operating system.
I'm
using Mac, so this is
the address of python installation on
Mac OS.
On Windows you're probably going to get something like
C drive Backslash program files Python.\ blah
blah blah.
So when Python sees an import statement
it will search
all this directories to find this module.
As soon
as it finds the module,
the search stops there.
Now
you might be curious
How we can import a module from a subdirectory?
Well
to do that we need to look at packages and
that's the topic for the next lecture.