Currently all our files or modules are
in this folder.
But as our application
grows, we probably want toorganize these files
into subdirectories,
otherwise
we'll end up with hundreds
or even thousands of python files or
python modules in one folder.
That is not good.
So in this demo I want to
move the sales module to
a subdirectory called
ecommerce.
So I'm going to add a new subdirectory e
commerce and then
drag and drop this module right
here.
Now back to app.py.
You can see we have a
red underline here because
Python cannot find
a sales module.
To fix this issue, we should come back
to our ecommerce folder
and add a new file called
double underscore init double underscore dot
py.
When we add this file here python would
treat the ecommerce foller
as a package.
So
a package is
a container
for one or more modules.
In
file system terms a package
is mapped to a directory and
a module is mapped to a file.
So now we
can go back to app dot py and
prefix the
name of this module with the
name of its package, that is e
commerce dot sells.
Save the changes.
The
error is gone.
Now to use any of the objects in the sales module,
we need to prefix them with
the name of their package
and modules.
So
ecommerce dot sales dot calculate tax.
Obviously this is going to make our code
a little bit noisy because
every time
we want to use one of the
objects in the sales module will have
to type ecommerce dot sales dot.
That is
tedious.
A better approach is to use the from statement.
So we changed this to
from ecommerce dot
sales import calculate tax.
Now
we can simply call this
function like a function defined in
app module.
That is better.
But what if you want to use
multiple objects in the sales module?
Well we
can list them all here.
But if that ends
up being too noisy,
we can take a different approach.
So we
can type
from ecommerce import sales.
So we're importing the sales
module as an object and then
we can use the dot operator to
access all the members of this module.