As your programs grown,
you may want to
break down a package into sub
packages.
For example let's imagine our
ecommerce package has grown a lot.
We have so many files and modules
here. So we decided to break
this package into a few sub
packages.
So I'm going to
add a new folder here
call it shopping.
And then move the
sales module in this folder.
So
on the top we have the ecommerce package and
under that we have
the shopping package.
Now currently shopping is not a package because
in this folder we don't have
the init file.
So
let's add a new file double underscore init
double underscore dot py.
Now
back to app dot py
Once again python cannot find our sales
module.
So to fix this issue, we need to add the
name of our new sub package here.
so ecommerce dot shopping.