There are times that you want to
import modules from sibling packages.
For
example here in our ecommerce package
I have added a
new sub package customer in this package. we
have this contact module
for contacting our customers.
Now
let's say in our sales module
we want to use the
contact module in the customer package.
Let me show you how
to do this.
So we open this.
To import
a module from another package,
we can use an absolute or
relative import statement.
So, here
is an absolute import:
from our top level
packages eccommerce, so we start there, then
we go to the customer sub package and
now we import
the contact module.
So this
contact object has a method
we can use anywhere in
this module.
So this is the absolute importance.
We
can also use a relative import.
So from
dot this represents the current package,
dat dat
takes us one level up,
so now we're at the ecommerce package
level.
In this package we have two sub packages:
customer and
shopping, so we can go to
the customers sub package and
then import the contact module.
As
a best practice prefer to use absolutely imports, and
that's what pep
eight also recommends.
But if your absolutely import gets really verbals
like a.b.c.d.e , then you
might be able to simplify the import statement
by using a relative import.