In this lecture we're going to look at
a powerful built in function called dir.
With
this function we can get the
list of attributes and methods defined
in an object.
So in this example
we're importing the sales module
as you learned earlier.
Now sales is an object, so we
can use the dot operator
to access all the methods and
attributes defined in this object.
As you work on large projects
there are times that things don't work as you expect,
so you can use the dir
function for debugging.
Let me show you.
So let's
print dit of sales.
When
we run this program, we get
an array of strings in
this array.
We have all the attributes and methods defined in
an object.
So as you see in our sales module, we have these
two functions calculate shipping and tax as
well as these magic attributes
that are automatically created for
us.
Let's take a look at a few of these.
so I'm
going to comment out this line and
print sales dot
name,
that returns the name of our module.
We
can also get name of the package,
as
well as the file name, as well as
the address of its file. So
let's run this program. So here
is the name of our module. As
you can see,
it's fully qualified with the name of its packages.
After
that we have the name of our package.
So the sales module is
defined in ecommerce dot shopping package,
and
below that we have the path to this file and file system