Here in our sales module
currently we have defined two functions.
But
we can also write any statements and
these statements will be executed the
first time this module is loaded.
So if you import this
module in a few different modules in our program,
python will load
this module only once and
then cash it in memory, so
the statements that be write
here will be executed once.
As
an example let's print something like sales
initialized.
Now let's go back to our app module.
To quickly look up a file,
you can press command and p on Mac or
control and p on windows.
Here we can type app dot
py.
There we are.
Now when we run this program you
can see our sales module is initialized.
Using the same technique
we can write the initialization code for our packages.
So
once again. command and pee
on Mac or control and pee
on Windows. We can go
to the input file for
the e commerce package and print e
commerce initialized. Now
let's go to R ap module.
Run the program again. As
you see first our ecommerce package and
then the
sales module are initialized.
Now let's take this to the next level.
Let's go to our sales module and
print the
name of this module.
So as you learn in the last lecture every
module has a built inname attribute
that is automatically
created for us. So save the changes back
to APP module. Let's run our program. So
as you see here is the name
of our module that is ecommerce dot
shopping dot sales.
However if
we go to sales dot py and
run this file, the
name of our module has changed to main.
So
the name of the module that
starts our program is always main.
Now
we can do something interesting.
Let me show you. So I'm gonna delete
this initialization code on the top. After we
define his functions. I'm going to
write some code like this. If
name equals main with two
underscores. I'm gonna print sales
started and then call the calculate tax
function.
With this code we
can make this file usable as a
script as well as a reusable module
that we can import into another module.
So if we
run this file directly,
the name of this module will be main, and
here we can have any initialization
code or we can call one
of the existing functions in this module.
However if
we import this module into another module,
this code will
not be executed because
at that point the name of this module will
no longer be main,
it will be e commerce dot shopping dot sales.