As you build various classes, you may
notice that some of these classes might
have one or more features
or functions in common. Here
is an example.
I'm going to create a class called mammal. All
mammals should be able to eat. right?
So let's define a
function called eat and
in this function would simply
print it Now. All mammals
. As far as I know.
I should be able to walk. So let's
define another method walk and
in this method with print walk. Now I'm
going to select all this
code and hold down Shift Ault
and Down Arrow to duplicate this class. No
. let's rename your
second class fish. As we
know all fish should be
able to eat. But fish
don't walk. They swim. So let's change the
second method to swim.
as well as this message that
we print. No. what is going
on here. As you can see.
we have repeated or duplicated
the eat method in both these classes.
Now
in this implementation are eight.
Method is only a single line of
code. but in the real world program.
you might have a method that
is five or 10 lines of code.
and you might have repeated that
in multiple classes. This is
bad because if there is
a bug in one of these methods.
you have to fix it in multiple places.
Or
similarly if you need to
change the behavior of this method then
again you have to do it in multiple places.
In programming we
have this concept called DRY
which stands for Don't Repeat
Yourself.
so we don't want to repeat ourselves to solve this
problem.
We have two solutions:
We can use inheritance or
composition.
In this lecture we're going to look at inheritance.
And
I'm going to talk about composition later in this section.
Inheritance
is a mechanism that allows us
to define the common behavior or
common functions in one
class and then inherit them
in other classes. Here's how it works.
So I'm going
to define a separate class called Animal and
then move the eight
method in this class like
this. Now you can
see our mammal classes simpler
. so to have it
inherit, the eat method, from
the Animal class. we simply add parenthesis here
and then specify the animal class. This is
inheritance in action.
We say the mammal class
is an Animal, so it inherits all
the features or all the
methods of the Animal class.
In
this situation we refer
to the Animal class as
the Parent or Base class and
Mammals
as the Child or Subclass. So
let's go ahead and apply
the same change on the fish
class. We get rid
of the eat method and
at animal as the base class. Now
when we create a mammal object
like m, you
can see this mammal has
both eat and walk
methods. So let's call it run the
program. We see this message
on the terminal so this verifies
that are mammal class inherits from the animal class.
Now
this inheritance is not limited to methods.
We can also inherit
the attributes of a base class.
for example. back
to our animal class.
I'm going to define a constructor. And
in this constructor. let's set age to
one. Now when we create a Mammal
object our Mammal object will automatically have the
age attribute initialized to one. Let me
show you so back here. Let's
print em that age. There you
go. Run the program. Here's
a result. So this
is the basic of inheritance
now. in real programs.
we don't build Animals or Mammals or
Fish.
on this we're building a game.
But I use this as an
example because it's easier
to understand the relationship between
a Mammal and an Animal.
Later in this section
I'm gonna give you a real world
example of inheritance in our programms.