In this example our Animal class
has this constructor where we
initialize the age attribute to one.
What If
you want to add a constructor
to the Mammal class and initialize its
weight?
Let's do that and see what happens?
So to
save time I'm going to
copy these two lines and
then paste them into mammal class. Now
. instead of the age attribute.
I'm going to set the weight attribute
to To with this. Let's
print em that age as well as
M that weight run the program began
. Attribute error because
mammal object has no attribute
. H. The reason this
happened was because this constructor
in the animal class was not executed.
In other
words this constructor that we
define in the Mammal class replaced
the constructor in the base class.
This is what we call method
overriding. So we are overriding or replacing a
method in the base class.
Now what if we still want
to execute this constructor and initialize the age
of an animal?
That's very easy.
Here in the constructor of
the mammal class we can
use the built in super function
to get access to the super
or base class which is in this
case animal.
So you have an access to the animal class
dot,
now we can call any of the methods in this
class. So let's go
ahead and call the innit
method Now to see the execution flow. I'm
going to add a print
statement here and print mammal
constructor. Similarly. here
in the constructor of the animal.
I'm going to print animal constructor
. Let's save the changes and run
the program to see what happens. As
you can see first. the constructor
of the animal was called. So
here we set the age to one.
Then the constructor
of the mammal was called
where we said the way to
to and finally we print one and two
. which are the results
of these two statements. Now
we can also change the order
of this method calls so we
can call the constructor of
the animal after we initialize
a mammal object. So here in
the mammal class. instead of calling Super that
in its first. we're going
to do it. After we do
all the basic work in
the mammal constructor. let's save
the changes and run the program.
As you can see. the
constructor of mammal was called
first and then we have the
constructor of the animal.
So to recap
method overriding means
replacing or extending
a method defined in the base class.
In this implementation
. we're extending the innit method
that we have defined in the
animal class. Because here
we do some work in
the constructor of the mammal and
then we call the constructor of
the animal.
If we didn't have this line here,
this
implementation would completely replace
the init method in the animal class.