So you have seen that inheritance is a good thing.
It prevents code
duplication and allows us to reuse code.
For
example here we have this bird
class that inherits from the animal, so
it inherits all the features
of this animal class.
In
this case we're reusing the eat Method here.
That's pretty
good.
However too much of a good thing is a bad thing.
And that's very true about inheritance because too
much inheritance between classes
can increase complexity and
introduce various kinds of issues.
Let me show you an example.
Here
I'm going to define a class called Chicken.
Well
a Chicken is a bird.
so we can inherit it from the
Bird class.
And here I'm going to use the pass statement to
define an empty class.
So as I've told you before. Pass
is a statement that doesn't do anything.
We just use it to make Python interpreter
happy because we cannot
have a class without anything
in it. We need to have
at least one statement. So here we
have the pass class.
But there is a problem in this code.
What is the problem?
Well the Chicken class inherits
all the features of the bird class.
But
the chicken cannot fly.
So with this implementation, I
can create a Chicken object and
call the fly method at it. So
this is an example of inheritance abuse.
Another
example of inheritance abuse
is around the concept of
employees and
I've seen that a lot in my career.
So some
people saying:
well an employee is a person and
a person is a living creature which
is a thing blah blah blah.
This is what we call
multilevel inheritance which
can significantly increase the
complexity of your software.
To tell you a little story in
one of my previous jobs,
we had this consultant and he was charging like
$150 an hour or more
and he came up with a huge inheritance
hierarchy like this.
In fact three times bigger than this.
There
were so many levels and
he essentially tried to model the entire
universe.
This is really really bad.
Just
because an employee is a person and the
person is a LivingCreature in the real world,
doesn't mean you
should have classes like this in your software.
The methods you
add in your classes
are there
to solve a business problem,
that
is the focus of your software.
So just because an animal can eat
in the real world,
doesn't mean your animal class should also have the
eat method.
You got the point, right?
So this is multilevel inheritance
and you should avoid it at all times.
If you want to use inheritance, limited
to one or two levels.
Going beyond that?
trust me,
your'e gonna shoot yourself in the food.