In Python a class can have multiple base classes.
So here
we have this manager class
that has two base classes: Employee
and Person,
This is what we call multiple inheritance and
similar to multilevel inheritance
it's a source of issues.
If
you don't use it properly,
you're going to introduce all sorts of bugs
in your programs.
Let's take a look at an example.
So
in this employee class we
have a great method and
in this method was
simply print employee greet. Our
person class also has
the exact same method. but
here we print a different message.
Now our manager class
currently has no implementation. It simply inherits all
the features of the
person and employee classes. Now
let's see:
what happens when we create a manager object and
call the great method?
Which great method do you think is
going to get called?
Let's take a look. So I'm
going to define a manager and called
manager that great. Let's run the
program. We get employee greed because
we added the employee class first.
So when Python interpreter
tries to execute this line,
first it looks at
the manager class to see if
it has a method called greet,
if
it doesn't, it will look
at its first base class,
Does
the employee have a great method?
Yes, So the look up terminates
here.
If the employee class
doesn't have the greet method, then
it will look at the person class.
So why is this an issue?
Because
if tomorrow another programmer joins
our team and for whatever
reason they decide to change the
order of these base classes, our
program will have a different behavior.
So if they move
this person class over here and
run the program.
Now we get a different output.
so similar to multilevel inheritance,
multiple inheritance can
create all sorts of issues in your programs.
You will end up
with classes that inherit features that they shouldn't,
like a chicken
that flies.
So if multiple inheritance is a bad
thing, why does python support it?
Well multiple
inheritance is not always a bad thing.
It's bad if you don't
use it properly.
If these classes that we have here, they
are small classes and they
have absolutely nothing in common
and you want to inherit their features in a separate class,
that's perfectly fine
to use multiple inheritance.
Things start to get complicated when
these classes have things in common,
like the greet method here.
So let me show you
a good example of multiple inheritance. Here
. We could have a
class called Flyer. It's any object
that knows how to fly.
So let's I fly here
So it's a very simple abstract concept.
Similarly
we could have another class called Swimmer.
It's
an object that knows how to swim.
Now
as you see, these two classes are
very small and abstract.
They
have nothing in common.
Now we can combine the features of
these two classes so we
can create a FlyingFish that
knows how to fly,
how to swim.
So it's a
Flyer and also a Swimmer.
This is a good example of a multiple inheritance.