We're going to continue with the example from the last lecture.
There are
a couple of issues with this implementation.
The first issue is that
we can create a Stream object and
called the open method.
Why is this an issue?
Because
this Stream class is an abstract concept.
What
does it mean to open a stream?
Are we working with the file stream here
and network stream? What kind of stream?
So we shouldn't be able to directly
create an instance of the stream class. We
should always sub classes and then create an
instance of the subclass,
that is the first issue.
So
we only created this stream class as a base class
to provide some code that
we're going to reuse across different
kinds of streams. This is the first issue.
Now the second issue.
If you look at the implementation of FineStream and
NetworkStream classes,
you can see both these classes have
a read method.
If tomorrow we decided to create a different
kind of stream, we should remember to implement this
read method and call it exactly
read if we call it read_line
or read_SDR or read whatever it's not
going to be consistent with
the other kinds of streams that
we have here.
In other words currently there is no way
to enforce a common interface across different
kinds of streams.
This is more of a convention we have used here.
It
would be nice to have a
common contract or common interface across
these different types of streams.
So how can we
solve these problems?
That's when we use an abstract base
class.
An abstract base class is like a half baked
cookie.
It's not ready to be eaten.
It's half baked.
It's
half cooked.
Its purpose is to provide some common code
to its derivatives.
So here we want to make this stream
class an abstract base class. To
do that. we go
on the top and from
ABC module. which stands for abstract base
class. we import the ABC class and
abstract method function. which
we're going to use as a decorator.
So make sure to type this
exactly like what you see here.
So the name of the module is all
lower case and
the name of the class is all upper
case. Now. to make
this stream class abstract. we
should derive it from
the ABC Class, Abstract Base
Class. Okay? that is the first step.
The second step
is to define the common interface for all streams.
We
want all streams to have a
read method and potentially a write
method in the future. So here
we define read method. This
method has no implementation. so we simply pass
here. Now we need to
decorate this method with abstract method decorator
With these two simple steps,
we fix both the problems I
talked about in this lecture.
So now if I save
the changes
and try to run
the program,
you can see we immediately have this red underline with
abstract methods instantiated.
Basically when
a class has an abstract method,
it's considered an
abstract class, and
we cannot instantiate them which means
we cannot create an instance of them.
So when
we run this program.
we get this type error. Okay
Now let's look at the second problem.
So let's say
tomorrow we're going to create a
new kind of stream recorded memory
stream. and we drive it
from the stream class For
now. Let's just pass and create a memory
stream. Object.
Once again you can see we have a
red underline.
abstract class with abstract methods
instantiated.
what's going on here?
In our
stream class we defined an abstract method called
read. Let's take a look.
Here's our abstract method
If a class derives from the Stream class,
it has to implement
this method.
Otherwise that class will also be considered abstract.
So in this example our new class Memory
Stream is also abstract.
If you want to make this a concrete class,
so we can instantiate it,
we'll have to implement the
read method. so define read. and
here we print reading data from a memory
stream.
Now this memory stream
is a concrete class.
We can instantiat it here and
it also follows the contract
or the interface of
the Stream class.
So all our Streams now have a read method.