All right.
Now let's see
how we can create a point class in Python?
So
we start with a class keyboard.
Then we give our
class a name like point.
Note
that here I'm using
Pascal naming convention which is
different from the naming convention
that we use for naming our
variables and functions to name
our variables and functions.
We
use all lower case
letters and we separate multiple
words using an underscore.
But to name our classes we
use a different convention
which is called Pascal naming
convention.
And basically it says that
the first letter
of every word should be uppercase and we
shouldn't use an underscore to separate multiple words.
Here is an example.
We can call this class MyPoint.
You
can see that the first letter
of every word is upper case and
there is no underscore here. Okay. so let's
change this back to point.
After this we add a colon to
indicate a block.
In this block we'll define
all the functions related to points.
For example
we can define functions for drawing a point,
for moving this
point to a new location,
or getting the distance from
this point and another point.
Here's an example.
We
define a function called draw parenthesis.
Now
all functions in our classes
should have at least one
parameter and
by convention we call that parameter self.
You will see what this is in a minute.
So bear with me. Now
we add our colon
and let's just print the
war draw under terminal.
So now we have a class
or a blueprint for creating point objects. Every
point object that we create
will have this draw method. Let's
take a look. So to
create a point object.
we call this class like a
function.
There you go.
Now this returns a
point object that we can
assign to a variable like
point. So if we use the dot operator,
you can see we have the draw
method as well as a bunch of other
methods that we didn't define
but our point object got these
methods from another object in python through a
mechanism called inheritance.
We'll look at that later in
this section. No if it print type
of point. Now let's run
this and see what we
get. We get a class of
Maine that point.
This __man__ you see here
is the name of our module. and we're
going to look at that later in this
section. So this is the
type function that you have
seen before.
We have another useful function called
isinstant.
Sometimes we have an object and
we want to know if this
object is an instance of a
given class. So let's see if
this point object is
an instance of the point
class. Now let's print the
result on the terminal
and run our program. So
obviously this point object is an
instance of our point class. However. if
it changed this to end. obviously our
point object is not an
instance of the end class
. So when we run this program.
we get false
. So this is how
we create custom classes in python
. So far. so good.
But our point objects need
some initial values like X and y.
To
set these values we need a constructor.
And that's the topic for the next lecture.