In Python we can also use inheritance
with the built in types.
For
example.
we can create a class context and having
been heard from
the built in string class.
With
this our text class will
inherit all the features of
python strings.
But we can also add additional features to
it.
For example we can
add the ability to summarize it
or duplicated and so on.
So let's define
a method called duplicate that takes self and
in this method we'll simply return self plus
self.
So let me explain what's going on here.
As
I told you before, self represents the current object which
is in this case an instance of a string class.
So
here we're contaminating a string with itself.
Now
we can easily use
our text class. So let's
add python store.
The result in this variable look
. Our text object has
all the methods of python strings
so we can convert it
to lower case and printed. And
here's the result. But we
can also duplicate it. Sir. when
we duplicated. we get a new string. which
is Python Python. pretty useful. right. As another
example. we can also extend python lists So
let's define in your class. Call it
trackable list that it hurts from
the built in list class.
Now. here I want to override the
append method. So every time we
want to append an object to this list.
we want to print a message on
the terminal. perhaps for logging. So let's
print a pant called Now
we want to call the open
method of the super class the base
class. So we call super dot append
and pass this object.
So here technically we're
extending the append method of the list class,
We're not
replacing it. Okay. No. We can
create a list object using trackable list called
append method.
And when we run this
program,
you can see this message on the terminal.
So
as you see extending building types in python
is really easy.