So here when we create a point object
we want to supply initial
values for X and Y coordinates.
Like this:
1 and 2.
To achive this we need a
constructor,
which is a special method that is called when
we create a new point object.
Let me show you how to create
a constructor.
So in our point class we
define a new function.
The name of this function should
be double underline init double underline.
This
is a special method that
we call a magic method.
In
python classes we have
several magic methods and you're
going to learn more about them
throughout this section.
So this magic
method is called a constructor and
it's executed when
we create a new point object.
Now earlier I told you
that all the methods that we
defined in the class should have
at least one parameter
which we call self by
convention.
You will see what this is shortly.
So
we add self and then
optionally we add any additional parameters
for initializing a point object, like x and
y.
Now what is this self?
self
is a reference to the current point object.
For
example, here on line nine when we call
the Point class,
Python will internally create a point
object in memory and set self to reference
that point object.
Now this point object has
a bunch of methods that you have seen before,
for example when we
use the dot operator,
you can see all the
methods in this point object.
But an
object can also have attributes
which are basically variables
that include data about that object.
For example
we can have attributes
like X and y that we
can easily print on the terminal.
In
other words a class
or an object bundles data,
and functions related to that
data into one unit. Once
again as a metaphor. think of a human.
A human can have
attributes like eye color. height. weight and
so on. as well
as functions like walk. talk
and so on. Okay.
so back to our constructor. you
learn that self is a
reference to the current object. so
we can use that to set
the X and Y attributes like
this self that eggs.
We can set it to
some default value.
like zero or this X argument
that we receive in this method. Similarly. let's
set self that. Why do why now
. With this code.
When we use the dot operator. look
. we have to draw method as
well as the two new attributes X
and Y. so we
can simply print point at
Exxon Terminal. Let's take a look around this
code. As you can see.
X is one no
back to our draw method.
Here again. we have this self parameter
So using this we have a
reference to the current point object. And
with that we can read the X and Y values and print
them on the terminal.
So here I'm going to change this implementation
and pass a formatted string like this point
parenthesis. Here I want to pass self dot
X. then comma and then self. That's
y.
So using self we can read
attributes of the current object
or we can also call other
methods in this object. Now let's change line
11 and simply call point dot draw.
Save the changes.
Run the program.
And this
is what we get now.
What is interesting here
is that when calling the draw method
we didn't have to supply a
value for the self parameter
because Python does that by
default.
Now technically we could come back here
and pass this point object as a reference to
the current object,
but this is really unnecessary and
it makes our code busy or noisy, so
here's what you need to take away.
The methods that we define in a class
should have at least one parameter
which by convention is
called self.
And this references the current point object
that we're working with when
calling methods of an object.
We
never have to supply a value for this parameter,
Python interpreter does that for us.