So in the last lecture we
defined two attributes for our
point objects in the constructor of the point class.
So
now whenever we create a new point object,
this point
object will have these attributes by default.
We can
also define an attribute
after we create a point
object.
So here we can
set point dot z to
10, because
objects in python are dynamic, similar
to javascript,
So we don't have to define all the attributes in
a constructor,
We can define them later whenever we need.
Now
here's what is important for you to understand:
all these attributes we
have defined so far x, y and Z,
these
are instance attributes.
In other words
these are attributes that
belong to point instances or
point objects.
So every point object can have different
values for these attributes.
Here is an example. We
have one point object with these values. We
can create another point. object with
different set of values and then draw
that una terminal. Let me run this. You
can see we have two point
objects and these are completely independent
of each other.
Each point has its own attributes
just like John and Mary
can have different eye collars.
So
these are instance attributes.
But we can also
define class attributes and
these are attributes that
we define at the class level and
they are the same across
all instances of a class.
As a metaphor
we can say all humans have
two eyes and two ears.
So
these are the attributes that we
define at the class level and
they are shared by all instances.
So after
a point example here we can define a
class level attribute in the
body of this class like
this default_collar.
Now
for simplicity, I'm using a string here
because we don't want to worry about using
color objects. That's a different story.
So now we
have a class level attribute.
and we can read this via
a class reference or an object reference.
Let me show you what
I mean.
So here online 12
we have a point object.
We can use this object reference
to get access to
the default_color attribute and then print it.
But
we can also use the Point class to
get access to this attribute.
Let's print both of
them and
run our program.
so we
get red and red.
As I told you
before. class attributes are shared across
all instances of a class. So here before
we printed the fault collar.
If I change. point
that default color to. let's say yellow. note
that here online 11.
I'm using a class reference. so
I'm not working with any point objects.
I'm working with the point class
now. When we run this program.
you can see that
the default color of this point object it's
changed to yellow. Similarly. here we
have another point object if it print another
default color. The
value of this attribute
has also changed. So class
level attributes are shared across all instances of
a class. If we change their value.
the changes visible
to all objects of that type now
. in practical terms.
you will be using instance attributes
most of the time. But there
are times that you may want to
define a class level attribute
that is shared across all objects of a given type.