Throughout this course
I've mentioned magic methods a few times.
These
are the methods that have
two underscores at the beginning and
end of their name
and they're called automatically by
Python interpreter depending on how
we use our objects and
classes.
For example here we
have this __init__ magic method. We
don't directly call it.
It's called automatically by Python interpreter
when we create a new point object.
Now we
have quite a few magic methods in Python.
Over the next few
lectures. you're going to learn about the key ones.
But if you want to see the
complete list. simply search for python 3 magic
methods Look at this first page here.
a guide to
Python's magic methods.
I really like this documentation. It's
actually better than pitons documentation itself. On
this page you can see
various magic methods in different categories with
examples. For example.
look at the category of representing
your classes. These are the
magic methods that we have in
this category.
The first one ster is a
really useful one and
this is called when we try to convert
an object to a string.
Let me show you how it works so
back to our code. We have
this point object. If we print this
on the terminal.
see what we get.
We
get the name of our module
followed by the class name and
the address of this point Object in memory.
This is the default
implementation of the str magic
method in our point object.
So if it I point dot
you can see all magic methods
that are available in our point object.
We didn't explicitly create these methods.
Our point object inherited
them from another object,
This is what we call inheritance and
you're going to learn about that soon.
Now in this list you can see we
have this str method.
So by default this
returns the name of the
class of this object followed by
its memory address.
Now let's reimplement this method
to get a better result So delayed
back to our class Let's define this
stir method So 200 scores stir to
underscore Now. just like before. the first parameter
should be self. Now here
we should simply return a
string representation of this point object. So
I'm going to return a
formatted string in this string. I'm
going to add parenthesis first we add self
dot eggs than comma self that
why save the changes now when
we print this point of Jack. this
is what we get.
This is very useful. We get
the same result if you
also try to convert a
point object to a string
using the str function.
So
look.
We get the same result.
So
in it and stir are
examples of two useful magic
methods in python.
Over the next few lectures,
you're going to learn about other useful magic methods.