There are times that we need to compare two objects.
For example here
we have this point object.
If I define another point object
with the exact same values
then compare
them and print the
result, What do you think we're going to get?
Let's take a
look.
We get False.
What's going on here?
The
reason we get False is that
by default this equality operator
compares the references or addresses of these two
objects in memory.
In this case these two variables are
referencing to different objects in memory and
that's why they're
not equal.
To solve this problem we need a
magic method.
That magic method is called when we compare two
objects. So back to this page here
we have comparison magic methods. Let's
take a look. So these are
all the magic methods we have for
comparing two objects.
for example. we have EQ for
testing equality. We also have any which is
short for not equal. We have L t.
which is short for less
than greater than and so on. So back
to a point class.
we need to define e
que magic method.
On that page. we can see
that this method requires two parameters self and
other. Now. in this method.
we need to return
true if these two
objects are equal. otherwise false
. So we can write
an expression like this self that
X equals other than eggs and self
that wine equals other than why. So
if this expression is evaluated to true. these
two objects are considered equal. Now let's
save the changes. We run our program
one more time. and we get true
Beautiful. Now what if
you want to compare these
two point objects like this if point is
greater than other. we run the program. We
get a type error because the
greater than operator is not supported
based on instances of
the point class. So to
solve this problem. we need to define another
magic method. So define G t
. which is short for greater
than once again. We have two
parameters self and other and write some code
like this. Return Self dot X is greater
than other that X and self that y
is greater than other. that why save the
changes. Now. Let's modify this
value So I'm going to
change the X and y
of the first point
to 10 and 20 So
the first point is greater
than the second point. Let's run
the program. We get true beautiful.
What if we
change this to less
than run the program. We
get false. So as you see
you don't have to explicitly implement
each of these operators,
when you implement the greater than
magic method Python would
automatically figure out
what to do if you use less than operator.