Earlier in the course you learn about
the common data structures in python. You
learn about lists.
sets. dictionaries and so on. These
data structures or container types are pretty useful
and sufficient for most cases.
But there are times that
you want to create your own custom container types.
For
example here we have this class TagCloud.
We're going to implement this
from scratch together.
With this class we can keep
track of the number of various tags on a block.
For
example, How many articles do we have that are tagged with python or
JavaScript and so on?
So because this class represents a
container, it supports various operations around
containers.
Here are a few examples.
Let me create
an object. Okay.
Now because this
is a container, we can get the
number of items in this container.
We
can also get an item by its key.
For
example we can get the number of articles tagged with
python.
We can also set that and finally
we can iterate over this container.
So for tag in
cloud we can print each tag in cloud.
These
are the operations that are
supported by this custom container
type.
So let me show you how to implement a
class like this.
We create a class called it
TagCloud.
Now internally we're going to use one
or more of the built-in data structures
like lists, dictionaries
and so on. In this case.
I'm going to use a dictionary because it
allows us to quickly get
the number of given tax. So
first we define a constructor self
. and in this constructor we initialize tag's
attribute to an empty dictionary. Now
we can optionally add
a method like add that
takes a tag. Now here we
should check to see if we
have this tack in our dictionary.
If we don't have it. we're going to
set its value to one.
Otherwise. we're going to increment it
by one. Here's one way
to implement this logic so
self. The tags.
We use the get method to
get an item by this key and
supply a default value.
If we don't have that now
we get the count incremental by one.
And finally we
set the value for
this key so self. the
tags of tag. We set it
to this new value. Okay. let's test our
program up to this point.
so I'm going to create the
cloud object and then call the
add method a few times.
Let's add python three
times and then print cloud of the
tags. Save the changes. Run the program. So
in our dictionary we have
one key value pair python set
to three. Beautiful.
Now you might be wondering why
I created a custom class
instead of using a plain old
dictionary?
The reason for this is because I want to make
this a little bit smarter
than a typical dictionary. What
if we add a python
tag with the capital P. Technically
. this is the same tag
as a lower case python. So
when we run this program.
we should see one python tag repeated
three times. Let's run the program.
That's not what we
get. We get two separate items.
This is how a typical dictionary
behaves. So in this class. I'm
going to take care
of case sensitivity. Whatever time
we receive here. we're going
to convert it to lure a
case when setting in as
well as when reading it
. Now. save the changes.
Run the program one more time. The
problem is gone.
Beautiful. So with this class your
encapsulating the complexity around the case sensitivity
of tags. When using this class.
we no longer have to worry
about lowercase or uppercase characters. So our code
looks cleaner and simpler.
All that complexity is encapsulated
in the tight cloud class.
It's not visible to the rest of our
program. Okay. now let's take
this to the next level. I
want to be able to read the
account of a tag like this using
square brackets.
To do this we need to implement a
magic method called __getitem__. So define
get item. It should take
self as well as a
key in this case tag
and this method. We're going
to return self the tags that
get this tag. and if we
don't have it. we want
to return zero by default. And
once again. we should convert
this to lower case. As
we can see. with this implementation.
we can easily get the number of
a given tax. We can't do
this with a typical dictionary if
we don't have the python tag
our dictionary with through an era. Now
let's take this to the next level.
With the current implementation we can only
read the number of a given tack.
We cannot set it
like this.
To do that we need to implement another
magic method called __setitem__. It's pretty straightforward
. So define set item. It
takes three parameters. Self key and
value in this case
are key is tag and
our value is just count. So here we
set self the tags of tag
that lower to this new account. So
with this implementation. we can set
the number of a given tag. Now
. in order to be able
to get the number of items in
this TagCloud we should implement the
__len__ magic method again.
Very very
easy. S
o define len.
It
takes only the self parameter.
And here we return
len of self dot tags.
And
finally to make this iterable,
so we can iterate over
it using a for loop,
we need to implement another magic method
that is __iter__.
So define
iter.
It takes self.
Now
all we have to do is to
use one of the built in functions to
get an iterator object.
An iterator object is
an object that walks a
container and gets one item at
a time. So we call either. which is
one of the built in functions.
What do we want to iterate over in
this case. Self. The tax. So
this function returns an operator object.
which gives us
one item at a time
in a for loop. so we