So you have learned how to use
for loops to repeat one or more
statements in your programs.
Now let's dive deeper and
see what this range function returns so earlier
. you learn about the
built in Thai function. With
this function. we can get the
type of an object. So if I
pass five here and run this program
. this is what we get. So the
type of this number or this object is
into or energy er.
Now let's look at the type
of the value that we get
from the range function. So as
an argument. we pass
range of a number. Let's
run this program so this range function returns
an object of type range. So
in python we have
primitive types like numbers, strings
and booleans. But we
also have complex types. Range
is an example of one of
those complex types. Throughout this course
you're going to learn about
a lot of other complex types. Now
what is interesting about
this range object is that
it's Iterable. which means we can iterate over
it or use it in
a for loop. That is
why we can write code like this. So
this range function returns a range object which
is iterable which means
we can iterate over it.
In each iteration
X will have a different value.
.Now, range objects are not
the only iterable objects in
python. Strings are also Iterable.
so here we
can add a string like Python.
Now, in each iteration
X will hold one character in
the string. Let me show
you So print eggs. and
I'm gonna delete these two lines here. Let's
run this program so
in each iteration will get
one character and printed. We have
another complex type called list, which we used
to store a list of objects.
so we add square
brackets, This indicates a list.
Now we can add
a list of numbers or a list of strings
like a list of names.
You will learn about lists
later in the course. so let's
run this one more time.
As you can see, we can iterate
over lists.
In each iteration we'll get one object
in this list.
Now, later in the course I will show
you how to create your
own custom objects that are
iterable. For example you will learn
how to write code like this
four item in shopping cart
print item. So shopping card is going
to be a custom object that you will create.
It's not going to be
an integer or a string or Boolean.
It's a custom object.
It has a different structure
and we'll make it iterable so
we can use it in a for loop
and in each iteration we can get one item in the shopping_cart and
print it on the terminal.