all right. Time for an exercise.
I want you to write a
program to display the even numbers between 1
to 10. So when you run this program.
you should see 2 4 6 and 8
and after these I want
you to print this message: We
have 4 even numbers. Now,
here is a quick hint.
Before you get started. you should call the
range function with 1 and 10.
Do not use
the third argument which is called Step.
So basically, I
want you to iterate over all the
numbers between 1 to 10. Check
if each number is an
even number and then print it on
the terminal. So pause the video. Spend two
minutes on this exercise. When you're done,
come back Continue watching. So
we start with a four
loop for number in range 1
to 10 colon. We check
to see if the remainder
of division of this number by
two equals zero. So if number module
IHS two equals zero. then reprint
this number. Now let's
run this program. So we get 2468 Beautiful
. Now to count the even numbers.
we need a separate
variable. So let's call that count. Initially. we
set it to zero Now in
this if block. every time we
find an even number.
we need to increment count
. So we said
Count Plus equals one. And
finally. after our four loop.
we can print a
formatted strength. We have count. even
numbers. Let's run the program. And
here's the result. So that brings
us to the end of this
section. In the next section.
you're going to learn how to create your
own functions. I hope you
enjoy the section and thank you