In almost every program,
there are times you need to make
decisions, and that's when
you use an if statement.
Here's an example.
Let's say we have a variable
called temperature is 30 to 35.
Now, if temperature is greater than 30,
perhaps we want to display
a message to the user.
So we use an if statement if
after if we add a condition,
which is basically a boolean expression,
an expression that produces
a boolean value.
So if temperature is greater than 30,
here we have a Boolean expression.
If this expression evaluates to True, the
following statements will be executed.
Let me show you now, here's the important
part that a lot of beginners miss.
When you use an if statement,
you should always terminate
your statement with a colon.
Now, let's see what happens
when I press enter,
our cursor is in indented,
so here we have two white spaces.
This is very important because using these
indentations, Python interpreter will
know what statements should be executed.
If this condition is true here,
we want to print a message like
"it's warm".
We can print another message as well,
"Drink water". so we can have as
many statements as we want here
as long as there are indented,
they belong to this if block.
Now, when we finish here,
we should remove indentation
to indicate the end of this if block.
So here we can add a print statement
with a message like Don,
this statement will always be executed,
whether this condition is true or not.
Now, note that when I saved the changes,
this indentation you see here
is going to be doubled up.
Take a look. save, there you go.
So when we save the changes auto pep8
reformats our code and uses
four white spaces for indentation.
So one, two, three, four.
It uses four white spaces because
that's what pep8 recommends.
All right.
Now let's run this program.
So because temperature is greater than 30,
we see the first two messages and we
see the darn message regardless.
So if I change the temperature to,
let's say, 15 and run the program one more
time, look, this Done message is executed
whether our condition is true or not.
So pay great attention
to these indentations,
That's one of the issues
I see in beginner's code.
Let's say they want both these
print statements to be executed.
If the condition is true accidentally,
they remove the indentation on the fourth
line and that's why their program
doesn't work as they expect.
So be careful about this.
Now, what if you want to have multiple
conditions? we use an elif statement.
So elif. That is short for else if.
Here we can add another condition,
another expression.
So temperature is greater than 20.
Once again, colon, enter now by default
here VSCode is using two white spaces.
So don't worry about this as soon as you
save the changes, those two white spaces
will be converted to four white spaces.
So let's print a different message.
It's nice.
Save the changes now, look,
all these lines are indented consistently.
You can have as many elif statements as
you want, and optionally you
can also have an else statement,
So if none of the previous conditions are
True, then what you have
in the else block will be executed.
Once again, we had the colonannotation,
print.
Here we can add a message
like it's cold.
Save the changes.
In this case temperature is 15,
so none of these two conditions will be
True and we will see it's cold.
Let's run the program.
There you go.