In this lecture, I'm gonna show you
a technique for writing cleaner code.
So let's say we're building an application
for a university
and we wanna check to see if the person
who's applying for this university
program is eligible or not.
So we start by defining
a variable called Age Sedita 22.
Now, if age is greater than or equal
to 18, Courland Prent eligible.
Remove the indentation else,
colon print, not eligible.
Let's run a program, make sure it works.
Beautiful.
Now, there is nothing wrong in this piece
of code, but I want to show you a cleaner
way to achieve the same result.
Instead of having a print statement here,
we can define a variable like message
and set it to this string.
That is the first step.
So message equals this string
and then we will print this message.
Now, when you have and if else statement
with this structure where you're basically
assigning a value to a variable,
you can rewrite this in a simpler way.
So this is how it works.
All we want to do over these few lines is
to assign a value to this
message variable.
Right.
So we start with the message.
We set it to eligible
if age is greater than or equal to 18
or else we set it to not eligible.
This statement is almost like plain
English,
so what we have on line seven is exactly
equivalent to these four
lines of code delete.
Save the changes round the program.
You can see this person is eligible.
If I change the age to 12 and run
the program, we get not eligible.
So what we have here is
called ternary operator.