In Python, we have three logical operators
and we use these operators
to model more complex conditions.
So these operators are and or and not,
let's see, a real world example
of using this operators.
So imagine we're building
an application for processing loans.
So we need two variables, high income.
We can set this to true.
And good underline credit,
which set it to true.
Now here's the condition
we want to implement.
If the applicant has high income and good
credit score, then they
are eligible for the loan.
So if high income and good credit,
we had to call in and prevent eligible.
Now, note that here I have not compared
the value of this variable with true.
That is one of the issues I see
in a lot of beginners code.
This is redundant and unprofessional
because high income is a boolean.
So it's either true or false.
We don't need to compare true with true.
So if this condition is true
and this second condition is true, then
we will prevent eligible, indeterminable.
So say the changes and run the program,
obviously, this person is eligible.
However, if one of these conditions is
false, we will not be
eligible in the terminal.
So let's add an EL statement here.
And PRAnd not eligible.
We're on the program.
We see not eligible.
So this is how the and operator works
with and operator, if both conditions are
true, the result will be true
in contrast with the owner operator,
as long as at least one of the conditions
is true, the result will be true.
So if I replace and with or here
we should see eligible and a terminal.
Let's run it one more time.
There you go.
So these are the and and or operators.
Now let's take a look at an
example of the not operator.
So I'm going to define another variable
still and set it to true temporarily.
I'm going to remove this expression and
simplify it will come back to this later.
So let's say if the person is eligible,
if they are not a student,
then not operator basically in
the value of a bullier.
So in this case, student is true.
When we apply the not operator,
the result will be false.
So in this case, our condition will be
false and that's why this print
statement will not be executed.
Let me show you the same Rhondda program.
They are not eligible
if a student was false.
When we apply, the not operator will get
through, so our condition will be
true and we'll see it eligible.
Let's run it one more time.
There you go.
With this operators,
we can model even more complex conditions,
here is an example,
a person can be eligible
if they have either high income or good
credit and they should not be a student.
Let me show you how
to implement this condition.
So if high income or good credit,
we want at least one of these
conditions to be true.
So we put these in parentheses.
We want to separate these from the other
condition, which is not a student.
Now, the result of this should be true,
which means at least one of these
conditions should be true.
After that, we'll add and not student.
And finally caught.
So it is operators, you can model
all kinds of real world scenarios.