mhm and this
lecture. I'm going to show you
how to change comparison operators. This
is a very powerful technique
for writing clean code. Here's an
example. Let's say we want
to implement a rule that
says age should be between 18 and 65
. Here's how we can implement it.
So we define a variable like age
7 to 22. Now. if age is
greater than or equal
to 18 and age is
less than 65 then we print eligible
. Now here's a question for you.
How do we write this rule in math. We
can write it like this well
. more accurately. We should
have an equal sign here. so
age should be between 18 and 65
. This is how we write
this rule in math. Now I've got
some good news for you.
We can write the exact same expression in
Python. so I'm going
to move this up put
And if statement here Line four and
93 are exactly equivalent.
But as you can see
. Line four is cleaner
and easier to read. So let's
get rid of Line three. This is what