All right. here's a little quiz for
you. I want you to pause
the video and think about this
quiz for 10 to 20 seconds.
What do you think we'll
see on the terminal when
we run this program. So
pause the video. Figure out the
answer when you're ready. Come back
. Continue watching. All
right. Let's see what happens
when we run this program. First
we get this. If statement
in this case. we're comparing two
different objects for equality.
And these objects have different types
. We have a number
compared with the strength. So
number 10 and strengthen are not equal.
That is why
they will not be printed
on the terminal. So the control
moves the L F part here we have two
billion expressions. Here is
the first one. Here's the
second one and they
are combined using the logical
end. So if both
these expressions are evaluated to
true. then this intern expression will be
true and we will see
beyond the terminal. Let's see
if both these expressions
are evaluated to true. Here's
the first part.
Bag is greater than Apple. That
is true because when we
sort these words. bag comes
after apple. But look
at the second part. This
expression is evaluated to
false because bag is not
greater than cat. So when
we apply the logical end
between true and false. the result will be
false. That is why this statement will not
be executed. So to control
moves to the else part. And
when we run this program.
the letter C will be printed on